<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Craftsbury Outdoor Center News</title>
		<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/sculling/sculling-camps/sculling-news/</link>
		<atom:link href="https://www.craftsbury.com/sculling/sculling-camps/sculling-news/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<description></description>

		
		<item>
			<title>2019 CommRow</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2027/</link>
			<description>Ready to row? The season is coming. CommRow will be four afternoons a week this summer, running Monday-Thursday from May 20 through the end of September. The first date for returning CommRowers will be Monday, May 20th, at 4:30pm. First time CommRowers and beginners (one year of sculling experience or less) are welcome to attend on Wednesdays, starting on Wednesday, June 5th! Check out the CommRow page for all of the updated information, including details for newcomers and returners alike. Looking forward to seeing you on Great Hosmer this summer! </description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 16:11:11 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[Ready to row? The season is coming. CommRow will be four afternoons a week this summer, running Monday-Thursday from May 20 through the end of September. The first date for returning CommRowers will be Monday, May 20th, at 4:30pm. First time CommRowers and beginners (one year of sculling experience or less) are welcome to attend on Wednesdays, starting on Wednesday, June 5th! Check out the CommRow page for all of the updated information, including details for newcomers and returners alike. Looking forward to seeing you on Great Hosmer this summer!  <img src="/assets/bulkUpload/IMG-2201.jpg" alt="IMG 2201" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2027/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Summer Activities for kids and teens</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2273/</link>
			<description>


Check out the inaugural biannual resource listing provided by a collaboration of local organizations, including the Craftsbury Outdoor Center, WonderArts, Hosmer Point, and Center for an Agricultural Economy. This list is designed to help families find summer activities in our area for kids ages 0-18. This list is a work in progress and you are welcome to help make the next edition even better by sending additions and edits to activitiesforyoungpeoplevt@gmail.com.
See and download the calendar. 
 
 


</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 14:52:43 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[


Check out the inaugural biannual resource listing provided by a collaboration of local organizations, including the Craftsbury Outdoor Center, WonderArts, Hosmer Point, and Center for an Agricultural Economy. This list is designed to help families find summer activities in our area for kids ages 0-18. This list is a work in progress and you are welcome to help make the next edition even better by sending additions and edits to activitiesforyoungpeoplevt@gmail.com.
See and download the calendar. 
 
 


 <img src="/assets/bulkUpload/10364085-811690448855953-2087165446026660010-n.jpg" alt="10364085 811690448855953 2087165446026660010 n" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2273/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Save the Date:  Skiing for Scullers, January 2-5, 2019</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2146/</link>
			<description>Are you a sculler looking to expand your outdoor winter training options? Nordic skiing might just be the best way for rowers to cross-train while the liquid water is frozen – we certainly believe it is – and to that end, we’re hosting a “Skiing for Scullers” weekend January 2-5. It may surprise you to know that our GRP rowers spend more hours on skis from November through March than they do on the erg, and that they return to the water with even greater enthusiasm having given their bodies and their brains something new and different to work at. If anything, they find that not only have they not lost speed from the hiatus, they’ve gained greater readiness to put in more quality miles when they get back to liquid water. With equal measures of instruction, patience, and time, you can do the same, and this weekend will show you how.Craftsbury in winter is just as spectacular as Craftsbury in summer, with the focus shifted to gliding over snow instead of water. Following the same formula you know from sculling camps, we&#039;ll teach you how to ski (or how to improve your skiing) and how skiing will benefit your sculling next summer. Drills, video, training talks, a low student-to-coach ratio, our usual delicious food, and more will fill your weekend as you learn from our sculling staff who have become proficient skiers, as well as our full-time skiing staff. The program will have a focus on skate technique and is geared toward scullers who are beginning/intermediate skiers and would like to make Nordic skiing a viable cross-training option, gain a new athletic skill set, or simply find a new way to enjoy winter. Familiarity with some form of skiing or skating winter sports is a prerequisite, but vast Nordic-specific experience is not.The program includes three nights of lodging, full meals in our newly renovated dining hall, equipment rentals, trail passes, ski instruction, videotaping sessions and review, use of the Center’s facilities including fitness center, sauna, snowshoe trails, and more.  Questions about the program should be emailed to sculling director Troy Howell. More details to come, but keep this on your radar.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2018 12:03:48 -0500</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[Are you a sculler looking to expand your outdoor winter training options? Nordic skiing might just be the best way for rowers to cross-train while the liquid water is frozen – we certainly believe it is – and to that end, we’re hosting a “Skiing for Scullers” weekend January 2-5. It may surprise you to know that our GRP rowers spend more hours on skis from November through March than they do on the erg, and that they return to the water with even greater enthusiasm having given their bodies and their brains something new and different to work at. If anything, they find that not only have they not lost speed from the hiatus, they’ve gained greater readiness to put in more quality miles when they get back to liquid water. With equal measures of instruction, patience, and time, you can do the same, and this weekend will show you how.Craftsbury in winter is just as spectacular as Craftsbury in summer, with the focus shifted to gliding over snow instead of water. Following the same formula you know from sculling camps, we&#039;ll teach you how to ski (or how to improve your skiing) and how skiing will benefit your sculling next summer. Drills, video, training talks, a low student-to-coach ratio, our usual delicious food, and more will fill your weekend as you learn from our sculling staff who have become proficient skiers, as well as our full-time skiing staff. The program will have a focus on skate technique and is geared toward scullers who are beginning/intermediate skiers and would like to make Nordic skiing a viable cross-training option, gain a new athletic skill set, or simply find a new way to enjoy winter. Familiarity with some form of skiing or skating winter sports is a prerequisite, but vast Nordic-specific experience is not.The program includes three nights of lodging, full meals in our newly renovated dining hall, equipment rentals, trail passes, ski instruction, videotaping sessions and review, use of the Center’s facilities including fitness center, sauna, snowshoe trails, and more.  Questions about the program should be emailed to sculling director Troy Howell. More details to come, but keep this on your radar. <img src="/assets/bulkUpload/wesskiing2.jpg" alt="wesskiing2" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2146/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>GRP Races at Canal de Lachine in Montreal</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2279/</link>
			<description>The GRP traveled to Canada last weekend for some good ole fashioned Quebecer racing. The 11th annual Lachine Regatta was held on the Canal de Lachine in Montreal. As this regatta was free of “US national ranking implications” the GRP decided to made the most of the trip by doubling up in two events each - everyone raced in both the 1x and the 4x.The first race of the day was the 1x event. There were nearly 50 entries between the open men/women, masters men/women, and junior boys/girls. The racecourse was a 5k stretch in a shipping canal. Much to Wes’ demise, the start line was about 1k downstream from a set of shipping locks, which he desperately wanted to row through. But, even without the locks, the course certainly had its share of crazy obstacles. Over the course of 5k, the competitors had to navigate themselves through six bridges and around countless port/starboard buoys - some of which were located in the middle of the canal. The format was head race style with approximately ten second intervals between each competitor. This made for some pretty interesting racing as there was a lot of passing and lead changes taking place in a narrow canal. It was a successful morning outing for everyone in the 1x as it was a total Cedar Leaf sweep in all events. The men took places 1-5 in the event with Lucas coming in first, followed by Kevin, Wes, Nate and Andy in that order. Alex and Bridget took first and second respectively in the women’s division, and Troy took home the W in the men’s masters 1x. The group came in for a quick snack and reboot before they headed out in quads. Both 4xs raced in the open men’s division, but had slightly diverse lineups in that the women, Alex and Bridget raced in each of the quads, and Troy joined one as well.The second race of the day turned into a GRP vs. GRP battle as the two boats were able to separate themselves from the rest of the field within the first two kilometers of the race. Eventually, the 4x with Lucas, Andy, Kevin and Bridget came out with the win over Troy, Nathan, Wes and Alex. It was a great event in Montreal and the GRP is grateful for the great hospitality of the folks at Lachine Rowing Club. They are now back on Hosmer and look forward to training for Club Nationals and Trials III.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 15:44:02 -0400</pubDate>
			
			
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2279/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>GRP Race at Trials II/Speed Order II</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2277/</link>
			<description>Last weekend the rowers of the Green Racing Project traveled to Princeton, NJ to compete in their second race of the 2019 season. The regatta had different implications for the men and the women, as it was Trials for the Women’s 2x – meaning that the winner of the regatta earned the right to represent the United States in the 2x at this summer’s World Championships in Linz, Austria. Whereas it was a Speed Order for the Men’s 2x – meaning that the winner of the regatta earned the right to race at World Cup II, but will have to race at Trials III in July to earn the right to race at the World Championships in August. After a successful Trials I in the 1x, the members of the GRP had to do a bit of “dating around” to find a partner in the lead up to 2x Trials. Some members of the team found their match within the GRP, ie. Wes and Nathan on the men’s side and Alex and Taylor on the women’s side. Meanwhile, other GRPers linked up with rowers from different club programs. Lucas raced with Jacob Plihal from Vesper, Kevin raced with JP Kirkegaard from Vesper, Andy raced with Eric Hallenbeck from MRC, John raced with Justin Keen from PennAC, and Bridget found her match in Charlotte Buck from NYAC.Racing kicked off on Thursday AM with a 1900m Time Trial. Due to limited entries, no crews were eliminated in the Time Trial, but were seeded into heats based on finish order. The heats were scheduled to take place Friday morning, but in true Princeton-in-the-Spring fashion, Friday afternoon winds forced the race officials to push racing forward by half a day. Therefore the heats took place Thursday evening. On the men’s side, the top four from each heat advanced to the A/B semis, and the fifth place crews went directly to the C-final. Wes/Nathan, Lucas/Jacob, Kevin/JP and John/Justin all advanced to the A/B Semis and Andy/Eric went on to race in and win the C-final. On the women’s side, only the top two from each heat advanced directly to the semi’s and all others went to Friday morning repechages. Alex/Taylor and Bridget/Charlotte narrowly missed out on the top two spots, therefore the two GRP boats had to face each other in Friday morning’s repechage. Alex/Taylor came out on top with Bridget/Charlotte taking second place. Unfortunately only Alex/Taylor were able to move on to the semi’s. Saturday morning&#039;s semis had mixed results for the GRP. Due to the Trials four-lane progression on the women’s side, only the top two from each semi advanced to the final on Sunday. Alex/Taylor took a hard-fought third place in their semi and therefore did not move onto the final. On the men’s side, the top three from each semi moved onto the A final and the rest went to the B final. John/Justin, Kevin/JP and Lucas/Jacob all advanced to the A-final. Wes/Nathan narrowly missed the cutoff, but went on to win Sunday’s B final. Sunday’s Men’s 2x A final was hot and GRP heavy as half of the boats in the final were powered by Cedar Leaves. John/Justin came away with the win with Kevin/JP coming in second and Lucas/Jacob taking fifth place!Overall it was a great weekend of racing for the GRP. The team is happy to be back training on Hosmer as they look ahead to Trials III and Club Nationals in July!</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 11:20:19 -0400</pubDate>
			
			
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2277/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>2019 U23 Scullers</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2275/</link>
			<description>Craftsbury is pleased to welcome its 2019 U23 sculling class. A dozen athletes total, 8 prior attendees from either 2017 and 18, and 4 new athletes make up this summer&#039;s squad.Peter Chatain,  Stanford University - 2018 Craftsbury U23Samuel Gatsos,  Colgate UniversityLaura Hegemann,  Rutgers University - 2018 Craftsbury U23Thomas Johnson,  Virginia Commonwealth University - 2018 Craftsbury U23Grace Joyce,  University of Wisconsin - 2017 Craftsbury U23Mackenzie King,  University of Virginia - 2018 Craftsbury U23Jenny McIlvane,  Craftsbury Green Racing ProjectRhiannon Mulligan,  Wellesley College - 2018 Craftsbury U23Nathan Phelps,  Princeton UniversityElizabeth Ray,  Columbia UniversityJack Reid,  Trinity College - 2018 Craftsbury U23James Wright,  Stanford UniversityThe GRP U23 Summer Program is designed to provide athletes a bridge from collegiate rowing to the US National Team, with a focus on small boat skill development. In the nearest term, the immediate goal is to put together small boats to compete at U23 World Championship Trials, July 7-10, 2019 in West Windsor, NJ.The program offers coaching, equipment, room &amp;amp; board, and travel support. Rowers are eligible for, and may compete in, any of the following events: U23 World Trials; Senior Nationals; Senior Team World Trials; World Championships (U23 and Senior); and, Canadian Henley.Participants offset the costs of the program by giving fourteen hours of work per week back to the Outdoor Center. Work projects support the Craftsbury Outdoor Center and its mission. Tasks vary from chopping wood, to coaching Community Rowing participants, to working in the garden, to designing energy systems and maps.Welcome rowers!</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2019 14:48:36 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[Craftsbury is pleased to welcome its 2019 U23 sculling class. A dozen athletes total, 8 prior attendees from either 2017 and 18, and 4 new athletes make up this summer&#039;s squad.Peter Chatain,  Stanford University - 2018 Craftsbury U23Samuel Gatsos,  Colgate UniversityLaura Hegemann,  Rutgers University - 2018 Craftsbury U23Thomas Johnson,  Virginia Commonwealth University - 2018 Craftsbury U23Grace Joyce,  University of Wisconsin - 2017 Craftsbury U23Mackenzie King,  University of Virginia - 2018 Craftsbury U23Jenny McIlvane,  Craftsbury Green Racing ProjectRhiannon Mulligan,  Wellesley College - 2018 Craftsbury U23Nathan Phelps,  Princeton UniversityElizabeth Ray,  Columbia UniversityJack Reid,  Trinity College - 2018 Craftsbury U23James Wright,  Stanford UniversityThe GRP U23 Summer Program is designed to provide athletes a bridge from collegiate rowing to the US National Team, with a focus on small boat skill development. In the nearest term, the immediate goal is to put together small boats to compete at U23 World Championship Trials, July 7-10, 2019 in West Windsor, NJ.The program offers coaching, equipment, room &amp;amp; board, and travel support. Rowers are eligible for, and may compete in, any of the following events: U23 World Trials; Senior Nationals; Senior Team World Trials; World Championships (U23 and Senior); and, Canadian Henley.Participants offset the costs of the program by giving fourteen hours of work per week back to the Outdoor Center. Work projects support the Craftsbury Outdoor Center and its mission. Tasks vary from chopping wood, to coaching Community Rowing participants, to working in the garden, to designing energy systems and maps.Welcome rowers! <img src="/assets/bulkUpload/320-WchTrls-2021.jpg" alt="320 WchTrls 2021" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2275/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>U23 Sculling assistant, intern named</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2270/</link>
			<description>Grace Hollowell is returning to Craftsbury for her second summer as assistant coach for the Green Racing Project (GRP). Hollowell brings a wealth of coaching experience to GRP. A member of the Boston College coaching staff since fall 2018, she previously spent four years as the assistant women’s coach and recruiting coordinator at Dartmouth. She had coaching stints at Boston University (2013-14) and Smith College (2011-13). GRP head coach Steve Whelpley says “(Grace) gets our approach to small boats and individualized attention, but also brings a different perspective from her years coaching at various collegiate programs. We look forward to her leadership and ideas for the summer.&quot;Last summer at Craftsbury Hollowell helped coach the U23 M2x and M1x that qualified for the 2018 World Championships in Poland. She also coached the M2x and W4x that won the Royal Canadian Henley that summer. Before starting her career as a coach, she rowed at Harvard, where she was the captain of the lightweight team. Hollowell earned three varsity letters, was named team MVP twice, was an Eastern Association of Women’s Rowing Colleges (EAWRC) gold medalist, and completed her Bachelor of Arts degree. While coaching at Smith (2011-13), Hollowell also completed her Master of Science degree.Hollowell says she is “incredibly excited to return to Craftsbury this summer to work with a talented, driven, and thoughtful group of athletes and coaches. The community and culture of Craftsbury foster a unique experience that creates mindful, focused athletes who can make boats go fast and compete at the highest level. Not to mention you can&#039;t beat Vermont in the summer (or the food!!).&quot;We&#039;re equally excited about another successful summer with Grace!The Green Racing Project is pleased to welcome its first-ever summer intern, Mackenzi Sherman, this summer. &quot;Craftsbury has a wealth of coaches on campus during the summer. The addition of the GRP internship will allow for an up-and-coming coach to gain exposure to not only the GRP coaches but all those who coach throughout the summer camps,” says Coach Steve. Sherman has just finished her second season as the graduate assistant coach at Smith College, where she is getting her master’s degree in Exercise and Sport Studies. Before going to Smith, she spent the 2016-17 season as a volunteer assistant coach at Virginia - her alma mater.Sherman was a member of the UVA Women’s Rowing Team, earning three varsity letters (2014-16), All-ACC Second Team honors (2015-16) and was named to the All-ACC Academic Rowing Team in 2014 and 2016. She rowed on the Second Varsity Eight in 2016, when it won the ACC Championship. The same year, she rowed on the Second Varsity Eight when it placed fourth at the NCAA Championships. In 2013-14, Sherman was stroke seat on the Varsity Eight, which won the ACC Championship and placed third at NCAAs. We look forward to getting to know, grow, and row with you Mackenzi!</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 15:52:47 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[Grace Hollowell is returning to Craftsbury for her second summer as assistant coach for the Green Racing Project (GRP). Hollowell brings a wealth of coaching experience to GRP. A member of the Boston College coaching staff since fall 2018, she previously spent four years as the assistant women’s coach and recruiting coordinator at Dartmouth. She had coaching stints at Boston University (2013-14) and Smith College (2011-13). GRP head coach Steve Whelpley says “(Grace) gets our approach to small boats and individualized attention, but also brings a different perspective from her years coaching at various collegiate programs. We look forward to her leadership and ideas for the summer.&quot;Last summer at Craftsbury Hollowell helped coach the U23 M2x and M1x that qualified for the 2018 World Championships in Poland. She also coached the M2x and W4x that won the Royal Canadian Henley that summer. Before starting her career as a coach, she rowed at Harvard, where she was the captain of the lightweight team. Hollowell earned three varsity letters, was named team MVP twice, was an Eastern Association of Women’s Rowing Colleges (EAWRC) gold medalist, and completed her Bachelor of Arts degree. While coaching at Smith (2011-13), Hollowell also completed her Master of Science degree.Hollowell says she is “incredibly excited to return to Craftsbury this summer to work with a talented, driven, and thoughtful group of athletes and coaches. The community and culture of Craftsbury foster a unique experience that creates mindful, focused athletes who can make boats go fast and compete at the highest level. Not to mention you can&#039;t beat Vermont in the summer (or the food!!).&quot;We&#039;re equally excited about another successful summer with Grace!The Green Racing Project is pleased to welcome its first-ever summer intern, Mackenzi Sherman, this summer. &quot;Craftsbury has a wealth of coaches on campus during the summer. The addition of the GRP internship will allow for an up-and-coming coach to gain exposure to not only the GRP coaches but all those who coach throughout the summer camps,” says Coach Steve. Sherman has just finished her second season as the graduate assistant coach at Smith College, where she is getting her master’s degree in Exercise and Sport Studies. Before going to Smith, she spent the 2016-17 season as a volunteer assistant coach at Virginia - her alma mater.Sherman was a member of the UVA Women’s Rowing Team, earning three varsity letters (2014-16), All-ACC Second Team honors (2015-16) and was named to the All-ACC Academic Rowing Team in 2014 and 2016. She rowed on the Second Varsity Eight in 2016, when it won the ACC Championship. The same year, she rowed on the Second Varsity Eight when it placed fourth at the NCAA Championships. In 2013-14, Sherman was stroke seat on the Varsity Eight, which won the ACC Championship and placed third at NCAAs. We look forward to getting to know, grow, and row with you Mackenzi! <img src="/assets/Uploads/19-Grace-Hollowell-w3.jpg" alt="19 Grace Hollowell w3" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2270/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Green Racing Project Rowers at C.R.A.S.H-B. Sprints</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2230/</link>
			<description>When as much of your year is spent with ice covering your body of water as our Green Racing Project athletes, you obviously spend plenty of time on the ergometer over the course of the year. The men on our GRP Rowing side of the team headed down to Boston this past weekend to join in on the pinnacle of erging, the C.R.A.S.H.-B. Sprints 2,000m race with almost a thousand other participants of all ages and categories. This was the first year in a new venue, the Boston University Indoor Track and Field arena with a full crowd of spectators reaching deafening volumes towards the end of each round of 2ks. C.R.A.S.H.-B. format, for anyone unfamiliar, is a one-and-done 2k for each age group and division. Each category sits down together and when the buzzer goes off, it’s a mad dash to the last meter on each person’s monitor. A “live-stream” of each race is up on a couple jumbotrons behind the ergs for the spectators to see the relative position of each boat as they proceed through each virtual meter. They also have some fantastic announcers that give insight into each race for the crowd to really get invested in the results. The paramedics have to work overtime at this event as well with countless people reaching the point of vomiting or passing out by the end of their 2k throughout the day. It’s quite the spectacle considering it’s just a bunch of people erging.Our men all sat down at 2:15pm for the Open Men’s category with Wes Vear, Lucas Bellows, Andy Raitto, and Kevin Meador, the newest member of the GRP Rowing team, all representing the Cedar Leaf. Bellows led the race for the first hundred meters and then was overtaken by Connor Corwen of Bucknell Crew Association for a few hundred meters. Then Vear took the lead and held onto it until the end, finishing with a 5:59.2 over Corwen’s 5:59.7. Meador finished third with a 6:02.0 and then Raitto took fifth with a 6:05.9. Bellows rounded out the GRP with a 6:09.9.You can find full results here.It was some great racing from the men and now they head south for their weeklong training trip to Peachtree City, Georgia to start to get the feel back for the water. Keep up with their training via the GRP blog over the next week!</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 15:16:57 -0500</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[When as much of your year is spent with ice covering your body of water as our Green Racing Project athletes, you obviously spend plenty of time on the ergometer over the course of the year. The men on our GRP Rowing side of the team headed down to Boston this past weekend to join in on the pinnacle of erging, the C.R.A.S.H.-B. Sprints 2,000m race with almost a thousand other participants of all ages and categories. This was the first year in a new venue, the Boston University Indoor Track and Field arena with a full crowd of spectators reaching deafening volumes towards the end of each round of 2ks. C.R.A.S.H.-B. format, for anyone unfamiliar, is a one-and-done 2k for each age group and division. Each category sits down together and when the buzzer goes off, it’s a mad dash to the last meter on each person’s monitor. A “live-stream” of each race is up on a couple jumbotrons behind the ergs for the spectators to see the relative position of each boat as they proceed through each virtual meter. They also have some fantastic announcers that give insight into each race for the crowd to really get invested in the results. The paramedics have to work overtime at this event as well with countless people reaching the point of vomiting or passing out by the end of their 2k throughout the day. It’s quite the spectacle considering it’s just a bunch of people erging.Our men all sat down at 2:15pm for the Open Men’s category with Wes Vear, Lucas Bellows, Andy Raitto, and Kevin Meador, the newest member of the GRP Rowing team, all representing the Cedar Leaf. Bellows led the race for the first hundred meters and then was overtaken by Connor Corwen of Bucknell Crew Association for a few hundred meters. Then Vear took the lead and held onto it until the end, finishing with a 5:59.2 over Corwen’s 5:59.7. Meador finished third with a 6:02.0 and then Raitto took fifth with a 6:05.9. Bellows rounded out the GRP with a 6:09.9.You can find full results here.It was some great racing from the men and now they head south for their weeklong training trip to Peachtree City, Georgia to start to get the feel back for the water. Keep up with their training via the GRP blog over the next week! <img src="/assets/bulkUpload/20190217-150556-e1550791009412-814x1024.jpg" alt="20190217 150556 e1550791009412 814x1024" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2230/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Head of the Charles 2018 Recap and Results</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2132/</link>
			<description>After a whirlwind weekend in Boston, the 54th Head of the Charles is complete! The entire rowing world converges on the Charles River every year during the third weekend of October, and Craftsbury is no exception. Blustery winds and (mostly) blue skies marked the event, which saw nearly 11,000 racers negotiating the bridges and turns of the infamous three-mile course. Sculling staff and GRP rowers had a fantastic time both racing and working the tent in the bustling finish line area, handing out nearly 80 dozen cookies and chatting with tons of past and future campers. We also raffled off a free week of camp; we’ll be announcing the winner soon.Now, to the racing: First up on Saturday was Director of Sculling Troy Howell, racing in the Men’s Grand Master Singles. His seventh-place finish in a field of 52 easily secured him a guaranteed entry for next year’s regatta. Also on Saturday morning, Dick Dreissigacker and Judy Geer raced in the Senior Master Eights categories, for Motley Rowing Club and 1980 Rowing Club, respectively.  Motley finished 35th out of 62 crews, and 1980 came in 23rd out of 44 crews. Saturday afternoon features the championship sculling events, which kicked off with the Men’s Champ Doubles. GRP’s Nathan Lado and Wes Vear kicked it off indeed, racing to a first-place finish. Their winning time of 17:02 bested the second-place finishers and GRP alums Peter and Tom Graves by five seconds. Also in the event was a double of Mats Terwiesch and Josh Bilchik, two of our 2018 U23 alums. They placed eighth overall, and earned gold medals as the top lightweight double within the event. In the Women’s Champ Doubles, Jen Forbes raced with GRP alum Elizabeth Sonshine to a close second-place finish behind ARION, less than 1.5 seconds back. Jen also jumped into a Director’s Challenge Mixed 8+ on Sunday and a won a second medal, this time gold. (Important note: she was dressed as Olaf, the snowman from Frozen, for her victorious run down the course.)The Women’s Champ Singles saw Alex Spaulding and new GRP rower Taylor Goetzinger race to 11th and 20th places, respectively.  The field featured numerous top US and international scullers, but no one was surprised to see Charles River local Gevvie Stone taking her record ninth win in the event. Jenny McIlvane raced in the Women’s Lightweight Singles, finishing in ninth place.The Men’s Champ Singles also featured a wickedly competitive field, with some of the fastest US men, including our own John Graves and Ben Davison (rowing for his school, the University of Washington) mixing it up with the biggest international names (Mahe Drysdale, Damir Martin, and Robbie Manson, to name a few). As the results started to roll in, it appeared that first place would go to local Andy Campbell, American lightweight sculler and course record holder, with John holding in second place. But this is head racing, and nothing is set until the last sculler has crossed the line. As the wakes settled, it became clear that Ben Davison had rowed through the field from bow #26 to take the win. Ben’s gold-medal time was 17:55, Andy Campbell went 18:00 for silver, and John finished in 18:11 for bronze. Sunday was a quieter day on the racing front for Craftsbury, but Fleet Manager Erika Sloan raced to ninth place out of 22 in the Women’s Club Singles, and GRP sculler Lucas Bellows traded two oars for one to hop in with some New York Athletic Club athletes in the Men’s Champ Fours, placing 12th. Congratulations to all who raced, including the myriad other Craftsbury-connected crews out on the Charles this weekend. Well rowed by all!  Full results can be found on RegattaCentral or on HereNOW. Photos from the racing can be found on Row2k, Sport Graphics, and Scullingfool.The GRP next races from November 3-4 at the USRowing Fall Speed Order, a chance to test speed on the erg and in singles before winter training begins in earnest. John Graves is currently in the lead for the Lotman Challenge, and will also head to Philadelphia to contest the final leg at the Head of the Schuylkill Regatta next weekend. </description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 21:02:06 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[After a whirlwind weekend in Boston, the 54th Head of the Charles is complete! The entire rowing world converges on the Charles River every year during the third weekend of October, and Craftsbury is no exception. Blustery winds and (mostly) blue skies marked the event, which saw nearly 11,000 racers negotiating the bridges and turns of the infamous three-mile course. Sculling staff and GRP rowers had a fantastic time both racing and working the tent in the bustling finish line area, handing out nearly 80 dozen cookies and chatting with tons of past and future campers. We also raffled off a free week of camp; we’ll be announcing the winner soon.Now, to the racing: First up on Saturday was Director of Sculling Troy Howell, racing in the Men’s Grand Master Singles. His seventh-place finish in a field of 52 easily secured him a guaranteed entry for next year’s regatta. Also on Saturday morning, Dick Dreissigacker and Judy Geer raced in the Senior Master Eights categories, for Motley Rowing Club and 1980 Rowing Club, respectively.  Motley finished 35th out of 62 crews, and 1980 came in 23rd out of 44 crews. Saturday afternoon features the championship sculling events, which kicked off with the Men’s Champ Doubles. GRP’s Nathan Lado and Wes Vear kicked it off indeed, racing to a first-place finish. Their winning time of 17:02 bested the second-place finishers and GRP alums Peter and Tom Graves by five seconds. Also in the event was a double of Mats Terwiesch and Josh Bilchik, two of our 2018 U23 alums. They placed eighth overall, and earned gold medals as the top lightweight double within the event. In the Women’s Champ Doubles, Jen Forbes raced with GRP alum Elizabeth Sonshine to a close second-place finish behind ARION, less than 1.5 seconds back. Jen also jumped into a Director’s Challenge Mixed 8+ on Sunday and a won a second medal, this time gold. (Important note: she was dressed as Olaf, the snowman from Frozen, for her victorious run down the course.)The Women’s Champ Singles saw Alex Spaulding and new GRP rower Taylor Goetzinger race to 11th and 20th places, respectively.  The field featured numerous top US and international scullers, but no one was surprised to see Charles River local Gevvie Stone taking her record ninth win in the event. Jenny McIlvane raced in the Women’s Lightweight Singles, finishing in ninth place.The Men’s Champ Singles also featured a wickedly competitive field, with some of the fastest US men, including our own John Graves and Ben Davison (rowing for his school, the University of Washington) mixing it up with the biggest international names (Mahe Drysdale, Damir Martin, and Robbie Manson, to name a few). As the results started to roll in, it appeared that first place would go to local Andy Campbell, American lightweight sculler and course record holder, with John holding in second place. But this is head racing, and nothing is set until the last sculler has crossed the line. As the wakes settled, it became clear that Ben Davison had rowed through the field from bow #26 to take the win. Ben’s gold-medal time was 17:55, Andy Campbell went 18:00 for silver, and John finished in 18:11 for bronze. Sunday was a quieter day on the racing front for Craftsbury, but Fleet Manager Erika Sloan raced to ninth place out of 22 in the Women’s Club Singles, and GRP sculler Lucas Bellows traded two oars for one to hop in with some New York Athletic Club athletes in the Men’s Champ Fours, placing 12th. Congratulations to all who raced, including the myriad other Craftsbury-connected crews out on the Charles this weekend. Well rowed by all!  Full results can be found on RegattaCentral or on HereNOW. Photos from the racing can be found on Row2k, Sport Graphics, and Scullingfool.The GRP next races from November 3-4 at the USRowing Fall Speed Order, a chance to test speed on the erg and in singles before winter training begins in earnest. John Graves is currently in the lead for the Lotman Challenge, and will also head to Philadelphia to contest the final leg at the Head of the Schuylkill Regatta next weekend.  <img src="/assets/bulkUpload/HOCR2018-Craftsbury-2x-ForbesSonshine-MC2.jpg" alt="HOCR2018 Craftsbury 2x ForbesSonshine MC2" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2132/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>GRP Scullers Race Green Mountain Head: Win syrup, apples, and cider</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2116/</link>
			<description>GRP scullers raced at Green Mountain Head this weekend for what are arguably the best prizes in all of fall head racing. For the last 37 years, Putney Rowing Club has hosted the regatta on their small stretch of the Connecticut River, and have provided single and double scullers of all ages a truly unique race experience. For starters, the regatta parking lot is a corn field that is usually harvested just days before the start of GMH. Volunteers usher racers that are both towing trailers and car-topping their boats over mounds of dirt and remainders of prickly corn stalks. Cars bounce comically over the now-empty rows of corn in anticipation of a great day of racing. Don’t be fooled by the low-key nature of this race, though - some of the athletes you see noshing freshly fried apple cider donuts are Olympians and world champions alike. “I looked over and saw Gevvie putting away two cider doughnuts, and then Mary came over and bought one,“ Alex Spaulding (who won a gallon of cider for her third place finish behind Mary and Gevvie) recounts feeling inspired by 2016 Olympic Silver Medalist Gevvie Stone and 2018 World Championship Silver Medalist Mary Jones Nabel on their pre-race fueling methods. “I knew that [Jen and I] should probably get one too, maybe [cider doughnuts] are the secret to going fast.” The men’s and women’s single sculls events were heavily peppered with athletes from national teams past and present, along with novice, club, and masters rowers alike.  Aside from the general friendliness and good-natured vibes, Putney Rowing Club members and volunteers provide racers with a lunch of healthy snacks, cheese sandwiches, apples, apple cider, and the famously quirky offering of....egg rolls?“I’ve never had an egg roll before,” recalls GRP sculler and self-proclaimed “big eater” Wes Vear - “but after today, I think I’ve more than well enough made up for lost time.” GRP scullers had sights set on both racing well during the 5 kilometer race (split in half by a two stake buoys that racers have to effectively make a u-turn around), and taking home one of the prizes awarded to the top three finishers of each event. First place finishers receive a quart of maple syrup, second place gets a bag of apples, and third takes home a gallon of apple cider. All of these products are local to the great state of Vermont. Men’s 1x (19-34)Nathan Lado- 2nd *APPLE WINNER*Wes Vear- 6thLucas Bellows- 8th Men’s 1x (45-55)Troy Howell- 3rd *CIDER WINNER* Women’s 1x (19-34)Alex Spaulding- 3rd *CIDER WINNER*Jen Forbes- 4thJenny McIlvane- 8th Mixed 2x Jen Forbes/Nathan Lado- 1st *SYRUP WINNER*Wes Vear/Alex Spaulding- 3rd *CIDER WINNER*Troy Howell/Jenny McIlvane- 4th Congrats on a fun and successful weekend of racing! And a huge thank you to Putney Rowing Club for putting on such a fun, competitive and good-spirited regatta!Up next: Head of the Kevin III (October 13)  </description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 20:02:18 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[GRP scullers raced at Green Mountain Head this weekend for what are arguably the best prizes in all of fall head racing. For the last 37 years, Putney Rowing Club has hosted the regatta on their small stretch of the Connecticut River, and have provided single and double scullers of all ages a truly unique race experience. For starters, the regatta parking lot is a corn field that is usually harvested just days before the start of GMH. Volunteers usher racers that are both towing trailers and car-topping their boats over mounds of dirt and remainders of prickly corn stalks. Cars bounce comically over the now-empty rows of corn in anticipation of a great day of racing. Don’t be fooled by the low-key nature of this race, though - some of the athletes you see noshing freshly fried apple cider donuts are Olympians and world champions alike. “I looked over and saw Gevvie putting away two cider doughnuts, and then Mary came over and bought one,“ Alex Spaulding (who won a gallon of cider for her third place finish behind Mary and Gevvie) recounts feeling inspired by 2016 Olympic Silver Medalist Gevvie Stone and 2018 World Championship Silver Medalist Mary Jones Nabel on their pre-race fueling methods. “I knew that [Jen and I] should probably get one too, maybe [cider doughnuts] are the secret to going fast.” The men’s and women’s single sculls events were heavily peppered with athletes from national teams past and present, along with novice, club, and masters rowers alike.  Aside from the general friendliness and good-natured vibes, Putney Rowing Club members and volunteers provide racers with a lunch of healthy snacks, cheese sandwiches, apples, apple cider, and the famously quirky offering of....egg rolls?“I’ve never had an egg roll before,” recalls GRP sculler and self-proclaimed “big eater” Wes Vear - “but after today, I think I’ve more than well enough made up for lost time.” GRP scullers had sights set on both racing well during the 5 kilometer race (split in half by a two stake buoys that racers have to effectively make a u-turn around), and taking home one of the prizes awarded to the top three finishers of each event. First place finishers receive a quart of maple syrup, second place gets a bag of apples, and third takes home a gallon of apple cider. All of these products are local to the great state of Vermont. Men’s 1x (19-34)Nathan Lado- 2nd *APPLE WINNER*Wes Vear- 6thLucas Bellows- 8th Men’s 1x (45-55)Troy Howell- 3rd *CIDER WINNER* Women’s 1x (19-34)Alex Spaulding- 3rd *CIDER WINNER*Jen Forbes- 4thJenny McIlvane- 8th Mixed 2x Jen Forbes/Nathan Lado- 1st *SYRUP WINNER*Wes Vear/Alex Spaulding- 3rd *CIDER WINNER*Troy Howell/Jenny McIlvane- 4th Congrats on a fun and successful weekend of racing! And a huge thank you to Putney Rowing Club for putting on such a fun, competitive and good-spirited regatta!Up next: Head of the Kevin III (October 13)   <img src="/assets/bulkUpload/399D5DEA-C654-4943-8BD6-F18AA6C90B39.jpeg" alt="399D5DEA C654 4943 8BD6 F18AA6C90B39" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2116/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Norm Graf: 1926-2018</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2111/</link>
			<description>At the age of 92, Norman Graf passed away yesterday, September 23, 2018. Norm coached at the Center for almost 20 years, serving as Sculling Program Director for 11 years.Norm began rowing in 1940. He rowed with the undefeated Culver Military Academy 8+ in 1943. His rowing career took a hiatus during World War II, but in &#039;48 he returned to the sport as stroke and captain of the undefeated Rutgers University freshmen team. In the late &#039;50s Norm began coaching at Yale. In &#039;67 he became the Head Rowing Coach and Intramural Athletic Director at Trinity College in Connecticut, a position he held for 15 years. Norm was the varsity women&#039;s coach at Trinity from &#039;86-&#039;92, and the Men&#039;s Associate Head Coach at Wesleyan University from &#039;96-&#039;02, a position he returned to in 2006. While at Trinity, he took seven crews to the Henley Royal Regatta; winning the Ladies&#039; Plate in 1976 and lowering the course record six seconds.We will remember Norm for his leadership, teaching gifts, rigor and attention to detail - coupled with a keen sense of humor and deep appreciation of the good things in life. RIP Norm.Trinity Rowing remembrance and an 80th birthday video, including lots of footage from the Trinity College crews of the 70s.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 15:21:29 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[At the age of 92, Norman Graf passed away yesterday, September 23, 2018. Norm coached at the Center for almost 20 years, serving as Sculling Program Director for 11 years.Norm began rowing in 1940. He rowed with the undefeated Culver Military Academy 8+ in 1943. His rowing career took a hiatus during World War II, but in &#039;48 he returned to the sport as stroke and captain of the undefeated Rutgers University freshmen team. In the late &#039;50s Norm began coaching at Yale. In &#039;67 he became the Head Rowing Coach and Intramural Athletic Director at Trinity College in Connecticut, a position he held for 15 years. Norm was the varsity women&#039;s coach at Trinity from &#039;86-&#039;92, and the Men&#039;s Associate Head Coach at Wesleyan University from &#039;96-&#039;02, a position he returned to in 2006. While at Trinity, he took seven crews to the Henley Royal Regatta; winning the Ladies&#039; Plate in 1976 and lowering the course record six seconds.We will remember Norm for his leadership, teaching gifts, rigor and attention to detail - coupled with a keen sense of humor and deep appreciation of the good things in life. RIP Norm.Trinity Rowing remembrance and an 80th birthday video, including lots of footage from the Trinity College crews of the 70s. <img src="/assets/bulkUpload/Cmill-RIP-Norm-Graf-1.jpg" alt="Cmill RIP Norm Graf 1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2111/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>World Rowing Championships Results: Davison/Graves place 14th</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2109/</link>
			<description>In the long-awaited finale to their 2018 summer, the USA Men’s Double Sculls (2x) comprised of Ben Davison (stroke) and John Graves (bow) - finally got to put all of their hard work to the test at the 2018 World Rowing Championships (Plovdiv, BUL), and came away with a 14th place finish.The duo had a busy summer of international racing. Preparations for Bulgaria solidified after the 2x won domestically at Senior Trials I. At the same regatta, Ben was named the U23 1x; and, at the end of July, raced to a 4th place finish at U23 Worlds. In mid July, John and Ben placed first in the B final at World Cup III. Once back in Craftsbury, Ben and John spent the next month prepping for World Championships. With race countdown at just over a week, the 2x and Coach Whelpley departed for Bulgaria.Ben and John made their World Championship debut as the USA Men&#039;s 2x on September 9, placing 3rd in their heat (6:15.990) behind Great Britain (6:10.07) and Norway (6:14.67), meaning their path to the finals went through the repechage. Needing a top-two finish in their repechage on September 13th, the 2x knew they had a tough race ahead of them. In the build up to racing, Ben recalls feeling that “the boat was going better than it ever had”; but, unfortunately, their time of (6:21.80) behind last year’s silver medalist - Poland (6:19.29) - and this year’s eventual silver medalist - Switzerland (6:18.06) - was not enough to secure them a position in the A/B Semifinal race; and, effectively, eliminated the possibility of a podium finish. “After a sluggish start in the heat” Ben continues, “ and tough draw in the rep, it felt like our hunt for medals was over before it even started.” John thought that their best race was the rep, despite getting “a really tough draw” for that race.Friday the 14th, the 2x took first in their C/D semifinal (6:26.84), nearly three seconds ahead of the second (Slovenia, 6:29.28) and third (Croatia, 6:34.57) place finishers. They did not race on Saturday; instead they took time to recover and prepare for Sunday’s final.Coach Whelpley weighed in on their performance at World Championships, emphasizing the high quality of racing in the Men’s double sculls across the board. “Ben and John continued to hang with a noticeably thick and competitive doubles field. They did not have the best of luck through the progression, but still did their best to rise to each unique situation and raise the standards of their rowing as the regatta progressed.&quot;On Sunday, Ben and John lined up for what would be their last race of the 2018 World Rowing Championships. When all was said and done, they crossed the finish line (6:19.17) behind Argentina (6:15.58), taking their spot as the world&#039;s 14th fastest men&#039;s double of 2018. Ukraine (6:20.87); Greece (6:25.60); and Croatia (6:26.23) rounded out the rest of the field in the C final. John conceded to feeling that they “ struggled in tough conditions in the final”, and that “Overall, [they] are disappointed in the result”; but the boat as a whole shares in the same sense of determination and excitement for the year of training ahead. They are now on the search for more speed as they attempt to qualify the boat for Tokyo. And, if they are able to make some “slight tweaks” says John, the Olympic Qualification placement of top 11 at next year&#039;s Worlds could very well become a reality. The guys are both entered in the Head of the Charles in the Championship 1x “so our focus will be on that for now.” John will continue training in the 1x, while Ben will return to The University of Washington, where he will finish out his last year of collegiate rowing eligibility.Congratulations to the 26 boat classes that represented Team USA at this year&#039;s Worlds! The USA came away with an exceptional medal count this year (the highest among all of the 26 competing countries, winning 10 medals total). Italy came away with the highest points accrued as they attained 3 Gold, 4 Silver, and 1 Bronze, while the USA saw 3 Gold, 3 Silver, and 4 Bronze medals across men, women, and Para Athletes. Women&#039;s EventsEight w/ cox (W8+), GoldFour w/o cox (W4-), GoldQuad (W4x), 6th (GRP Alum Alert, Elizabeth Sonshine)Double (W2x), BronzeLightweight Pair w/o cox (LW2-), SilverLightweight Double, (LW2x), SilverPara Single (PR1 W1x), BronzePara Pair (PR3 W2-), Gold Men&#039;s EventsEight w/ cox (M8+), 4th (GRP Alum Alert, Andrew Reed)Quad (M4x), 11th (GRP Alum Alert, Erik Frid)Double (M2x), 14th (Ben Davison, John Graves)Lightweight Pair w/o cox (LM2-), BronzeLightweight Double, (LW2x), 24th (GRP Alum Alert, Hugh McAdam)Lightweight Single (LW1x), Bronze Mixed EventsPara Mixed Four w/ cox (PR3 Mix4+), SilverNext up: Head of the Kevin II, Boston MA (Sept. 23), Green Mountain Head, Putney VT (Sept.30), Head of the Charles, Boston MA (Oct. 20-21), Head of the Fish, Saratoga Springs, NY (Oct. 27-28), Fall Speed Order, Princeton, NJ (Nov. 3), Pan American Games Trials, Rio ...</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 15:33:40 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[In the long-awaited finale to their 2018 summer, the USA Men’s Double Sculls (2x) comprised of Ben Davison (stroke) and John Graves (bow) - finally got to put all of their hard work to the test at the 2018 World Rowing Championships (Plovdiv, BUL), and came away with a 14th place finish.The duo had a busy summer of international racing. Preparations for Bulgaria solidified after the 2x won domestically at Senior Trials I. At the same regatta, Ben was named the U23 1x; and, at the end of July, raced to a 4th place finish at U23 Worlds. In mid July, John and Ben placed first in the B final at World Cup III. Once back in Craftsbury, Ben and John spent the next month prepping for World Championships. With race countdown at just over a week, the 2x and Coach Whelpley departed for Bulgaria.Ben and John made their World Championship debut as the USA Men&#039;s 2x on September 9, placing 3rd in their heat (6:15.990) behind Great Britain (6:10.07) and Norway (6:14.67), meaning their path to the finals went through the repechage. Needing a top-two finish in their repechage on September 13th, the 2x knew they had a tough race ahead of them. In the build up to racing, Ben recalls feeling that “the boat was going better than it ever had”; but, unfortunately, their time of (6:21.80) behind last year’s silver medalist - Poland (6:19.29) - and this year’s eventual silver medalist - Switzerland (6:18.06) - was not enough to secure them a position in the A/B Semifinal race; and, effectively, eliminated the possibility of a podium finish. “After a sluggish start in the heat” Ben continues, “ and tough draw in the rep, it felt like our hunt for medals was over before it even started.” John thought that their best race was the rep, despite getting “a really tough draw” for that race.Friday the 14th, the 2x took first in their C/D semifinal (6:26.84), nearly three seconds ahead of the second (Slovenia, 6:29.28) and third (Croatia, 6:34.57) place finishers. They did not race on Saturday; instead they took time to recover and prepare for Sunday’s final.Coach Whelpley weighed in on their performance at World Championships, emphasizing the high quality of racing in the Men’s double sculls across the board. “Ben and John continued to hang with a noticeably thick and competitive doubles field. They did not have the best of luck through the progression, but still did their best to rise to each unique situation and raise the standards of their rowing as the regatta progressed.&quot;On Sunday, Ben and John lined up for what would be their last race of the 2018 World Rowing Championships. When all was said and done, they crossed the finish line (6:19.17) behind Argentina (6:15.58), taking their spot as the world&#039;s 14th fastest men&#039;s double of 2018. Ukraine (6:20.87); Greece (6:25.60); and Croatia (6:26.23) rounded out the rest of the field in the C final. John conceded to feeling that they “ struggled in tough conditions in the final”, and that “Overall, [they] are disappointed in the result”; but the boat as a whole shares in the same sense of determination and excitement for the year of training ahead. They are now on the search for more speed as they attempt to qualify the boat for Tokyo. And, if they are able to make some “slight tweaks” says John, the Olympic Qualification placement of top 11 at next year&#039;s Worlds could very well become a reality. The guys are both entered in the Head of the Charles in the Championship 1x “so our focus will be on that for now.” John will continue training in the 1x, while Ben will return to The University of Washington, where he will finish out his last year of collegiate rowing eligibility.Congratulations to the 26 boat classes that represented Team USA at this year&#039;s Worlds! The USA came away with an exceptional medal count this year (the highest among all of the 26 competing countries, winning 10 medals total). Italy came away with the highest points accrued as they attained 3 Gold, 4 Silver, and 1 Bronze, while the USA saw 3 Gold, 3 Silver, and 4 Bronze medals across men, women, and Para Athletes. Women&#039;s EventsEight w/ cox (W8+), GoldFour w/o cox (W4-), GoldQuad (W4x), 6th (GRP Alum Alert, Elizabeth Sonshine)Double (W2x), BronzeLightweight Pair w/o cox (LW2-), SilverLightweight Double, (LW2x), SilverPara Single (PR1 W1x), BronzePara Pair (PR3 W2-), Gold Men&#039;s EventsEight w/ cox (M8+), 4th (GRP Alum Alert, Andrew Reed)Quad (M4x), 11th (GRP Alum Alert, Erik Frid)Double (M2x), 14th (Ben Davison, John Graves)Lightweight Pair w/o cox (LM2-), BronzeLightweight Double, (LW2x), 24th (GRP Alum Alert, Hugh McAdam)Lightweight Single (LW1x), Bronze Mixed EventsPara Mixed Four w/ cox (PR3 Mix4+), SilverNext up: Head of the Kevin II, Boston MA (Sept. 23), Green Mountain Head, Putney VT (Sept.30), Head of the Charles, Boston MA (Oct. 20-21), Head of the Fish, Saratoga Springs, NY (Oct. 27-28), Fall Speed Order, Princeton, NJ (Nov. 3), Pan American Games Trials, Rio ... <img src="/assets/bulkUpload/C23B0B3A-0C92-4B0B-AA74-18557F4D598E.jpeg" alt="C23B0B3A 0C92 4B0B AA74 18557F4D598E" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2109/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Green Racing Project Success at Pan American Games Trials</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2095/</link>
			<description>Last week marked the final summer racing for our Green Racing Project rowers as they took to the waters of Lake Mercer for the fifth time this summer for a couple of them. Our athletes continued the progress that they’ve had over the course of the summer at the Pan American Games Trials Regatta last Monday to determine who will represent the United States and the Pan American Games Qualifying Regatta in Rio de Janeiro on November 29th. Last week’s racing had a different format than has been used in the past with a morning time trial leading to a straight final of four boats in the afternoon. Taking the new format in stride… or should we say stroke?… all of our five boats advanced to their respective finals with Lucas Bellows leading off the Greenies for the day by placing third in the Men’s Single Sculls. Jenifer Forbes and Alex Spaulding followed in short order, placing first and third, respectively, in the Women’s Single Sculls. Rounding out the GRP time trials were Nathan Lado and Wes Vear in the Men’s Double Sculls as well as Frank Horpel in a composite lineup of Craftsbury and Oklahoma City High Performance Team’s Kevin Cardno, finishing first and fourth. On to the afternoon’s finals seven hours later. It was Craftsbury’s bowballs across the line first in all three of their events. Lucas Bellows once again started the Greenies off in their headwind racing conditions by winning his final with a time of 7:47.98 and a margin of more than four seconds over second place. Jenifer Forbes proceeded to win her final in a time of 8:29.51 and a two second margin over second place with Alex Spaulding rounding out fourth place with a time of 8:46.51. Nathan Lado and Wes Vear won their final with a time of 7:00.23 and one of the highest percentages of the day over second place of Frank Horpel’s GRP/OKC composite boat with a time of 7:09.48.The first place finishers have all accepted their bids which means that the GRP will be heading down to Rio de Janeiro on November 27th to race at the qualifying regatta. Qualifying crews from that regatta will then race at the Pan American Games next July in Lima, Peru.Go GRP, go Green!Full racing results can be found here!</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 07:12:18 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[Last week marked the final summer racing for our Green Racing Project rowers as they took to the waters of Lake Mercer for the fifth time this summer for a couple of them. Our athletes continued the progress that they’ve had over the course of the summer at the Pan American Games Trials Regatta last Monday to determine who will represent the United States and the Pan American Games Qualifying Regatta in Rio de Janeiro on November 29th. Last week’s racing had a different format than has been used in the past with a morning time trial leading to a straight final of four boats in the afternoon. Taking the new format in stride… or should we say stroke?… all of our five boats advanced to their respective finals with Lucas Bellows leading off the Greenies for the day by placing third in the Men’s Single Sculls. Jenifer Forbes and Alex Spaulding followed in short order, placing first and third, respectively, in the Women’s Single Sculls. Rounding out the GRP time trials were Nathan Lado and Wes Vear in the Men’s Double Sculls as well as Frank Horpel in a composite lineup of Craftsbury and Oklahoma City High Performance Team’s Kevin Cardno, finishing first and fourth. On to the afternoon’s finals seven hours later. It was Craftsbury’s bowballs across the line first in all three of their events. Lucas Bellows once again started the Greenies off in their headwind racing conditions by winning his final with a time of 7:47.98 and a margin of more than four seconds over second place. Jenifer Forbes proceeded to win her final in a time of 8:29.51 and a two second margin over second place with Alex Spaulding rounding out fourth place with a time of 8:46.51. Nathan Lado and Wes Vear won their final with a time of 7:00.23 and one of the highest percentages of the day over second place of Frank Horpel’s GRP/OKC composite boat with a time of 7:09.48.The first place finishers have all accepted their bids which means that the GRP will be heading down to Rio de Janeiro on November 27th to race at the qualifying regatta. Qualifying crews from that regatta will then race at the Pan American Games next July in Lima, Peru.Go GRP, go Green!Full racing results can be found here! <img src="/assets/bulkUpload/IMG-1164.jpg" alt="IMG 1164" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2095/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>U23 Worlds Results: Davison races to historic 4th, Dwinell &amp; Bilchik 5th in C Final</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2074/</link>
			<description>
GRP U23 athletes wrapped up racing yesterday at the Under 23 World Rowing Championships in Poznan, Poland which ran from July 25 - 29, 2018. 
Ben Davison had an impressive five days of racing as the USA’s U23 Men’s Single Sculler (BM1x). When all was said and done, he came away with a 4th place finish (06:55.250) in the A Final. Canada (6:48.70); Germany (6:48.700); and Bulgaria (6:51.420) took gold, silver, bronze, respectively. Ireland (6:59.570) and Brazil (7:06.45) took 5th and 6th place respectively. Although it was tough coming short of the podium, Ben’s performance was a historic best in this event; and, we are so proud of him for quietly and humbly showing his devotion to this sport though his racing and his actions off the water. This year marks Ben&#039;s 4th year with the GRP, his 3rd year racing the BM1x at worlds, and his last year of eligibility to race at the Under 23 level. Ben had two 1st place finishes in the B final for the U23 Men’s 1x in both 2015 and 2016. In 2017 Ben won a bronze medal in the U23 Men’s 4+ (with coxswain).
Evan Dwinell &amp;amp; Josh Bilchik (BM2x) placed 5th (7:13.65) ​in Saturday’s C Final ​behind Romania (6:55.39); Norway (6:55.51); Estonia (7:03.34) and Israel (7:07.22) who placed  1-4 in the C final respectively. Evan and Josh​ did a great job of putting together a lineup within just one month of arriving at Craftsbury this June. Before their summer at Craftsbury Evan and Josh had some sculling experience, but Evan noted that U23 Worlds Trials was his first experience with racing in a sculling shell. Evan placed 4th at the  2016 U23 World Champs in the Men&#039;s 4- (without coxswain) - and notes that aside from his gap year learning how to scull with the club Sarasota Crew, he has no prior sculling experience. In high school, Josh placed 3rd in the junior double at Youth Nationals; but, until this summer, he hadn&#039;t raced since. Well done, gentlemen!Team USA totaled 5 Gold Medals, 1 Silver Medal, and 2 Bronze Medals from worlds this year. Congratulations to all Team USA U23 athletes for your successes; and, to the winners and medalists - well rowed!!  Photo credit: USRowing (more photos here)Detailed results can be found at World RowingNext up...Ben + John take on Senior World Champs in the 2xGRP Senior Men race at Senior Worlds Trials II in their 1xsGRP U23ers race at Canadian HenleyGRP Senior Women race at PanAm Games Trials in their 1xs</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 22:08:24 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[
GRP U23 athletes wrapped up racing yesterday at the Under 23 World Rowing Championships in Poznan, Poland which ran from July 25 - 29, 2018. 
Ben Davison had an impressive five days of racing as the USA’s U23 Men’s Single Sculler (BM1x). When all was said and done, he came away with a 4th place finish (06:55.250) in the A Final. Canada (6:48.70); Germany (6:48.700); and Bulgaria (6:51.420) took gold, silver, bronze, respectively. Ireland (6:59.570) and Brazil (7:06.45) took 5th and 6th place respectively. Although it was tough coming short of the podium, Ben’s performance was a historic best in this event; and, we are so proud of him for quietly and humbly showing his devotion to this sport though his racing and his actions off the water. This year marks Ben&#039;s 4th year with the GRP, his 3rd year racing the BM1x at worlds, and his last year of eligibility to race at the Under 23 level. Ben had two 1st place finishes in the B final for the U23 Men’s 1x in both 2015 and 2016. In 2017 Ben won a bronze medal in the U23 Men’s 4+ (with coxswain).
Evan Dwinell &amp;amp; Josh Bilchik (BM2x) placed 5th (7:13.65) ​in Saturday’s C Final ​behind Romania (6:55.39); Norway (6:55.51); Estonia (7:03.34) and Israel (7:07.22) who placed  1-4 in the C final respectively. Evan and Josh​ did a great job of putting together a lineup within just one month of arriving at Craftsbury this June. Before their summer at Craftsbury Evan and Josh had some sculling experience, but Evan noted that U23 Worlds Trials was his first experience with racing in a sculling shell. Evan placed 4th at the  2016 U23 World Champs in the Men&#039;s 4- (without coxswain) - and notes that aside from his gap year learning how to scull with the club Sarasota Crew, he has no prior sculling experience. In high school, Josh placed 3rd in the junior double at Youth Nationals; but, until this summer, he hadn&#039;t raced since. Well done, gentlemen!Team USA totaled 5 Gold Medals, 1 Silver Medal, and 2 Bronze Medals from worlds this year. Congratulations to all Team USA U23 athletes for your successes; and, to the winners and medalists - well rowed!!  Photo credit: USRowing (more photos here)Detailed results can be found at World RowingNext up...Ben + John take on Senior World Champs in the 2xGRP Senior Men race at Senior Worlds Trials II in their 1xsGRP U23ers race at Canadian HenleyGRP Senior Women race at PanAm Games Trials in their 1xs <img src="/assets/Uploads/2018-U23WRC-M1x-Final-1-X3.jpg" alt="2018 U23WRC M1x Final 1 X3" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2074/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>USRowing Club Nationals Results: Horpel snags silver and bronze</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2068/</link>
			<description>GRP Senior Team scullers, Alex Spaulding and Frank Horpel competed this weekend in USRowing’s Club National Championships (Cooper River, Camden, NJ). Horpel and the composite crews he was a part of for the regatta - OKC and ARION (Oklahoma City High Performance Training Center and Advanced Rowing Initiative of the Northeast) - snagged a silver and bronze medal from the Men’s Elite 2x and Men’s Elite 4x, respectively. Spaulding placed 6th in Saturday’s 1900-meter time trial (7:37.118) and 4th (7:59.732) in her semifinal later that afternoon. Alex needed to place 3rd in order to advance to the finals. GRP U23 alumna Mickey Fili threw down the fasted time in the semi (7:48.256), and went on to win the event on Sunday (7:37.260). Always great to hear of success from our alums!The OKC/GRP composite double with OKC’s Kevin Cardno, and our own, Frank Horpel posted the 2nd fastest time in Saturday’s time trial (6:12.768) behind the ARION 2x (6:10.505) that contained Liam Casey, who raced with Horpel in the Men’s Elite 4x less than an hour later. The OKC/GRP/ARION composite quad of Matt Koehler/Kevin Cardno/Frank Horpel/Liam Casey posted the 5th best time trial time (5:57.041).The OKC/GRP 2x raced to a silver medal finish in Sunday afternoon’s final (6:34.679) behind gold medalist ARION (6:29.576). The OKC/GRP/ARION Men’s Elite 4x raced an hour later to a bronze medal finish (6:01.806) behind Penn AC’s B (6:00.858) and A boats (5:59.902).Great weekend of racing by our domestic crews. Thank you to Reilly Dampeer (OKCHPC) and to Eric Catalano (ARION) for collaborating with the GRP. Such collegial work is advancing the quality of elite sculling in the United States.Be sure to follow the GRP &amp;amp; COC on Instagram and Facebook for access to more news, pictures, and daily updates!GRP InstagramGRP FacebookCOC InstagramCOC Facebook</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 14:01:56 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[GRP Senior Team scullers, Alex Spaulding and Frank Horpel competed this weekend in USRowing’s Club National Championships (Cooper River, Camden, NJ). Horpel and the composite crews he was a part of for the regatta - OKC and ARION (Oklahoma City High Performance Training Center and Advanced Rowing Initiative of the Northeast) - snagged a silver and bronze medal from the Men’s Elite 2x and Men’s Elite 4x, respectively. Spaulding placed 6th in Saturday’s 1900-meter time trial (7:37.118) and 4th (7:59.732) in her semifinal later that afternoon. Alex needed to place 3rd in order to advance to the finals. GRP U23 alumna Mickey Fili threw down the fasted time in the semi (7:48.256), and went on to win the event on Sunday (7:37.260). Always great to hear of success from our alums!The OKC/GRP composite double with OKC’s Kevin Cardno, and our own, Frank Horpel posted the 2nd fastest time in Saturday’s time trial (6:12.768) behind the ARION 2x (6:10.505) that contained Liam Casey, who raced with Horpel in the Men’s Elite 4x less than an hour later. The OKC/GRP/ARION composite quad of Matt Koehler/Kevin Cardno/Frank Horpel/Liam Casey posted the 5th best time trial time (5:57.041).The OKC/GRP 2x raced to a silver medal finish in Sunday afternoon’s final (6:34.679) behind gold medalist ARION (6:29.576). The OKC/GRP/ARION Men’s Elite 4x raced an hour later to a bronze medal finish (6:01.806) behind Penn AC’s B (6:00.858) and A boats (5:59.902).Great weekend of racing by our domestic crews. Thank you to Reilly Dampeer (OKCHPC) and to Eric Catalano (ARION) for collaborating with the GRP. Such collegial work is advancing the quality of elite sculling in the United States.Be sure to follow the GRP &amp;amp; COC on Instagram and Facebook for access to more news, pictures, and daily updates!GRP InstagramGRP FacebookCOC InstagramCOC Facebook <img src="/assets/Uploads/image2.jpeg" alt="image2" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2068/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Results: GRP U23 &amp; Senior Trials 1, Davison/Graves + Dwinell/Bilchik to race at World Championships </title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2065/</link>
			<description>Hot on the heels of the 4th, 18 Green Racing Project rowers competed to represent the US at U23 Worlds and on the FISA World Cup/Senior World Championships later this season. Three GRP boats took the win and will represent the US internationally:  US M2x Ben Davison and John Graves, U23 US M2x Evan Dwinell and Josh Bilchik, and U23 M1x Ben Davison (doubling up with his Open M2x appearance). The winner of US Trials 1 earns the right to represent the United States at either U23 or Senior World Championships (or - SPOILER ALERT - in the case of Ben Davison, both). U23 World Championships run July 25 - 29 in Poznan, Poland. Senior World Championships run September 9 - 16 in Plovdiv, Bulgaria.12 GRP U23 athletes raced across eight U23 events, four GRP Senior team athletes fielded two Men’s doubles, and Senior GRPer Frank Horpel formed a composite entry in the Men’s 2x with Oklahoma City High Performance Training Center’s Kevin Cardno (coached by Reilly Dampeer).Men’s 2x: Ben Davison/John Graves; Wes Vear/Lucas Bellows ; Kevin Cardno (OKC)/ Frank Horpel (GRP)Davison/Graves were on a tear, winning the TT, heat, semi and final, leaving little doubt they were the US M2x for this summer. Vear/Bellows advanced to semis via the reps, as did Cardno/Horpel. Vear/Bellows qualified for the finals, ending the regatta 3rd.U23 Men’s 2- : Peter Chatain/Jack ReidChatain/Reid placed 4th in the U23 Men’s 2- (6:58.44, 87.9%).U23 Women’s 2x: Laura Hegemann/Macenzie KingAdvanced to the finals via the reps, placing 3rd (7:24.32, 89.3%).U23 Men’s 2x: Thomas Johnson/Mats Terwiesch ; Evan Dwinell/Josh BilchikDwinell/Bilchik won the U23 Men’s 2x (6:50.86, 87.6%) and the rights to race at U23 Worlds. Johnson/Terwiesch finished behind the other U23 2x with a 2nd (6:53.69, 87.0%).U23 Women’s Lightweight 1x: Jenny McIlvaneHaving gained finals via the reps, Jenny placed 3rd (8:13.86, 89.9%).U23 Men’s Lightweight 1x: Dom WilliamsWilliams missed 2nd place by four one-hundredths of a second (a bow ball) in a photo-finish and did not advance to Sunday’s Final. U23 Women’s 1x: Rhiannon MulliganMulligan placed 3rd in the U23 Women’s 1x (8:11.19, 86%), having advanced via the repechage.U23 Men’s 1x: Ben DavisonBen drained much of the drama from this contest as he did with John in the US M2x, winning the rights to race at U23 Worlds (7:04.33, 92.1%).U23 Men’s 4x: Evan Dwinell/Josh Bilchik/Mats Terwiesch/Dom WilliamsDwinell/Bilchik/Terswiesch/Williams placed (2nd) in their final (6:14.49, 88.7%)Congratulations to Ben, John, Evan and Josh for punching your tickets to Worlds! We are proud of all our athletes for well-representing the Green Racing Project last week, and are especially excited for the U23 athletes that - before coming to Craftsbury in June - had little to no prior sculling experience.A full lay out of results is available at HereNow. Race photos available on Row2k.Upcoming Races…Ben and John will race this weekend at World Cup III (Luzern, Switzerland) July 13 -15.Alex Spaulding &amp;amp; Frank Horpel will race this weekend at US Club Nationals. (Camden, NJ)Ben, Evan, and Josh’s will race at U23 World Championships (Poznan, Poland) July 25 - 29Ben &amp;amp; John will race at Senior World Championships (Plovdiv, Bulgaria) September 9 - 16Check back here, Facebook, or Instagram for updates on racing. Go GRP, Go USA!Thank you to Rob Pungello for providing access to the photos of our GRP athletes competing at Worlds Trials.You can see more of Rob&#039;s work on his Instagram, @rpungello or web page </description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2018 05:06:08 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[Hot on the heels of the 4th, 18 Green Racing Project rowers competed to represent the US at U23 Worlds and on the FISA World Cup/Senior World Championships later this season. Three GRP boats took the win and will represent the US internationally:  US M2x Ben Davison and John Graves, U23 US M2x Evan Dwinell and Josh Bilchik, and U23 M1x Ben Davison (doubling up with his Open M2x appearance). The winner of US Trials 1 earns the right to represent the United States at either U23 or Senior World Championships (or - SPOILER ALERT - in the case of Ben Davison, both). U23 World Championships run July 25 - 29 in Poznan, Poland. Senior World Championships run September 9 - 16 in Plovdiv, Bulgaria.12 GRP U23 athletes raced across eight U23 events, four GRP Senior team athletes fielded two Men’s doubles, and Senior GRPer Frank Horpel formed a composite entry in the Men’s 2x with Oklahoma City High Performance Training Center’s Kevin Cardno (coached by Reilly Dampeer).Men’s 2x: Ben Davison/John Graves; Wes Vear/Lucas Bellows ; Kevin Cardno (OKC)/ Frank Horpel (GRP)Davison/Graves were on a tear, winning the TT, heat, semi and final, leaving little doubt they were the US M2x for this summer. Vear/Bellows advanced to semis via the reps, as did Cardno/Horpel. Vear/Bellows qualified for the finals, ending the regatta 3rd.U23 Men’s 2- : Peter Chatain/Jack ReidChatain/Reid placed 4th in the U23 Men’s 2- (6:58.44, 87.9%).U23 Women’s 2x: Laura Hegemann/Macenzie KingAdvanced to the finals via the reps, placing 3rd (7:24.32, 89.3%).U23 Men’s 2x: Thomas Johnson/Mats Terwiesch ; Evan Dwinell/Josh BilchikDwinell/Bilchik won the U23 Men’s 2x (6:50.86, 87.6%) and the rights to race at U23 Worlds. Johnson/Terwiesch finished behind the other U23 2x with a 2nd (6:53.69, 87.0%).U23 Women’s Lightweight 1x: Jenny McIlvaneHaving gained finals via the reps, Jenny placed 3rd (8:13.86, 89.9%).U23 Men’s Lightweight 1x: Dom WilliamsWilliams missed 2nd place by four one-hundredths of a second (a bow ball) in a photo-finish and did not advance to Sunday’s Final. U23 Women’s 1x: Rhiannon MulliganMulligan placed 3rd in the U23 Women’s 1x (8:11.19, 86%), having advanced via the repechage.U23 Men’s 1x: Ben DavisonBen drained much of the drama from this contest as he did with John in the US M2x, winning the rights to race at U23 Worlds (7:04.33, 92.1%).U23 Men’s 4x: Evan Dwinell/Josh Bilchik/Mats Terwiesch/Dom WilliamsDwinell/Bilchik/Terswiesch/Williams placed (2nd) in their final (6:14.49, 88.7%)Congratulations to Ben, John, Evan and Josh for punching your tickets to Worlds! We are proud of all our athletes for well-representing the Green Racing Project last week, and are especially excited for the U23 athletes that - before coming to Craftsbury in June - had little to no prior sculling experience.A full lay out of results is available at HereNow. Race photos available on Row2k.Upcoming Races…Ben and John will race this weekend at World Cup III (Luzern, Switzerland) July 13 -15.Alex Spaulding &amp;amp; Frank Horpel will race this weekend at US Club Nationals. (Camden, NJ)Ben, Evan, and Josh’s will race at U23 World Championships (Poznan, Poland) July 25 - 29Ben &amp;amp; John will race at Senior World Championships (Plovdiv, Bulgaria) September 9 - 16Check back here, Facebook, or Instagram for updates on racing. Go GRP, Go USA!Thank you to Rob Pungello for providing access to the photos of our GRP athletes competing at Worlds Trials.You can see more of Rob&#039;s work on his Instagram, @rpungello or web page  <img src="/assets/Uploads/IMG-9673.jpg" alt="IMG 9673" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2065/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>2018 U23 Rowers</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2060/</link>
			<description>As U23 Trials in Princeton, NJ approach, we would like to introduce this year’s batch of U23 rowers to the Craftsbury community. Consisting of ten new faces plus our resident U23 athlete, these rowers have joined us at the Outdoor Center from all over the country. For those unfamiliar with the Center’s support of aspiring professional rowers and skiers, each summer, the Center accepts athletes from across the country to come live and train at the Center. These U23 athletes train alongside our year-round, post-collegiate athletes who train towards the Olympics in rowing, skiing, and biathlon. They help work on the various aspects of Center’s mission of lifelong sports and sustainability while they train over the summer. The U23 rowers that join us have the goal of winning U23 Trials in their respective boat class to race for the United States at the World Rowing Under 23 Championships, this year in Poznan, Poland July 25-28. The Center has sent many rowers over the years to the U23 World Championships and we’re looking forward to seeing this batch of athletes race next week in Princeton!Information about U23 Trials can be found here!Results will be posted here!</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2018 17:21:35 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[As U23 Trials in Princeton, NJ approach, we would like to introduce this year’s batch of U23 rowers to the Craftsbury community. Consisting of ten new faces plus our resident U23 athlete, these rowers have joined us at the Outdoor Center from all over the country. For those unfamiliar with the Center’s support of aspiring professional rowers and skiers, each summer, the Center accepts athletes from across the country to come live and train at the Center. These U23 athletes train alongside our year-round, post-collegiate athletes who train towards the Olympics in rowing, skiing, and biathlon. They help work on the various aspects of Center’s mission of lifelong sports and sustainability while they train over the summer. The U23 rowers that join us have the goal of winning U23 Trials in their respective boat class to race for the United States at the World Rowing Under 23 Championships, this year in Poznan, Poland July 25-28. The Center has sent many rowers over the years to the U23 World Championships and we’re looking forward to seeing this batch of athletes race next week in Princeton!Information about U23 Trials can be found here!Results will be posted here! <img src="/assets/Uploads/IMG-20180629-091430.jpg" alt="IMG 20180629 091430" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2060/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>2018 Sculling Interns </title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2051/</link>
			<description>Sculling camps have now been underway for just over a month, and those of you who have already attended camps (or CommRow) have no doubt been assisted by our fantastic interns. Each year, high school and collegiate rowers from around the country apply for our student internship program, and while it was difficult to select only 16 from an excellent pool of applicants, we&#039;re thrilled to announce our 2018 interns: Returning InternsMax Borrmann, May 29 - June 15Max Borrmann is a rising junior at Middlebury College in Middlebury, Vermont. Max is originally from Northeast Ohio, not too far from Cleveland. Max started sweep rowing as a novice during the fall of his first year at Middlebury. He began learning how to scull as an intern at Craftsbury last summer. In addition to rowing, Max is an avid runner. Max is looking forward to being back at Craftsbury this summer, sculling and working with campers and coaches on Great Hosmer Pond.Jon Hoey, June 17 - July 2Jon Hoey is a rising sophomore at Middlebury College in Vermont where he intends to study Economics.  He began his rowing career at St. John’s High School in Shrewsbury, MA in the fall of freshman year and has loved the sport ever since.  While Jon mostly rows sweep in-season, during the summer he sculls at the QRC in Worcester, MA.  This is Jon’s third summer interning at Craftsbury and he is more excited than ever to meet, work, and row with new people. Josie Konopka, July 8 - 20 Josie started rowing the summer before her freshman year of high school and has continued to row for all four years. This year, she graduated from the Episcopal Academy and will attend the University of Pennsylvania this coming fall. Josie has experience in both sculling and sweeping and is looking forward to what she can learn at Craftsbury. Andrew Maritan, May 29 - June 8 and August 26 - September 7Andrew is from Medfield, Massachusetts and currently attends Middlebury College where he studies Biology. He transitioned from swimming to rowing his freshman year and quickly fell in love with this water sport. He is currently the captain of the Middlebury Crew Team. This is his second year at Craftsbury and he looks forward to improving his technical rowing while meeting rowers from all over the country while here.Alexei Sondergeld, May 10 - 25Alexei graduated from UConn with a degree in Mechanical Engineering. He will be attending Boston University as a Ph.D. student beginning in the fall, and is looking forward to rowing regularly on the Charles River. He competed on Riverfront Recapture’s juniors sweep team from 2012 to 2016 and continues to scull competitively. He became a sculling addict from the first day that he ever rowed a single and saved enough to buy his own single. Competing in an open-water sculling event is next on Alexei’s list of lifetime goals.First-Time Interns Lindsay Albert, July 8 - 20Lindsay just finished her senior year at Lexington High School, in Massachusetts.  She began rowing as a novice at CRI in 2016 and just finished her first full year on the varsity team.  Before discovering rowing, Lindsay trained as a competitive gymnast for twelve years.  She will be attending Boston University in the fall, where she will continue rowing on the varsity lightweight team. This will be her second time at Craftsbury, and she&#039;s super stoked to be back!Valerie Blakely, August 19 - 26Valerie is a rising junior at Middlebury College where she rows on the women&#039;s crew team. She started rowing after playing volleyball for nine years, and her first time ever in a boat was at a sculling camp here at Craftsbury two years ago. She is majoring in Environmental Studies with a focus in Philosophy, and is minoring in Biology. She is excited about being at Craftsbury because it means spending time outside, learning more about sculling, and getting to know lots of new people.  Susanna Bruce, August 5 - 17Susanna Bruce is an upcoming senior at Easton High School in Easton Maryland. She rows for a club team located there called Freedom Rowers. She began rowing her freshman year and, in the beginning of her junior year, she was named team captain. Susanna joined the rowing team to cross-train for her competitive swim career, but ended up falling in love with the sport, especially the sculling aspect. She has been sculling since her sophomore year and most notably attended the Youth Regional Challenged wherein she raced in a quad. This summer, Susanna is planning on attending the Ready Set Row Dev camp, in addition to being an intern. At Craftsbury, she wishes improve her technique and gain more knowledge about the sport to help because she plans on rowing in college. Kathryn Campbell, August 19 - 31Kathryn is in grade 11 at Citadel High School in Halifax, Nova Scotia. She started recreational rowing in the summer of 2016 at Halifax Rowing Club, and started competing in the fall. She fell in love with the being on the water after her first row. She ...</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 14:56:17 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[Sculling camps have now been underway for just over a month, and those of you who have already attended camps (or CommRow) have no doubt been assisted by our fantastic interns. Each year, high school and collegiate rowers from around the country apply for our student internship program, and while it was difficult to select only 16 from an excellent pool of applicants, we&#039;re thrilled to announce our 2018 interns: Returning InternsMax Borrmann, May 29 - June 15Max Borrmann is a rising junior at Middlebury College in Middlebury, Vermont. Max is originally from Northeast Ohio, not too far from Cleveland. Max started sweep rowing as a novice during the fall of his first year at Middlebury. He began learning how to scull as an intern at Craftsbury last summer. In addition to rowing, Max is an avid runner. Max is looking forward to being back at Craftsbury this summer, sculling and working with campers and coaches on Great Hosmer Pond.Jon Hoey, June 17 - July 2Jon Hoey is a rising sophomore at Middlebury College in Vermont where he intends to study Economics.  He began his rowing career at St. John’s High School in Shrewsbury, MA in the fall of freshman year and has loved the sport ever since.  While Jon mostly rows sweep in-season, during the summer he sculls at the QRC in Worcester, MA.  This is Jon’s third summer interning at Craftsbury and he is more excited than ever to meet, work, and row with new people. Josie Konopka, July 8 - 20 Josie started rowing the summer before her freshman year of high school and has continued to row for all four years. This year, she graduated from the Episcopal Academy and will attend the University of Pennsylvania this coming fall. Josie has experience in both sculling and sweeping and is looking forward to what she can learn at Craftsbury. Andrew Maritan, May 29 - June 8 and August 26 - September 7Andrew is from Medfield, Massachusetts and currently attends Middlebury College where he studies Biology. He transitioned from swimming to rowing his freshman year and quickly fell in love with this water sport. He is currently the captain of the Middlebury Crew Team. This is his second year at Craftsbury and he looks forward to improving his technical rowing while meeting rowers from all over the country while here.Alexei Sondergeld, May 10 - 25Alexei graduated from UConn with a degree in Mechanical Engineering. He will be attending Boston University as a Ph.D. student beginning in the fall, and is looking forward to rowing regularly on the Charles River. He competed on Riverfront Recapture’s juniors sweep team from 2012 to 2016 and continues to scull competitively. He became a sculling addict from the first day that he ever rowed a single and saved enough to buy his own single. Competing in an open-water sculling event is next on Alexei’s list of lifetime goals.First-Time Interns Lindsay Albert, July 8 - 20Lindsay just finished her senior year at Lexington High School, in Massachusetts.  She began rowing as a novice at CRI in 2016 and just finished her first full year on the varsity team.  Before discovering rowing, Lindsay trained as a competitive gymnast for twelve years.  She will be attending Boston University in the fall, where she will continue rowing on the varsity lightweight team. This will be her second time at Craftsbury, and she&#039;s super stoked to be back!Valerie Blakely, August 19 - 26Valerie is a rising junior at Middlebury College where she rows on the women&#039;s crew team. She started rowing after playing volleyball for nine years, and her first time ever in a boat was at a sculling camp here at Craftsbury two years ago. She is majoring in Environmental Studies with a focus in Philosophy, and is minoring in Biology. She is excited about being at Craftsbury because it means spending time outside, learning more about sculling, and getting to know lots of new people.  Susanna Bruce, August 5 - 17Susanna Bruce is an upcoming senior at Easton High School in Easton Maryland. She rows for a club team located there called Freedom Rowers. She began rowing her freshman year and, in the beginning of her junior year, she was named team captain. Susanna joined the rowing team to cross-train for her competitive swim career, but ended up falling in love with the sport, especially the sculling aspect. She has been sculling since her sophomore year and most notably attended the Youth Regional Challenged wherein she raced in a quad. This summer, Susanna is planning on attending the Ready Set Row Dev camp, in addition to being an intern. At Craftsbury, she wishes improve her technique and gain more knowledge about the sport to help because she plans on rowing in college. Kathryn Campbell, August 19 - 31Kathryn is in grade 11 at Citadel High School in Halifax, Nova Scotia. She started recreational rowing in the summer of 2016 at Halifax Rowing Club, and started competing in the fall. She fell in love with the being on the water after her first row. She ... <img src="/assets/bulkUpload/IMG-5864.jpg" alt="IMG 5864" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2051/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Rowers compete at 53rd HOCR and prep for Schuylkill</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1907/</link>
			<description>This past weekend 13 COC affiliated athletes competed in The 53rd Annual Head of the Charles Regatta. The athletes enjoyed great weather with temperatures reaching the mid-seventies and manageable winds for the majority of the weekend. The Head of the Charles is a 4800 meter race in Boston, MA that requires athletes to safely travel under six bridges, make three turns to port, and two turns to starboard. Racers must balance their hardest rowing piece against steering the fastest course in order to perform well. Collisions with other crews, skipping buoys, going through the incorrect arches, and violating the traffic pattern all result in time penalties; it&#039;s incumbent upon the athletes to know the course well.  Green Racing Project athletes: John Graves, Wes Vear, Nathan Lado, Jen Forbes, and Jenny McIlvane saw favorable results in their singles this past weekend, and are currently  preparing for their next race (Head of the Schuylkill Regatta) that will take place this weekend in Philadelphia, PA.Graves, Lado, and Vear are in the running for the The Lotman Challenge - a Triple Crown for Rowing - that awards cash prizes to the top three male and female scullers who have accrued the highest collection of points based on their performance at three previously-selected regattas in 2017.  Scullers must compete in the USRowing Club National Championships, Head of the Charles, and Head of the Schuylkill in order to be eligible for this award. With two-thirds of the races now completed, John Graves is the Lotman Challenge leader with 26 points; his brother Tom (New York AC) with 24; and, Wes Vear, at a close third, with 22 points. Nathan Lado holds the fifth place slot with 16 points. Detailed results from The Head of the Charles Regatta are below:Men&#039;s Grand Masters 1x - 51 entriesBow #9: Troy Howell (6th)(19:12.113)Winning time: Gregory Benning, Cambridge Boat Club (18:26.751) Men&#039;s Senior Masters 8+ - 57 entriesBow #27 : Motley Crew (38th)*this year marked the Motley Crew’s 39th consecutive race together*Dick Dreissigacker (7 seat)Peter Dreissigacker (6 seat)Larry Gluckman (5 seat)(17:34.299)Winning time: Marin (15:28.144) Women&#039;s Senior Masters 8+ - 36 entriesBow #14 : 1980 Rowing Club (15th)Judy Geer (3 seat)Carlie Geer (bow)(18:57.744)Winning time: Chinook (17:22.899) Women’s Alumni 8+ - 43 entriesBow #28: Middlebury Alums (37th)Erika Sloan (stroke)(19:40.16) Winning time: UVA Alumni (15:48.524) Men&#039;s Alumni 8+ - 50 entriesBow #29: Messalonskee Rowing Club (28th)Steve Whelpley (7 seat)(16:18.819)Winning time: BMA Boat Club (14:42.019) Men&#039;s Champ 1x - 22 entriesBow #1: John Graves (2nd)(17:59.696)Bow #15: Wes Vear (9th)(18:34.275)Bow #14: Nathan Lado (14th)(18:53.939)Winning time: Michael Schmid, See-Club Luzern (17:56.416)Women&#039;s Champ 1x - 23 entriesBow #18: Jen Forbes (13th)(19:49.341)Winning time: Gevvie Stone, Cambridge Boat Club (18:44.210)Women&#039;s Lightweight 1x - 15 entriesBow #4 Jenny McIlvane (6th)(20:26.380)Winning time: Juliane Rasmussen, Odder Roklub (19:18.091)--To see more results from Head of the Charles, go to Regatta Central Photo coverage of the regatta can be found at Row2k , Sculling Fool, and Sport Graphics--Article contributor:Jenifer Forbes </description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 19:20:05 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[This past weekend 13 COC affiliated athletes competed in The 53rd Annual Head of the Charles Regatta. The athletes enjoyed great weather with temperatures reaching the mid-seventies and manageable winds for the majority of the weekend. The Head of the Charles is a 4800 meter race in Boston, MA that requires athletes to safely travel under six bridges, make three turns to port, and two turns to starboard. Racers must balance their hardest rowing piece against steering the fastest course in order to perform well. Collisions with other crews, skipping buoys, going through the incorrect arches, and violating the traffic pattern all result in time penalties; it&#039;s incumbent upon the athletes to know the course well.  Green Racing Project athletes: John Graves, Wes Vear, Nathan Lado, Jen Forbes, and Jenny McIlvane saw favorable results in their singles this past weekend, and are currently  preparing for their next race (Head of the Schuylkill Regatta) that will take place this weekend in Philadelphia, PA.Graves, Lado, and Vear are in the running for the The Lotman Challenge - a Triple Crown for Rowing - that awards cash prizes to the top three male and female scullers who have accrued the highest collection of points based on their performance at three previously-selected regattas in 2017.  Scullers must compete in the USRowing Club National Championships, Head of the Charles, and Head of the Schuylkill in order to be eligible for this award. With two-thirds of the races now completed, John Graves is the Lotman Challenge leader with 26 points; his brother Tom (New York AC) with 24; and, Wes Vear, at a close third, with 22 points. Nathan Lado holds the fifth place slot with 16 points. Detailed results from The Head of the Charles Regatta are below:Men&#039;s Grand Masters 1x - 51 entriesBow #9: Troy Howell (6th)(19:12.113)Winning time: Gregory Benning, Cambridge Boat Club (18:26.751) Men&#039;s Senior Masters 8+ - 57 entriesBow #27 : Motley Crew (38th)*this year marked the Motley Crew’s 39th consecutive race together*Dick Dreissigacker (7 seat)Peter Dreissigacker (6 seat)Larry Gluckman (5 seat)(17:34.299)Winning time: Marin (15:28.144) Women&#039;s Senior Masters 8+ - 36 entriesBow #14 : 1980 Rowing Club (15th)Judy Geer (3 seat)Carlie Geer (bow)(18:57.744)Winning time: Chinook (17:22.899) Women’s Alumni 8+ - 43 entriesBow #28: Middlebury Alums (37th)Erika Sloan (stroke)(19:40.16) Winning time: UVA Alumni (15:48.524) Men&#039;s Alumni 8+ - 50 entriesBow #29: Messalonskee Rowing Club (28th)Steve Whelpley (7 seat)(16:18.819)Winning time: BMA Boat Club (14:42.019) Men&#039;s Champ 1x - 22 entriesBow #1: John Graves (2nd)(17:59.696)Bow #15: Wes Vear (9th)(18:34.275)Bow #14: Nathan Lado (14th)(18:53.939)Winning time: Michael Schmid, See-Club Luzern (17:56.416)Women&#039;s Champ 1x - 23 entriesBow #18: Jen Forbes (13th)(19:49.341)Winning time: Gevvie Stone, Cambridge Boat Club (18:44.210)Women&#039;s Lightweight 1x - 15 entriesBow #4 Jenny McIlvane (6th)(20:26.380)Winning time: Juliane Rasmussen, Odder Roklub (19:18.091)--To see more results from Head of the Charles, go to Regatta Central Photo coverage of the regatta can be found at Row2k , Sculling Fool, and Sport Graphics--Article contributor:Jenifer Forbes  <img src="/assets/bulkUpload/320-WchTrls-2019.jpg" alt="320 WchTrls 2019" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1907/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Whelpley Returns to Craftsbury as GRP Coach</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1895/</link>
			<description>Craftsbury Outdoor Center is pleased to welcome back Green Racing Project alum Steve Whelpley as new Green Racing Project (GRP) Rowing Coach. Having first come to the Outdoor Center as a GRP sculler himself, Steve is uniquely suited to join us in this role, and as a member of our Sculling Management team. Steve will step into the position immediately, having just completed a summer of coaching Craftsbury’s U23 group. Before that, he served as assistant coach at Colby College, his alma mater.Steve’s rowing career spanned many years, the last 4 of which were spent at Craftsbury. He raced as the US M1x in 2013, the US M4x in 2014, and the M2x in the 2016 Olympic Trials Last Chance regatta.&quot;Coming back to Craftsbury as a coach may excite me even more than when I came as an athlete,” said Whelpley. “The environment, philosophy, and goals all align with what I hope to provide athletes with as a coach. With the community, resources, and blue skies of Craftsbury, I aim to make athletes better than I was and in less time.&quot;The Center is equally enthusiastic about Whelpley’s return in a new role. Craftsbury principals Dick Dreissigacker and Judy Geer commented, “Steve is a student of rowing and training and he brings a combination of experience, enthusiasm, and strong organizational and communication skills. He’s deeply motivated to help each GRP athlete achieve their best individually, and to assemble fast boats to represent the US.”If you’re an athlete interested in joining GRP this fall, feel free contact Steve at steve.whelpley@craftsbury.com, and find the application here.</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 15:41:48 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[Craftsbury Outdoor Center is pleased to welcome back Green Racing Project alum Steve Whelpley as new Green Racing Project (GRP) Rowing Coach. Having first come to the Outdoor Center as a GRP sculler himself, Steve is uniquely suited to join us in this role, and as a member of our Sculling Management team. Steve will step into the position immediately, having just completed a summer of coaching Craftsbury’s U23 group. Before that, he served as assistant coach at Colby College, his alma mater.Steve’s rowing career spanned many years, the last 4 of which were spent at Craftsbury. He raced as the US M1x in 2013, the US M4x in 2014, and the M2x in the 2016 Olympic Trials Last Chance regatta.&quot;Coming back to Craftsbury as a coach may excite me even more than when I came as an athlete,” said Whelpley. “The environment, philosophy, and goals all align with what I hope to provide athletes with as a coach. With the community, resources, and blue skies of Craftsbury, I aim to make athletes better than I was and in less time.&quot;The Center is equally enthusiastic about Whelpley’s return in a new role. Craftsbury principals Dick Dreissigacker and Judy Geer commented, “Steve is a student of rowing and training and he brings a combination of experience, enthusiasm, and strong organizational and communication skills. He’s deeply motivated to help each GRP athlete achieve their best individually, and to assemble fast boats to represent the US.”If you’re an athlete interested in joining GRP this fall, feel free contact Steve at steve.whelpley@craftsbury.com, and find the application here. <img src="/assets/bulkUpload/IMG-5170.jpg" alt="IMG 5170" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1895/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>SBTC Athletes Compete at World Rowing U23 Championships</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1879/</link>
			<description>This past week, the Craftsbury Outdoor Center had two of our SBTC athletes racing in Plovdiv, Bulgaria at the World Rowing U23 Championships. Nick Montalvo and Daniel Perez competed in the Men&#039;s Open weight Double with Linda Muri as their coach. The double placed 4th in their heat, sending them to a repechage where they again placed 4th. Their repechage advanced them to the C/D semifinal where they placed 4th. They then proceeded to finish 2nd in their final with a time of 6:37 despite a rib injury and illness while abroad. Now onto Canadian Henley with the rest of the SBTC athletes.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 20:37:37 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[This past week, the Craftsbury Outdoor Center had two of our SBTC athletes racing in Plovdiv, Bulgaria at the World Rowing U23 Championships. Nick Montalvo and Daniel Perez competed in the Men&#039;s Open weight Double with Linda Muri as their coach. The double placed 4th in their heat, sending them to a repechage where they again placed 4th. Their repechage advanced them to the C/D semifinal where they placed 4th. They then proceeded to finish 2nd in their final with a time of 6:37 despite a rib injury and illness while abroad. Now onto Canadian Henley with the rest of the SBTC athletes. <img src="/assets/bulkUpload/SBTC-letterhead.jpg" alt="SBTC letterhead" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1879/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>GRP Athletes Race at World Cup II and III and the Club National Championship</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1874/</link>
			<description>Over the past month, GRP athlete Hugh McAdam was in Europe racing at both the World Cup II in Poznan, Poland and the World Cup III in Lucerne, Switzerland representing the USA as the Lightweight Men&#039;s Single Sculls. In Poznan, McAdam placed second in his heat and then third in his repechage, progressing him to the C Final. Hugh then placed fifth in his final. In Lucerne, McAdam placed second in his heat and then fifth in his quarterfinal, progressing him to the C Final where he then came in third. This past week, GRP athlete Wesley Vear and former GRP athlete John Graves raced at the Club National Championships in Bethel, OH. They started the week off placing 6th and 1st, respectively, in the time trial for the Elite Single Sculls. They then placed third and first in each of their semifinal races to progress them to the A Final. On Friday, Graves came in second in the A final by a margin of less than a second after leading the entire race up until the last 100m with Vear placing 6th in the A final. Later that Friday afternoon, Vear raced in the Intermediate Single Sculls time trial, placing 6th. Saturday afternoon he then won his semifinal race with the second fastest time of the semifinals, advancing him to the final. In the final, Vear sat down on the field until the 1000m mark and then moved into second place behind Luke Rein from Undine where he finished, earning silver. The GRP athletes are now shifting back into preparation for Senior Trials in Princeton on August 6th.Results</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 07:31:00 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[Over the past month, GRP athlete Hugh McAdam was in Europe racing at both the World Cup II in Poznan, Poland and the World Cup III in Lucerne, Switzerland representing the USA as the Lightweight Men&#039;s Single Sculls. In Poznan, McAdam placed second in his heat and then third in his repechage, progressing him to the C Final. Hugh then placed fifth in his final. In Lucerne, McAdam placed second in his heat and then fifth in his quarterfinal, progressing him to the C Final where he then came in third. This past week, GRP athlete Wesley Vear and former GRP athlete John Graves raced at the Club National Championships in Bethel, OH. They started the week off placing 6th and 1st, respectively, in the time trial for the Elite Single Sculls. They then placed third and first in each of their semifinal races to progress them to the A Final. On Friday, Graves came in second in the A final by a margin of less than a second after leading the entire race up until the last 100m with Vear placing 6th in the A final. Later that Friday afternoon, Vear raced in the Intermediate Single Sculls time trial, placing 6th. Saturday afternoon he then won his semifinal race with the second fastest time of the semifinals, advancing him to the final. In the final, Vear sat down on the field until the 1000m mark and then moved into second place behind Luke Rein from Undine where he finished, earning silver. The GRP athletes are now shifting back into preparation for Senior Trials in Princeton on August 6th.Results <img src="/assets/bulkUpload/FullSizeRender4.jpg" alt="FullSizeRender4" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1874/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>John Graves Places Second in Henley Diamond Challenge Sculls</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1866/</link>
			<description>While the SBTC athletes were wrapping up U23 Trials racing in Princeton, John Graves was busy flying the GRP flag at the Henley Royal Regatta in England in the initial heats of the Diamond Challenge Sculls Cup. Racing as Craftsbury Sculling Center, John defeated M.P. O’Leary of Oxford. In the second round on Friday, John beat J.A. Kirkwood of Leander by 2 ¾ lengths and won his semifinal yesterday over J.B. Stimpson of Nottingham by 3 lengths, setting up a match with M.R.G. Dunham of Waiariki Rowing Club (New Zealand) at 11:20 today.The row2k website billed the matchup as “a streetfight” and they were not far from the mark with the prediction: John got out to an early lead of a little over a length by the Barrier, which is a little over two minutes into the race in singles.  He held roughly that margin for most of the body of the race. Somewhere between the halfway mark at Fawley and the Steward’s Enclosure near the finish line, it looked like John made a big push to break the race open but the Kiwi didn’t blink and kept coming; the final margin was Dunham over Graves by 1 ¾ lengths.  A great race by both men by any measure. Also noteworthy: John wore a GRP uni and rowed with U.S.A. blades throughout the regatta, and the race commentators gave a mid-race shout out to Craftsbury – John had included thanks for COC’s support in his notes to the regatta.  Well-rowed, Johnny.Row2k CoverageResults</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2017 16:04:45 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[While the SBTC athletes were wrapping up U23 Trials racing in Princeton, John Graves was busy flying the GRP flag at the Henley Royal Regatta in England in the initial heats of the Diamond Challenge Sculls Cup. Racing as Craftsbury Sculling Center, John defeated M.P. O’Leary of Oxford. In the second round on Friday, John beat J.A. Kirkwood of Leander by 2 ¾ lengths and won his semifinal yesterday over J.B. Stimpson of Nottingham by 3 lengths, setting up a match with M.R.G. Dunham of Waiariki Rowing Club (New Zealand) at 11:20 today.The row2k website billed the matchup as “a streetfight” and they were not far from the mark with the prediction: John got out to an early lead of a little over a length by the Barrier, which is a little over two minutes into the race in singles.  He held roughly that margin for most of the body of the race. Somewhere between the halfway mark at Fawley and the Steward’s Enclosure near the finish line, it looked like John made a big push to break the race open but the Kiwi didn’t blink and kept coming; the final margin was Dunham over Graves by 1 ¾ lengths.  A great race by both men by any measure. Also noteworthy: John wore a GRP uni and rowed with U.S.A. blades throughout the regatta, and the race commentators gave a mid-race shout out to Craftsbury – John had included thanks for COC’s support in his notes to the regatta.  Well-rowed, Johnny.Row2k CoverageResults <img src="/assets/Uploads/Untitled.png" alt="Untitled" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1866/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Welcome to the 2017 Summer SBTC Athletes </title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1855/</link>
			<description>We are happy to announce the roster for this year&#039;s Small Boat Training Center program.Check back later this month for bios of the athletes.  Nick Montalvo – University of WisconsinDaniel Perez – Dartmouth CollegeJennifer McIlvane – Cape Cod Brianna Wynne – University of WisconsinGrace Joyce – University of WisconsinMarilyn Garberg- University of WisconsinEmily Lane – University of New Hampshire    Kendall Sinosky – University of Southern California Ashley Johnson – Syracuse University Sydney Michalak – University of New Hampshire Drake Deuel – Dallas United Congrats to the 2017 SBTC Class!!  </description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 16:14:16 -0400</pubDate>
			
			
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1855/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>GRP Rowers McAdam, McIlvane, and Vear at Spring Speed Order</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1851/</link>
			<description>On April 18-21, three Green Racing Project rowers started their season off at the Spring Speed Order in Mercer Lake, NJ. As the first race of the 2017 rowing season, this year the Speed Order had no bearings towards World Cup or World Championships qualification later in the year, but was a good opportunity for the rowers to get in their first race efforts after a long winter of training and six weeks of on-water time in Sarasota, Florida.Hugh McAdam had the top GRP result of the week as the winner of the men’s lightweight single. McAdam took second in the time trial on Tuesday (the 18th), but went on to win his semifinal on Thursday. In Friday’s final he was behind off the start and chased down the Riverside sculler ahead of him to win by a 2 second margin. It’s a promising start to McAdam’s season as he looks towards World Cups and World Championships.Jenny McIlvane also competed for the GRP in the women’s lightweight single. She took 8th place in the time trial on Tuesday, then went on to place 4th in her semifinal, which qualified her for the B Final for Friday. She rowed well in the B Final and placed 2nd, good for 8th overall in the senior women’s lightweight field. McIlvane is still a U23 so she’ll be looking ahead to U23 Trials later this summer.Wes Vear competed in the men’s heavyweight single, his first 2k race in the single as a GRP rower. He placed 10th in the time trial, then took 3rd in his heat and made the B Final. His 6th place in the B Final netted him a 12th place overall in the men’s 1x field, a solid start to his first post-collegiate season.Also competing were GRP alums John Graves, Erik Frid, Liz Vogt, Elizabeth Sonshine, and Andrew Reed. John Graves and Erik Frid went 1-2 in the men’s heavyweight single, while Andrew Reed took 2nd in the men’s pair. Full results from the week of racing can be found on Row2k HERE. Next up for the rowers will be the National Selection Regatta 2, which starts on May 20th.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 11:08:36 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[On April 18-21, three Green Racing Project rowers started their season off at the Spring Speed Order in Mercer Lake, NJ. As the first race of the 2017 rowing season, this year the Speed Order had no bearings towards World Cup or World Championships qualification later in the year, but was a good opportunity for the rowers to get in their first race efforts after a long winter of training and six weeks of on-water time in Sarasota, Florida.Hugh McAdam had the top GRP result of the week as the winner of the men’s lightweight single. McAdam took second in the time trial on Tuesday (the 18th), but went on to win his semifinal on Thursday. In Friday’s final he was behind off the start and chased down the Riverside sculler ahead of him to win by a 2 second margin. It’s a promising start to McAdam’s season as he looks towards World Cups and World Championships.Jenny McIlvane also competed for the GRP in the women’s lightweight single. She took 8th place in the time trial on Tuesday, then went on to place 4th in her semifinal, which qualified her for the B Final for Friday. She rowed well in the B Final and placed 2nd, good for 8th overall in the senior women’s lightweight field. McIlvane is still a U23 so she’ll be looking ahead to U23 Trials later this summer.Wes Vear competed in the men’s heavyweight single, his first 2k race in the single as a GRP rower. He placed 10th in the time trial, then took 3rd in his heat and made the B Final. His 6th place in the B Final netted him a 12th place overall in the men’s 1x field, a solid start to his first post-collegiate season.Also competing were GRP alums John Graves, Erik Frid, Liz Vogt, Elizabeth Sonshine, and Andrew Reed. John Graves and Erik Frid went 1-2 in the men’s heavyweight single, while Andrew Reed took 2nd in the men’s pair. Full results from the week of racing can be found on Row2k HERE. Next up for the rowers will be the National Selection Regatta 2, which starts on May 20th. <img src="/assets/Uploads/WesSpeedOrder.jpg" alt="WesSpeedOrder" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1851/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Craftsbury Announces SBTC Rowing Coaches; Athlete Applications Due by May 1.</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1831/</link>
			<description>Craftsbury is excited to welcome new coaches for the summer U23 Small Boat Training Center program. This summer’s Lead Coach will be Linda Muri. Assisting her will be Steve Whelpley and our Sculling Director Troy Howell.Linda is currently the Women’s Coach at Dartmouth, having previously coached the Harvard Lightweights for 13 years. Before that she coached at Cornell. She has also coached a number of very successful US crews at U23, Junior and Senior World Championships. Not to mention her own medals in the Light Women’s Pair and Four.Steve was a Craftsbury Green Racing Project athlete for 4 years, during which time he represented the US as the single in Korea in 2013, and in the US men’s quad in 2014. He won the M2x Olympic Trials last summer, but just missed qualifying for Rio. He retired last fall and has been coaching at Colby College, his alma mater, this past year.The focus of the SBTC program is working in small boats, and especially sculling boats, with a goal of putting together crews that can win at the U23 Trials. Since the program’s inception in 2009, SBTC has sent seventeen trials winning crews overseas to U23 Worlds, including a bronze medal in the women’s 2X in 2010 (Elizabeth and Rebecca Donald) and the highest-ever finish by a U.S. men’s 1X (Ben Davison, won the B Final in both 2015 and 2016). Read more about the program here. Athletes will also compete at Canadian Henley, and possibly other summer regattas as well.Looking at a new quadrennial, involvement in the SBTC may also open future opportunities for those graduating to Senior events the following year as the GRP is open for applications as well. While SBTC aims to develop U23 athletes through their summers in small boats, the goal of the GRP is to establish one of the most internationally relevant and successful training centers in the United States through individualized and dynamic coaching, unparalleled support, incredibly healthy surroundings, and a very constructive local community.For athletes whose U23 eligibility runs out this year, you may qualify to join GRP after your summer with SBTC. If you are interested in this possibility, please indicate so on your application. Being part of SBTC does not guarantee admission to GRP, but it can help a lot.What does Craftsbury have to offer as a training center? Our goal is to make sure that each individual athlete gets the training and coaching they need to get faster. We strongly believe in the enormous value of small boat rowing in general, and sculling in particular, to make every athlete a more effective rower in any class of boat. Whether you’re a sweep rower wanting to switch to sculling, or you want to learn to scull to make you a better sweep rower, time spent in a single under the guidance of our experienced coaches will serve you well.There is no fee for these programs, however we do ask all of our athletes to contribute work hours to the Outdoor Center to partially cover room, board, coaching and race travel. </description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 14:25:46 -0500</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[Craftsbury is excited to welcome new coaches for the summer U23 Small Boat Training Center program. This summer’s Lead Coach will be Linda Muri. Assisting her will be Steve Whelpley and our Sculling Director Troy Howell.Linda is currently the Women’s Coach at Dartmouth, having previously coached the Harvard Lightweights for 13 years. Before that she coached at Cornell. She has also coached a number of very successful US crews at U23, Junior and Senior World Championships. Not to mention her own medals in the Light Women’s Pair and Four.Steve was a Craftsbury Green Racing Project athlete for 4 years, during which time he represented the US as the single in Korea in 2013, and in the US men’s quad in 2014. He won the M2x Olympic Trials last summer, but just missed qualifying for Rio. He retired last fall and has been coaching at Colby College, his alma mater, this past year.The focus of the SBTC program is working in small boats, and especially sculling boats, with a goal of putting together crews that can win at the U23 Trials. Since the program’s inception in 2009, SBTC has sent seventeen trials winning crews overseas to U23 Worlds, including a bronze medal in the women’s 2X in 2010 (Elizabeth and Rebecca Donald) and the highest-ever finish by a U.S. men’s 1X (Ben Davison, won the B Final in both 2015 and 2016). Read more about the program here. Athletes will also compete at Canadian Henley, and possibly other summer regattas as well.Looking at a new quadrennial, involvement in the SBTC may also open future opportunities for those graduating to Senior events the following year as the GRP is open for applications as well. While SBTC aims to develop U23 athletes through their summers in small boats, the goal of the GRP is to establish one of the most internationally relevant and successful training centers in the United States through individualized and dynamic coaching, unparalleled support, incredibly healthy surroundings, and a very constructive local community.For athletes whose U23 eligibility runs out this year, you may qualify to join GRP after your summer with SBTC. If you are interested in this possibility, please indicate so on your application. Being part of SBTC does not guarantee admission to GRP, but it can help a lot.What does Craftsbury have to offer as a training center? Our goal is to make sure that each individual athlete gets the training and coaching they need to get faster. We strongly believe in the enormous value of small boat rowing in general, and sculling in particular, to make every athlete a more effective rower in any class of boat. Whether you’re a sweep rower wanting to switch to sculling, or you want to learn to scull to make you a better sweep rower, time spent in a single under the guidance of our experienced coaches will serve you well.There is no fee for these programs, however we do ask all of our athletes to contribute work hours to the Outdoor Center to partially cover room, board, coaching and race travel.  <img src="/assets/bulkUpload/2017-LindaMuri.jpg" alt="2017 LindaMuri" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1831/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>DEC Lake Meeting</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1792/</link>
			<description>Saturday, January 21, 10:00am – tomorrow - the Department of Environmental Conservation (DEC) will be holding a public meeting in the Craftsbury Academy Gym. This past summer there were safety violations - specifically high-speed boats traveling too close to human-powered boats. These violations, taken in the context of ever-growing lake use by boats of all kinds, have raised concern at the State level, and they are considering establishing new rules for the lake. The Department of Environmental Conservation (DEC) is spearheading that process, and is gathering input from stakeholders about whether and how rule-making can reduce conflicts among users of Great Hosmer Pond.The Outdoor Center’s hope is to continue to offer programming of all kinds on Big Hosmer, as we have for over 40 years. The Center sees the lake as a valuable public resource that should be shared and enjoyed as widely as possible for the greater community’s benefit, while preserving the lake into the future and making sure that everyone has access. This fits our mission well - and we support many people’s access, through our sculling camps, our Community Rowing program, our GRP team and our waterfront canoes, kayaks and SUPs.Over the past 8 years, we&#039;ve voluntarily reduced our sculling programming, both in terms of number of camp sessions, scheduling holiday weekends free of sculling camps, as well as banning sculling from our docks for portions of the day. Beyond the impact on users&#039; access, our cuts have had a negative impact on the local economy — through fewer jobs, fewer hours worked, decreased Center purchasing from Vermont vendors, as well as visitor purchases made in town and around the area. Cuts also impact our ability to offer other programs that are not as self-sustaining as the sculling camps are; things like school programming, junior programming, community fitness, and affordable memberships or trail passes.If you&#039;re a lake user, are interested in advocating for ongoing use of the lake, or enjoy other facets of Center programming that sculling revenue facilitates, we invite you to join in the process this Saturday. You can read more about the challenges on Big Hosmer Pond in this story last June from Seven Days. Here’s a link if you missed it, and you can read more about the process from the DEC here.</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 10:38:10 -0500</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[Saturday, January 21, 10:00am – tomorrow - the Department of Environmental Conservation (DEC) will be holding a public meeting in the Craftsbury Academy Gym. This past summer there were safety violations - specifically high-speed boats traveling too close to human-powered boats. These violations, taken in the context of ever-growing lake use by boats of all kinds, have raised concern at the State level, and they are considering establishing new rules for the lake. The Department of Environmental Conservation (DEC) is spearheading that process, and is gathering input from stakeholders about whether and how rule-making can reduce conflicts among users of Great Hosmer Pond.The Outdoor Center’s hope is to continue to offer programming of all kinds on Big Hosmer, as we have for over 40 years. The Center sees the lake as a valuable public resource that should be shared and enjoyed as widely as possible for the greater community’s benefit, while preserving the lake into the future and making sure that everyone has access. This fits our mission well - and we support many people’s access, through our sculling camps, our Community Rowing program, our GRP team and our waterfront canoes, kayaks and SUPs.Over the past 8 years, we&#039;ve voluntarily reduced our sculling programming, both in terms of number of camp sessions, scheduling holiday weekends free of sculling camps, as well as banning sculling from our docks for portions of the day. Beyond the impact on users&#039; access, our cuts have had a negative impact on the local economy — through fewer jobs, fewer hours worked, decreased Center purchasing from Vermont vendors, as well as visitor purchases made in town and around the area. Cuts also impact our ability to offer other programs that are not as self-sustaining as the sculling camps are; things like school programming, junior programming, community fitness, and affordable memberships or trail passes.If you&#039;re a lake user, are interested in advocating for ongoing use of the lake, or enjoy other facets of Center programming that sculling revenue facilitates, we invite you to join in the process this Saturday. You can read more about the challenges on Big Hosmer Pond in this story last June from Seven Days. Here’s a link if you missed it, and you can read more about the process from the DEC here. <img src="/assets/bulkUpload/G0030271-pt.jpg" alt="G0030271 pt" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1792/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>GRPRow Opens Applications for 16-17</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1753/</link>
			<description>Craftsbury Green Racing Project Rowing is inviting applications to join the program this Fall/Winter. Applications will be reviewed on a rolling basis from now, acceptances may be issued any time between now and January 1.The GRP goal is for each athlete to reach their greatest potential and to achieve maximum results as individuals and as a team. We recognize that every individual is different and has different strengths and limiting factors. Therefore the same training protocol will not be optimal for everyone. We will maintain a process designed to determine how best to maximize each individual’s potential, and how to assure continuous progress. We want to have GRP athletes improving on all fronts – power, endurance, technique, and mental preparedness. A core belief of the GRP is that mastery of small boat rowing and sculling is key to athletes’ success in all boat classes, so a commitment to that on the part of each athlete is expected. Whether your ultimate goal is excellence in a sweep boat or helping to build fast US sculling boats, Craftsbury aims to help you get there.The Green Racing Project offers a unique training situation: every athlete trains and works at the Craftsbury Outdoor Center. In exchange for work hours, COC provides athletes with room, board, and training/travel expenses. Work assignments, generally related to the mission of the Outdoor Center, are managed cooperatively between the athletes, coaches, and COC staff. This provides some work-life balance, an opportunity to learn new skills or practice old ones, and ensures that work fits the training schedule. The winter offers some terrific cross-training in the form of cross-country skiing (we’ll teach you if you don’t know how) to supplement erg and strength work-and then the team travels south well ahead of NSR’s and trials.Our Sculling Director, Troy Howell, is currently coaching and managing the program. Additional coaches will be added in the coming months as we take on more athletes.For more info, see the FAQs, and find the application. Remaining questions? Don’t hesitate to e-mail smallboats@craftsbury.com.</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 07:59:52 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[Craftsbury Green Racing Project Rowing is inviting applications to join the program this Fall/Winter. Applications will be reviewed on a rolling basis from now, acceptances may be issued any time between now and January 1.The GRP goal is for each athlete to reach their greatest potential and to achieve maximum results as individuals and as a team. We recognize that every individual is different and has different strengths and limiting factors. Therefore the same training protocol will not be optimal for everyone. We will maintain a process designed to determine how best to maximize each individual’s potential, and how to assure continuous progress. We want to have GRP athletes improving on all fronts – power, endurance, technique, and mental preparedness. A core belief of the GRP is that mastery of small boat rowing and sculling is key to athletes’ success in all boat classes, so a commitment to that on the part of each athlete is expected. Whether your ultimate goal is excellence in a sweep boat or helping to build fast US sculling boats, Craftsbury aims to help you get there.The Green Racing Project offers a unique training situation: every athlete trains and works at the Craftsbury Outdoor Center. In exchange for work hours, COC provides athletes with room, board, and training/travel expenses. Work assignments, generally related to the mission of the Outdoor Center, are managed cooperatively between the athletes, coaches, and COC staff. This provides some work-life balance, an opportunity to learn new skills or practice old ones, and ensures that work fits the training schedule. The winter offers some terrific cross-training in the form of cross-country skiing (we’ll teach you if you don’t know how) to supplement erg and strength work-and then the team travels south well ahead of NSR’s and trials.Our Sculling Director, Troy Howell, is currently coaching and managing the program. Additional coaches will be added in the coming months as we take on more athletes.For more info, see the FAQs, and find the application. Remaining questions? Don’t hesitate to e-mail smallboats@craftsbury.com. <img src="/assets/bulkUpload/HOCR16-IMG-1917.jpg" alt="HOCR16 IMG 1917" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1753/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>GRPRow at Speed Orders</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1754/</link>
			<description>The GRPRowers completed their fall season last weekend at the East Coast Speed Order, in Princeton, NJ. Fall speed orders always feature a unique format, with racing consisting of a 6k erg on Saturday and a 4.35k race in a single on Sunday. For everyone who attended (including COC community rower, Annie Rowell), it was an opportunity to gauge their speed against a lot of other athletes, across a couple of platforms.After traveling most of Friday, it seemed like most of the athletes were slightly off their game for the Saturday morning erg. Wes, in the Men’s open weight single category, finished 14th with a time of 19:45. In the Women’s open weight single category, Annie Rowell and Liz Vogt finished 9th and 11th, with times of 22:33 and 22:47, respectively. Jenny McIlvane finished 5th in the Women’s lightweight single category, with a time of 23:43. Troy Howell, current coach for the GRP athletes, also played his hand at the races last weekend, competing in the Men’s open weight single category. On Saturday, he finished 27th, with a time of 21:10Sunday was more redeemable for all. Athletes started the Sunday’s based on the finishing order from the 6k erg. Liz and Annie finished 3rd and 10th, with times of 17:35 and 18:29, respectively. Liz was over a minute faster than she was last year! Wes finished 16th with a time of 16:40. Jenny finished 4th, with a time of 18:05. Finally, Troy finished 20th, with a time of 17:05.So what is next for the GRP rowers? As winter approaches, the lake will freeze and the athletes will transition to land training for the majority of the winter, utilizing the ergs and weight room in the COC gym and snow-covered trails around the center, doing as much volume and strength training as they can.The next races will be held in March and are the National Selection Regattas for the US National team qualification. Preparation for those races begins now!Saturday resultsSunday results</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 21:28:40 -0500</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[The GRPRowers completed their fall season last weekend at the East Coast Speed Order, in Princeton, NJ. Fall speed orders always feature a unique format, with racing consisting of a 6k erg on Saturday and a 4.35k race in a single on Sunday. For everyone who attended (including COC community rower, Annie Rowell), it was an opportunity to gauge their speed against a lot of other athletes, across a couple of platforms.After traveling most of Friday, it seemed like most of the athletes were slightly off their game for the Saturday morning erg. Wes, in the Men’s open weight single category, finished 14th with a time of 19:45. In the Women’s open weight single category, Annie Rowell and Liz Vogt finished 9th and 11th, with times of 22:33 and 22:47, respectively. Jenny McIlvane finished 5th in the Women’s lightweight single category, with a time of 23:43. Troy Howell, current coach for the GRP athletes, also played his hand at the races last weekend, competing in the Men’s open weight single category. On Saturday, he finished 27th, with a time of 21:10Sunday was more redeemable for all. Athletes started the Sunday’s based on the finishing order from the 6k erg. Liz and Annie finished 3rd and 10th, with times of 17:35 and 18:29, respectively. Liz was over a minute faster than she was last year! Wes finished 16th with a time of 16:40. Jenny finished 4th, with a time of 18:05. Finally, Troy finished 20th, with a time of 17:05.So what is next for the GRP rowers? As winter approaches, the lake will freeze and the athletes will transition to land training for the majority of the winter, utilizing the ergs and weight room in the COC gym and snow-covered trails around the center, doing as much volume and strength training as they can.The next races will be held in March and are the National Selection Regattas for the US National team qualification. Preparation for those races begins now!Saturday resultsSunday results <img src="/assets/bulkUpload/2016Fall-ECSpeedOrders-Liz-P1010126.JPG" alt="2016Fall-ECSpeedOrders-Liz-P1010126" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1754/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>2017 Camp Rates and Dates published</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1752/</link>
			<description>Running and sculling campers:  our 2017 schedule is now live! Check it out:2017 Running Camps2017 Sculling Camps</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2016 17:17:53 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[Running and sculling campers:  our 2017 schedule is now live! Check it out:2017 Running Camps2017 Sculling Camps <img src="/assets/bulkUpload/AT7A0284.jpg" alt="AT7A0284" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1752/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Craftsbury at HOCR</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1751/</link>
			<description>October 22nd and 23rd was Head of the Charles weekend! While it was classic HOCR weather: cold, windy, and raining, the results of the racing was, overall, more enlightening. Craftsbury had a solid showing over the weekend, with current and former GRP members impressively racing up the course.Hugh McAdam had one of the more stand out races, winning the lightweight Men’s championship single with a time of 18:33, a 39 second margin ahead of 2nd place. In a steep field for the Women’s championship single, and her first HOCR ever, Liz Vogt placed 14th, with a time of 20:42. Jenny Mcilvane finished 7th in the lightweight Women’s championship single, with a time of 21:32.Former GRP members Maggie Fellows, Andrew Reed, Willy Cowles, Erik Frid, Maddie Lips, Jamie Chapman, Ben Dann, and the three Graves brothers all had impressive results that weekend as well. Erik Frid, racing for PennAC, was a part of the winning boat in the Men’s championship double, with a time of 16:58. Peter and Tom Graves finished 5th in the Men’s Championship double, with a time of 17:21, after hooking a buoy around the last turn. Willy Cowles, in a men’s double from Potomac, finished 13th, with a time of 17:55. Maggie Fellows finished 9th in the Women’s championship single, with a time of 20:33. John Graves and Ben Dann both had stellar races in the Men’s championship single event. John finished 2nd, with a time of 18:31, and Ben finished 8th, with a time 19:04. Ben also raced in the Men’s Director’s Challenge quad, finishing 3rd. Andrew Reed raced in the Men’s Championship four, finishing 2nd, behind the Princeton Training Center. Maddie Lips and Jamie Chapman raced in their alumni eights, finishing 6th and 8th, respectively. Maddie also raced in the Women’s Director’s Challenge quad, winning by over a minute and a half margin!Former SBTC coach, Greg Myhr, and Troy Howell both raced the Men’s single master single and finished 6th and 7th, respectively. Their times were 19:42 and 19:49. Judy Geer, and her sister Carlie, raced in the Women’s senior master eight event, finishing 17th. Dick Dreissigacker, along with his brother Peter and former SBTC and GRP coach, Larry Gluckman, raced in the Men’s senior master eight event, finishing 31st.All around, the 52nd annual Head of the Charles regatta was another great weekend of racing for everyone.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 14:34:27 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[October 22nd and 23rd was Head of the Charles weekend! While it was classic HOCR weather: cold, windy, and raining, the results of the racing was, overall, more enlightening. Craftsbury had a solid showing over the weekend, with current and former GRP members impressively racing up the course.Hugh McAdam had one of the more stand out races, winning the lightweight Men’s championship single with a time of 18:33, a 39 second margin ahead of 2nd place. In a steep field for the Women’s championship single, and her first HOCR ever, Liz Vogt placed 14th, with a time of 20:42. Jenny Mcilvane finished 7th in the lightweight Women’s championship single, with a time of 21:32.Former GRP members Maggie Fellows, Andrew Reed, Willy Cowles, Erik Frid, Maddie Lips, Jamie Chapman, Ben Dann, and the three Graves brothers all had impressive results that weekend as well. Erik Frid, racing for PennAC, was a part of the winning boat in the Men’s championship double, with a time of 16:58. Peter and Tom Graves finished 5th in the Men’s Championship double, with a time of 17:21, after hooking a buoy around the last turn. Willy Cowles, in a men’s double from Potomac, finished 13th, with a time of 17:55. Maggie Fellows finished 9th in the Women’s championship single, with a time of 20:33. John Graves and Ben Dann both had stellar races in the Men’s championship single event. John finished 2nd, with a time of 18:31, and Ben finished 8th, with a time 19:04. Ben also raced in the Men’s Director’s Challenge quad, finishing 3rd. Andrew Reed raced in the Men’s Championship four, finishing 2nd, behind the Princeton Training Center. Maddie Lips and Jamie Chapman raced in their alumni eights, finishing 6th and 8th, respectively. Maddie also raced in the Women’s Director’s Challenge quad, winning by over a minute and a half margin!Former SBTC coach, Greg Myhr, and Troy Howell both raced the Men’s single master single and finished 6th and 7th, respectively. Their times were 19:42 and 19:49. Judy Geer, and her sister Carlie, raced in the Women’s senior master eight event, finishing 17th. Dick Dreissigacker, along with his brother Peter and former SBTC and GRP coach, Larry Gluckman, raced in the Men’s senior master eight event, finishing 31st.All around, the 52nd annual Head of the Charles regatta was another great weekend of racing for everyone. <img src="/assets/bulkUpload/HOCR16-IMG-1917.jpg" alt="HOCR16 IMG 1917" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1751/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>&#039;16 Canadian Henley Results</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1720/</link>
			<description>Last week 9 GRP and SBTC rowers headed west to St. Catherine&#039;s Ontario for the Royal Canadian Henley Regatta - sort of the unofficial summer championships for North America. They had a full schedule ahead of them as:
Karli Kirk-GoerkeMadison LipsAndrew MacMillenJennifer McIlvaneBrooke MooneyAndrew ReedSarah Kate RogersElizabeth VogtParker Washburn
were entered a total of 34 across 26 events! Whew! But it was all worth it when the medal count came in:
SR W1x - 2nd: Maddie Lips, by under 0.5sSR W1x - 4th: Liz VogtU23 LW1x - 5th: Jenny McIlvaneSR W2- - Win: Lips/VogtSR W2x - Win: Lips/VogtM1x Dash - 5th: Andrew ReedW1x Dash - 3rd: VogtChamp W2- - Win: Lips/VogtChamp M2- - Win: Reed/Parker WashburnChamp W1x - 4th: LipsChamp W1x - 6th: Lips
Plus the GRP/SBTC combo put together a composite mixed 8+ that won the dash for cash! In addition to the results above, Brooke Mooney, Karli Kirk, Sarah Kate Rogers, and Jenny Mcilvane had an impressive, photo-finish semi-final and just narrowly missed out of the final in the Senior women’s quad, having never rowed together before racing, 
Much of the rowers are headed out for a much needed break, while Ben Davison, Sam O’Brien, and Nick Montalvo prep for World Champs in Rotterdam, the Netherlands starting August 21.
Congrats to all the athletes, and good luck to the SBTC rowers who&#039;ll be returning to their college programs soon. You can find full Henley results at the website.
 </description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 17:45:36 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[Last week 9 GRP and SBTC rowers headed west to St. Catherine&#039;s Ontario for the Royal Canadian Henley Regatta - sort of the unofficial summer championships for North America. They had a full schedule ahead of them as:
Karli Kirk-GoerkeMadison LipsAndrew MacMillenJennifer McIlvaneBrooke MooneyAndrew ReedSarah Kate RogersElizabeth VogtParker Washburn
were entered a total of 34 across 26 events! Whew! But it was all worth it when the medal count came in:
SR W1x - 2nd: Maddie Lips, by under 0.5sSR W1x - 4th: Liz VogtU23 LW1x - 5th: Jenny McIlvaneSR W2- - Win: Lips/VogtSR W2x - Win: Lips/VogtM1x Dash - 5th: Andrew ReedW1x Dash - 3rd: VogtChamp W2- - Win: Lips/VogtChamp M2- - Win: Reed/Parker WashburnChamp W1x - 4th: LipsChamp W1x - 6th: Lips
Plus the GRP/SBTC combo put together a composite mixed 8+ that won the dash for cash! In addition to the results above, Brooke Mooney, Karli Kirk, Sarah Kate Rogers, and Jenny Mcilvane had an impressive, photo-finish semi-final and just narrowly missed out of the final in the Senior women’s quad, having never rowed together before racing, 
Much of the rowers are headed out for a much needed break, while Ben Davison, Sam O’Brien, and Nick Montalvo prep for World Champs in Rotterdam, the Netherlands starting August 21.
Congrats to all the athletes, and good luck to the SBTC rowers who&#039;ll be returning to their college programs soon. You can find full Henley results at the website.
  <img src="/assets/bulkUpload/13909180-2513256791033-5252134124517837568-o.jpg" alt="13909180 2513256791033 5252134124517837568 o" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1720/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>U23/Senior World&#039;s Trials</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1719/</link>
			<description>The SBTC and Hugh Mcadam recently participated in the U23 and Senior World’s trials at Mercer Lake, West Windsor, NJ. Nick Montalvo and Sam O’Brien’s hard work of making weight and still finding speed, paid off in the U23 lightweight men’s double event, as they won with a time of 6:35, an 11 second cushion over 2nd place. Ben Davison reclaimed his 2015 berth as the U23 men’s single sculler. His time was 7:15. Andrew MacMillen also competed in the U23 men’s single event and came 2nd, with a time of 7:41. Brooke Mooney and Karli Kirk competed in both the U23 women’s single and double events. In the single, they just narrowly missed out of the final, coming 3rd in their separate semi-finals. In the double, they missed out of the semi-final in the repechage. Sarah Kate Rogers also raced in the U23 women’s single event. She was in the same semi-final as Brooke, finishing just three seconds behind her. Jenny McIlvane raced in the U23 lightweight women’s single.  After close racing in the final, she finished 4th with a time of 8:06. Hugh Mcadam had an exciting week, racing in the senior lightweight men’s single. All week, racing was extremely tight. He finished 4th in his final with a time of 7:01, only six seconds behind 1st place. The week was successful for some and maybe slightly disappointing for others, but overall, the team came home with new goals and are back putting in the final preparations before leaving for Canadian Henley on Sunday.

Photo by Row2k. Ben Davison, racing the evening time trial </description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 15:50:34 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[The SBTC and Hugh Mcadam recently participated in the U23 and Senior World’s trials at Mercer Lake, West Windsor, NJ. Nick Montalvo and Sam O’Brien’s hard work of making weight and still finding speed, paid off in the U23 lightweight men’s double event, as they won with a time of 6:35, an 11 second cushion over 2nd place. Ben Davison reclaimed his 2015 berth as the U23 men’s single sculler. His time was 7:15. Andrew MacMillen also competed in the U23 men’s single event and came 2nd, with a time of 7:41. Brooke Mooney and Karli Kirk competed in both the U23 women’s single and double events. In the single, they just narrowly missed out of the final, coming 3rd in their separate semi-finals. In the double, they missed out of the semi-final in the repechage. Sarah Kate Rogers also raced in the U23 women’s single event. She was in the same semi-final as Brooke, finishing just three seconds behind her. Jenny McIlvane raced in the U23 lightweight women’s single.  After close racing in the final, she finished 4th with a time of 8:06. Hugh Mcadam had an exciting week, racing in the senior lightweight men’s single. All week, racing was extremely tight. He finished 4th in his final with a time of 7:01, only six seconds behind 1st place. The week was successful for some and maybe slightly disappointing for others, but overall, the team came home with new goals and are back putting in the final preparations before leaving for Canadian Henley on Sunday.

Photo by Row2k. Ben Davison, racing the evening time trial  <img src="/assets/bulkUpload/320-WchTrls-2018.jpg" alt="320 WchTrls 2018" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1719/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>GRP at USRA Club Nats</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1709/</link>
			<description>Last week, July 11-17, was the USRowing Club Nationals in Cincinnati, OH. This year, it included all of the elite events that, in previous years, have been held as a separate regatta.
GRP scullers John Graves, Parker Washburn, Maddie Lips, and Liz Vogt drove down for the week to compete in elite men’s single, women’s double, and women’s single. Parker attended as the “team manager,” a pivotal job for the week, as Troy Howell and Greg Myhr traveled with the SBTC and Hugh to the U23/Senior World’s trials (which are in progress at the moment).
It was a successful week for all of the GRP members. John, one of Cincinnati’s own hometown heroes, won the elite single and 500m dash, racing against the 2016 Indian olympic, single sculler and the 2012 Mexican olympic, single sculler. Liz and Maddie continued their “dynamic duo” streak. They won the women’s double event and came 1st and 2nd, respectively, in both the women’s single event and 500m dash. The team is back in Craftsbury for the next couple of weeks, before they travel again to Canadian Henley in St. Catharines, Ontario.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2016 10:29:12 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[Last week, July 11-17, was the USRowing Club Nationals in Cincinnati, OH. This year, it included all of the elite events that, in previous years, have been held as a separate regatta.
GRP scullers John Graves, Parker Washburn, Maddie Lips, and Liz Vogt drove down for the week to compete in elite men’s single, women’s double, and women’s single. Parker attended as the “team manager,” a pivotal job for the week, as Troy Howell and Greg Myhr traveled with the SBTC and Hugh to the U23/Senior World’s trials (which are in progress at the moment).
It was a successful week for all of the GRP members. John, one of Cincinnati’s own hometown heroes, won the elite single and 500m dash, racing against the 2016 Indian olympic, single sculler and the 2012 Mexican olympic, single sculler. Liz and Maddie continued their “dynamic duo” streak. They won the women’s double event and came 1st and 2nd, respectively, in both the women’s single event and 500m dash. The team is back in Craftsbury for the next couple of weeks, before they travel again to Canadian Henley in St. Catharines, Ontario. <img src="/assets/bulkUpload/2017-07-17-W2xGRP-Lips-Vogt.jpg" alt="2017 07 17 W2xGRP Lips Vogt" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1709/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Independence Day Regatta Results</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1708/</link>
			<description>Over the fourth of July weekend, the SBTC and some of the GRP traveled to Philadelphia, PA for the Independence Day Regatta. Almost everyone came home with a new, Schuylkill Navy watch, the prize for winning their respective events.
For the SBTC, Sam O’Brien and Nick Montalvo won the intermediate lightweight men’s double sculls. They also came 2nd and 3rd, respectively, in the senior lightweight men’s single and 1st and 3rd, respectively, in the intermediate men’s single. Jenny Mcilvane won the intermediate women’s single and came 3rd in the senior lightweight women’s single. Brooke Mooney and Karli Kirk came 4th in the women’s intermediate double sculls. For the GRP, Maddie Lips and Liz Vogt won the senior women’s double sculls and came 1st and 2nd, respectively, in the senior women’s single. Hugh McAdam won the senior men’s single and lightweight men’s single.
This weekend marked the beginning of summer racing and was overall a successful trip for the SBTC and GRP athletes. Most of these athletes are now back home preparing for U23/Senior World’s trials, where the SBTC and Hugh McAdam will be racing for spots on the US team in various boat classes. This event begins July 18th in Mercer, NJ.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2016 10:24:47 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[Over the fourth of July weekend, the SBTC and some of the GRP traveled to Philadelphia, PA for the Independence Day Regatta. Almost everyone came home with a new, Schuylkill Navy watch, the prize for winning their respective events.
For the SBTC, Sam O’Brien and Nick Montalvo won the intermediate lightweight men’s double sculls. They also came 2nd and 3rd, respectively, in the senior lightweight men’s single and 1st and 3rd, respectively, in the intermediate men’s single. Jenny Mcilvane won the intermediate women’s single and came 3rd in the senior lightweight women’s single. Brooke Mooney and Karli Kirk came 4th in the women’s intermediate double sculls. For the GRP, Maddie Lips and Liz Vogt won the senior women’s double sculls and came 1st and 2nd, respectively, in the senior women’s single. Hugh McAdam won the senior men’s single and lightweight men’s single.
This weekend marked the beginning of summer racing and was overall a successful trip for the SBTC and GRP athletes. Most of these athletes are now back home preparing for U23/Senior World’s trials, where the SBTC and Hugh McAdam will be racing for spots on the US team in various boat classes. This event begins July 18th in Mercer, NJ. <img src="/assets/bulkUpload/IMG-20160703-112126.jpg" alt="IMG 20160703 112126" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1708/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>GRP at Olympic Trials II</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1703/</link>
			<description>Last weekend, five of the GRP athletes: Parker and Andrew, Peter and John, and Ben Dann (rowing with a partner from the Princeton training center) competed in Olympic Trials II. They were racing for the last two spots on the Olympic team in the Men’s pair. Racing was fierce, and all of the GRP boats were edged out in the semifinal, not advancing to the final. Parker and Andrew, and Peter and John were in the same semifinal, coming 3rd and 4th, respectively. Ben and his partner came 3rd in the other semifinal.</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2016 16:12:52 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[Last weekend, five of the GRP athletes: Parker and Andrew, Peter and John, and Ben Dann (rowing with a partner from the Princeton training center) competed in Olympic Trials II. They were racing for the last two spots on the Olympic team in the Men’s pair. Racing was fierce, and all of the GRP boats were edged out in the semifinal, not advancing to the final. Parker and Andrew, and Peter and John were in the same semifinal, coming 3rd and 4th, respectively. Ben and his partner came 3rd in the other semifinal. <img src="/assets/bulkUpload/320-WchTrls-2017.jpg" alt="320 WchTrls 2017" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1703/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Schedule Change:  2016 Hosmer Community Rowing</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1676/</link>
			<description>UPDATE:  Starting the week of July 3-9, &quot;first-timer&quot;/beginner night will switch from Mondays to Wednesdays. A reminder however:  we will NOT however offer any CommRow on Monday, July 4 - enjoy the holiday!
Craftsbury is excited to launch Hosmer Community Rowing for 2016!
Hosmer Community Rowing, or CommRow, is an opportunity for members of the community to gain some sculling experience alongside participants of the Craftsbury Sculling Camps. Instruction and organization is lead by the rowing members of the Craftsbury Green Racing Project.
Returning members are invited to grab their oars and hit the water starting May 16, while new members can have their baptismal &quot;flip test&quot; in the waters of Big Hosmer on May 31 after the holiday. After that initial week, scullers with less than a year experience should show up on Mondays when the GRP will be locked and loaded with extra enthusiasm (and numbers) to get everyone up to speed. Meanwhile, people with more experience can feel free to come during any of the three offerings on Mondays, Tuesdays, and Wednesdays.
Remember to stop in at the office to: verify your COC membership, sign a waiver for CommRow, and decide whether you would like to row once a week for $50/season or as many times as you can for $150/season.
New and not sure? Try three sessions on us to test the waters! This is a great opportunity to gain access to a majestic and rewarding sport.
There will be no CommRow on May 30 - enjoy the Holiday!
For more details on CommRow scheduling and membership, please head over our member programming section.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2016 11:37:19 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[UPDATE:  Starting the week of July 3-9, &quot;first-timer&quot;/beginner night will switch from Mondays to Wednesdays. A reminder however:  we will NOT however offer any CommRow on Monday, July 4 - enjoy the holiday!
Craftsbury is excited to launch Hosmer Community Rowing for 2016!
Hosmer Community Rowing, or CommRow, is an opportunity for members of the community to gain some sculling experience alongside participants of the Craftsbury Sculling Camps. Instruction and organization is lead by the rowing members of the Craftsbury Green Racing Project.
Returning members are invited to grab their oars and hit the water starting May 16, while new members can have their baptismal &quot;flip test&quot; in the waters of Big Hosmer on May 31 after the holiday. After that initial week, scullers with less than a year experience should show up on Mondays when the GRP will be locked and loaded with extra enthusiasm (and numbers) to get everyone up to speed. Meanwhile, people with more experience can feel free to come during any of the three offerings on Mondays, Tuesdays, and Wednesdays.
Remember to stop in at the office to: verify your COC membership, sign a waiver for CommRow, and decide whether you would like to row once a week for $50/season or as many times as you can for $150/season.
New and not sure? Try three sessions on us to test the waters! This is a great opportunity to gain access to a majestic and rewarding sport.
There will be no CommRow on May 30 - enjoy the Holiday!
For more details on CommRow scheduling and membership, please head over our member programming section. <img src="/assets/bulkUpload/20150611-SM-GRP-148.jpg" alt="20150611 SM GRP 148" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1676/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Heated Competition for GRP men at Last Chance Regatta and World Cup II</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1697/</link>
			<description>At the end of April, the Men’s quad of Ben Davison, Ben Dann, John Graves, and Peter Graves and the Men’s double, with Steve Whelpley and Willy Cowles, qualified to compete in the Final Olympic Qualification Regatta, or as it&#039;s more commonly called:  the “Regatta of Death.” This was the last opportunity for the United States to qualify these boat categories for the 2016 Olympics in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. This regatta is considered one of the most competitive events for elite rowing, with many of the winners usually winning Olympic medals later in the summer. Only the top two boats from these events would qualify.
Although both boats showed impressive speeds through the regatta, neither were able to snag one of the top two spots. The Men’s quad finished 4th, with a time of 5:45.7, very close behind Russia, Canada, and New Zealand. In the quad’s repechage, there was 0.6 seconds separating 1st from 4th--showing the level of extreme competition between these crews and quality of the athletes in this race. All of these crews are very capable of being strong competitors at the Olympic games. Unfortunately, two only get to go: Russia and Canada.
The Men’s double came 6th, with a time of 6:28.67, behind Norway, Serbia, Czech Republic, Poland, and Argentina. The men’s double is one of the most of competitive events in Olympic rowing. Even though Steve and Willy finished 6th, they threw down some of their fastest times and performances through the regatta - highly commendable.
Both crews competed in the second World Cup the week after the Last Qualification Regatta. Most crews that have already qualified for the summer Olympics competed in this event. The Quad had a fast heat, competed in the repechage, but narrowly missed out on the final. They were 0.14 seconds out of advancing to the final. After the previous weekend of intense racing, it was an impressive feat to even compete, as most crews that raced the weekend before didn’t race in the World Cup. It was a similar story for the Men’s double, where they just missed out on the final with a 4th place finish in the repechage. LM1x Hugh McAdam also contested World Cup II, competing in the Men’s lightweight single. He finished 3rd in the B final, with a time of 7:09.</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2016 18:25:32 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[At the end of April, the Men’s quad of Ben Davison, Ben Dann, John Graves, and Peter Graves and the Men’s double, with Steve Whelpley and Willy Cowles, qualified to compete in the Final Olympic Qualification Regatta, or as it&#039;s more commonly called:  the “Regatta of Death.” This was the last opportunity for the United States to qualify these boat categories for the 2016 Olympics in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. This regatta is considered one of the most competitive events for elite rowing, with many of the winners usually winning Olympic medals later in the summer. Only the top two boats from these events would qualify.
Although both boats showed impressive speeds through the regatta, neither were able to snag one of the top two spots. The Men’s quad finished 4th, with a time of 5:45.7, very close behind Russia, Canada, and New Zealand. In the quad’s repechage, there was 0.6 seconds separating 1st from 4th--showing the level of extreme competition between these crews and quality of the athletes in this race. All of these crews are very capable of being strong competitors at the Olympic games. Unfortunately, two only get to go: Russia and Canada.
The Men’s double came 6th, with a time of 6:28.67, behind Norway, Serbia, Czech Republic, Poland, and Argentina. The men’s double is one of the most of competitive events in Olympic rowing. Even though Steve and Willy finished 6th, they threw down some of their fastest times and performances through the regatta - highly commendable.
Both crews competed in the second World Cup the week after the Last Qualification Regatta. Most crews that have already qualified for the summer Olympics competed in this event. The Quad had a fast heat, competed in the repechage, but narrowly missed out on the final. They were 0.14 seconds out of advancing to the final. After the previous weekend of intense racing, it was an impressive feat to even compete, as most crews that raced the weekend before didn’t race in the World Cup. It was a similar story for the Men’s double, where they just missed out on the final with a 4th place finish in the repechage. LM1x Hugh McAdam also contested World Cup II, competing in the Men’s lightweight single. He finished 3rd in the B final, with a time of 7:09. <img src="/assets/Uploads/13055393-1274072445940416-5930149147514993876-n.jpg" alt="13055393 1274072445940416 5930149147514993876 n" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1697/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Buy your summer Open Gym Pass</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1480/</link>
			<description>Even with all the natural options for exercise around Craftsbury, some movements are best accomplished in the gym, with the right gear. Sign up to workout, spring to fall with our OpenGym Pass at the Craftsbury Outdoor Center. After you have your annual membership, passes are $50/person per season:
Winter- November 1 to April 30Summer- May 1 to October 31
Must be 14 or older. So, how do you get in on the action?
Step 1 - Make sure your Craftsbury membership is current.
Step 2 - Go to Skireg and sign up for a Gym Pass. This is a requirement to use the gym, even if you get a complimentary annual membership. Gym passes are NOT included in annual membership benefits.
Step 3 - Check the event calendar to get current Open Gym slots (Gym times are subject to change, pending COC programming schedules)
Step 4 - Get jacked! (Following the gym regulations posted for everyone&#039;s safety and enjoyment of course).
No matter your goals, we hope that the new space will be helpful to you as you strive to reach them. Questions? Reach us at fitness@craftsbury.com</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2015 17:10:35 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[Even with all the natural options for exercise around Craftsbury, some movements are best accomplished in the gym, with the right gear. Sign up to workout, spring to fall with our OpenGym Pass at the Craftsbury Outdoor Center. After you have your annual membership, passes are $50/person per season:
Winter- November 1 to April 30Summer- May 1 to October 31
Must be 14 or older. So, how do you get in on the action?
Step 1 - Make sure your Craftsbury membership is current.
Step 2 - Go to Skireg and sign up for a Gym Pass. This is a requirement to use the gym, even if you get a complimentary annual membership. Gym passes are NOT included in annual membership benefits.
Step 3 - Check the event calendar to get current Open Gym slots (Gym times are subject to change, pending COC programming schedules)
Step 4 - Get jacked! (Following the gym regulations posted for everyone&#039;s safety and enjoyment of course).
No matter your goals, we hope that the new space will be helpful to you as you strive to reach them. Questions? Reach us at fitness@craftsbury.com <img src="/assets/Uploads/2015GymPassAnn-dryland.jpg" alt="2015GymPassAnn dryland" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1480/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>GRP Double Wins Olympic Trials</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1682/</link>
			<description>The Green Racing Project men’s double of William Cowles (Farmington, Connecticut) and Steve Whelpley (Mequon, Wisconsin) finished the long week for Craftsbury winning their event at Olympic Trials in Sarasota, Florida. See results here.
The two won Sunday’s final handily, posting a time of 6:38.83 over crews from Vesper, Los Angeles and Community Rowing. This victory provides Cowles and Whelpley the opportunity to qualify for the Rio de Janeiro Olympics in Lucerne, Switzerland, where they will have to place top two among crews from around the world. The Olympics take place later this summer.
Two other Craftsbury entries competed in Sunday’s finals. The women’s double of Liz Vogt (Trout Lake, Washington) and Jamie Chapman (Traverse City, Michigan) made the final after winning their repechage on Saturday. They ultimately finished fourth in the final, behind crews from New York Athletic Club/Oklahoma City Training Center, Vesper and Riverside.
After training in California for the Fall and Winter, Tom Graves, racing as Craftsbury, lost a close men’s single final. Coming from behind on the field, Graves sprinted in an attempt to catch the leader and eventual winner Ken Jurkowski. Graves came just over one second short from winning the event.
The other Craftsbury scullers raced hard through the week in the highly subscribed men’s and women’s singles. Unfortunately they came up short of Sunday’s finals. Hugh McAdam (Hollis, New Hampshire), Erik Frid (Madbury, New Hampshire) and Maddie Lips (Parker, Colorado) all placed third in their respective semifinals, one place out of the finals. Maggie Fellows (Warwick, Massachusetts) raced through Friday’s repechages, but was unable to make the semifinal.
As an additional note, former GRP rower Josh Konieczny won the men’s lightweight double, racing at Cambridge Boat Club. With this trials win, Konieczny and his doubles partner Andrew Campbell earn a ticket to the Olympics.
Moving forward, the efforts of the GRP are directed towards the men’s quad and double competing at the Olympic Qualification Regatta in Lucerne. The men&#039;s quad of Ben Davison (Durham, England), Ben Dann (Pound Ridge, New York), John Graves (Cincinnati, Ohio) and Peter Graves (Cincinnati, Ohio) earned their opportunity to travel to Switzerland earlier in the week, winning the quad final on Tuesday.
Further on the horizon is the potential Olympic Trials II where the GRP pair of Parker Washburn (Andover, Massachusetts) and Andrew Reed (Wayland, Massachusetts) might get the chance to race the men’s pair for a spot in Olympics.
 </description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2016 10:37:55 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[The Green Racing Project men’s double of William Cowles (Farmington, Connecticut) and Steve Whelpley (Mequon, Wisconsin) finished the long week for Craftsbury winning their event at Olympic Trials in Sarasota, Florida. See results here.
The two won Sunday’s final handily, posting a time of 6:38.83 over crews from Vesper, Los Angeles and Community Rowing. This victory provides Cowles and Whelpley the opportunity to qualify for the Rio de Janeiro Olympics in Lucerne, Switzerland, where they will have to place top two among crews from around the world. The Olympics take place later this summer.
Two other Craftsbury entries competed in Sunday’s finals. The women’s double of Liz Vogt (Trout Lake, Washington) and Jamie Chapman (Traverse City, Michigan) made the final after winning their repechage on Saturday. They ultimately finished fourth in the final, behind crews from New York Athletic Club/Oklahoma City Training Center, Vesper and Riverside.
After training in California for the Fall and Winter, Tom Graves, racing as Craftsbury, lost a close men’s single final. Coming from behind on the field, Graves sprinted in an attempt to catch the leader and eventual winner Ken Jurkowski. Graves came just over one second short from winning the event.
The other Craftsbury scullers raced hard through the week in the highly subscribed men’s and women’s singles. Unfortunately they came up short of Sunday’s finals. Hugh McAdam (Hollis, New Hampshire), Erik Frid (Madbury, New Hampshire) and Maddie Lips (Parker, Colorado) all placed third in their respective semifinals, one place out of the finals. Maggie Fellows (Warwick, Massachusetts) raced through Friday’s repechages, but was unable to make the semifinal.
As an additional note, former GRP rower Josh Konieczny won the men’s lightweight double, racing at Cambridge Boat Club. With this trials win, Konieczny and his doubles partner Andrew Campbell earn a ticket to the Olympics.
Moving forward, the efforts of the GRP are directed towards the men’s quad and double competing at the Olympic Qualification Regatta in Lucerne. The men&#039;s quad of Ben Davison (Durham, England), Ben Dann (Pound Ridge, New York), John Graves (Cincinnati, Ohio) and Peter Graves (Cincinnati, Ohio) earned their opportunity to travel to Switzerland earlier in the week, winning the quad final on Tuesday.
Further on the horizon is the potential Olympic Trials II where the GRP pair of Parker Washburn (Andover, Massachusetts) and Andrew Reed (Wayland, Massachusetts) might get the chance to race the men’s pair for a spot in Olympics.
  <img src="/assets/Uploads/26024004603-8f66385f06-o.jpg" alt="26024004603 8f66385f06 o" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1682/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Craftsbury Wins the Quad at Olympic Trials</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1680/</link>
			<description>The Green Racing Project kicked of the week of Olympic Trials at Nathan Benderson Park in Sarasota, Florida with a win in the final of the men’s quad. Rowing the course in a time of 6:05.09, the crew of Ben Davison (Durham, England), Ben Dann (Pound Ridge, New York), John Graves (Cincinnati, Ohio), and Peter Graves (Cincinnati, Ohio) beat out quads from California Rowing Club and Community Rowing in Boston.
The victory gives the Craftsbury quad the opportunity to represent the United States at the Final Olympic Qualification Regatta in Lucerne, Switzerland, where they will have to place top two to make the Olympic games in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil later this summer.
The first trials victory for Craftsbury in the men’s quad since 2014, this year’s crew took a 3 second lead over second-place California by the 500-meter mark. This lead was expanded to less than 6 seconds by 1500 meters. Craftsbury finished the race nearly 5 seconds up on California and almost 28 seconds up on third-place Community rowing. Conditions were choppy at the start with a cross-headwind down the entire course.
The GRP’s week is just beginning at the Olympic Trials. Eight other athletes from Craftbury will compete in four events for an opportunity to represent the United States at the Olympics or the Final Qualification Regatta. The GRP is entered in the men’s and women’s single and the men’s and women’s double. The women&#039;s single and double are already qualified for the Olympics and winners of these events will punch a direct ticket to the 2016 Olympic Games. Racing begins Thursday, with finals on Sunday.
The crews from Craftsbury slated to compete are the men’s singles of Hugh McAdam (Hollis, New Hampshire) and Erik Frid (Madbury, New Hampshire); the women’s singles of Maddie Lips (Parker, Colorado) and Maggie Fellows (Warwick, Massachusetts); the men’s double of Steve Whelpley (Mequon, Wisconsin) and William Cowles (Farmington, Connecticut); and the women’s double of Elizabeth Vogt (Trout Lake, Washington) and Jamie Chapman (Traverse City, Michigan).
Keep track of results throughout the week on USRowing.org.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2016 12:07:38 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[The Green Racing Project kicked of the week of Olympic Trials at Nathan Benderson Park in Sarasota, Florida with a win in the final of the men’s quad. Rowing the course in a time of 6:05.09, the crew of Ben Davison (Durham, England), Ben Dann (Pound Ridge, New York), John Graves (Cincinnati, Ohio), and Peter Graves (Cincinnati, Ohio) beat out quads from California Rowing Club and Community Rowing in Boston.
The victory gives the Craftsbury quad the opportunity to represent the United States at the Final Olympic Qualification Regatta in Lucerne, Switzerland, where they will have to place top two to make the Olympic games in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil later this summer.
The first trials victory for Craftsbury in the men’s quad since 2014, this year’s crew took a 3 second lead over second-place California by the 500-meter mark. This lead was expanded to less than 6 seconds by 1500 meters. Craftsbury finished the race nearly 5 seconds up on California and almost 28 seconds up on third-place Community rowing. Conditions were choppy at the start with a cross-headwind down the entire course.
The GRP’s week is just beginning at the Olympic Trials. Eight other athletes from Craftbury will compete in four events for an opportunity to represent the United States at the Olympics or the Final Qualification Regatta. The GRP is entered in the men’s and women’s single and the men’s and women’s double. The women&#039;s single and double are already qualified for the Olympics and winners of these events will punch a direct ticket to the 2016 Olympic Games. Racing begins Thursday, with finals on Sunday.
The crews from Craftsbury slated to compete are the men’s singles of Hugh McAdam (Hollis, New Hampshire) and Erik Frid (Madbury, New Hampshire); the women’s singles of Maddie Lips (Parker, Colorado) and Maggie Fellows (Warwick, Massachusetts); the men’s double of Steve Whelpley (Mequon, Wisconsin) and William Cowles (Farmington, Connecticut); and the women’s double of Elizabeth Vogt (Trout Lake, Washington) and Jamie Chapman (Traverse City, Michigan).
Keep track of results throughout the week on USRowing.org. <img src="/assets/bulkUpload/26250094940-c75bfa063b-o.jpg" alt="26250094940 c75bfa063b o" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1680/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Olympic Rowing Trials begin Sunday</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1679/</link>
			<description>The Green Racing Project’s week at Olympic Trials I begins Sunday with the men’s quad of Ben Davison (Durham, England), Ben Dann (Pound Ridge, New York), John Graves (Cincinnati, Ohio), and Peter Graves (Cincinnati, Ohio).
The time trial race for lanes goes off at 5:00 p.m. on Sunday at Nathan Benderson Park in Sarasota, Florida. The Craftsbury quad will race crews from California Rowing Club and Community Rowing in Boston. The three-boat final takes place Tuesday morning at 8:00 a.m.
The winner of the quad at Olympic Trials I earns a chance to compete at the Final Olympic Qualification Regatta in Lucerne, Switzerland, where the quad representing the United States will have to place top two among a competitive field to earn a ticket to Rio de Janeiro, Brazil for the Olympics.
Olympic Trials I top off a long training period for the GRP. The team spent February through mid-April practicing on Canal 54 in Fellsmere, Florida and using the facilities at Treasure Coast Cross-Fit in Sebastian, Florida for weight training.
After the quad competes the rest of the team will round off the end of Olympic Trials I racing in the men’s and women’s single and double. These crews are the men’s singles of Hugh McAdam (Hollis, New Hampshire) and Erik Frid (Madbury, New Hampshire); the women’s singles of Maddie Lips (Parker, Colorado) and Maggie Fellows (Warwick, Massachusetts); the men’s double of Steve Whelpley (Mequon, Wisconsin) and William Cowles (Farmington, Connecticut); and the women’s double of Elizabeth Vogt (Trout Lake, Washington) and Jamie Chapman (Traverse City, Michigan). Finals for these events are on Sunday, April 24.
Keep track of results throughout the week on USRowing.org.</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 09:56:23 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[The Green Racing Project’s week at Olympic Trials I begins Sunday with the men’s quad of Ben Davison (Durham, England), Ben Dann (Pound Ridge, New York), John Graves (Cincinnati, Ohio), and Peter Graves (Cincinnati, Ohio).
The time trial race for lanes goes off at 5:00 p.m. on Sunday at Nathan Benderson Park in Sarasota, Florida. The Craftsbury quad will race crews from California Rowing Club and Community Rowing in Boston. The three-boat final takes place Tuesday morning at 8:00 a.m.
The winner of the quad at Olympic Trials I earns a chance to compete at the Final Olympic Qualification Regatta in Lucerne, Switzerland, where the quad representing the United States will have to place top two among a competitive field to earn a ticket to Rio de Janeiro, Brazil for the Olympics.
Olympic Trials I top off a long training period for the GRP. The team spent February through mid-April practicing on Canal 54 in Fellsmere, Florida and using the facilities at Treasure Coast Cross-Fit in Sebastian, Florida for weight training.
After the quad competes the rest of the team will round off the end of Olympic Trials I racing in the men’s and women’s single and double. These crews are the men’s singles of Hugh McAdam (Hollis, New Hampshire) and Erik Frid (Madbury, New Hampshire); the women’s singles of Maddie Lips (Parker, Colorado) and Maggie Fellows (Warwick, Massachusetts); the men’s double of Steve Whelpley (Mequon, Wisconsin) and William Cowles (Farmington, Connecticut); and the women’s double of Elizabeth Vogt (Trout Lake, Washington) and Jamie Chapman (Traverse City, Michigan). Finals for these events are on Sunday, April 24.
Keep track of results throughout the week on USRowing.org. <img src="/assets/Uploads/12916132-1271987162815611-6534503741709313747-o.jpg" alt="12916132 1271987162815611 6534503741709313747 o" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1679/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Green Racing Project Rowing Coach</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1675/</link>
			<description>Craftsbury is looking for an inquisitive and innovative rowing coach to guide the athletes of its elite rowing program: the Green Racing Project. Of particular importance:
Experience working with small boats and sculling
Desire to help each athlete develop to their fullest potential
Interest in current research and best practices
Knowledge of exercise physiology as well as rowing technique
Excellent communication skills both with athletes and other coaches
The GRP Coach will be a member of the team at Craftsbury that manages Sculling Camps, Community programming, and SBTC, and will be involved with those programs as well. It is also expected that the coach will become an integral part of the Craftsbury Outdoor Center community and will support its mission and many non-rowing activities. This is a full-time year-round position.
Interested coaches should submit a resume and a brief essay to explain their coaching philosophy and why they think they&#039;d be a good fit for the job. Send materials to smallboats@craftsbury.com.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2016 18:58:46 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[Craftsbury is looking for an inquisitive and innovative rowing coach to guide the athletes of its elite rowing program: the Green Racing Project. Of particular importance:
Experience working with small boats and sculling
Desire to help each athlete develop to their fullest potential
Interest in current research and best practices
Knowledge of exercise physiology as well as rowing technique
Excellent communication skills both with athletes and other coaches
The GRP Coach will be a member of the team at Craftsbury that manages Sculling Camps, Community programming, and SBTC, and will be involved with those programs as well. It is also expected that the coach will become an integral part of the Craftsbury Outdoor Center community and will support its mission and many non-rowing activities. This is a full-time year-round position.
Interested coaches should submit a resume and a brief essay to explain their coaching philosophy and why they think they&#039;d be a good fit for the job. Send materials to smallboats@craftsbury.com. <img src="/assets/bulkUpload/GRP16CoachSearch-HM.jpg" alt="GRP16CoachSearch HM" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1675/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>2016 Sculling Interns</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1673/</link>
			<description>Congratulations to our 2016 COC Sculling Camp interns:
Mackenzie Beckman
Bala Cynwyd, PA
Jenny McIlvaine
Cape Cod, MA
Alexei Sondergeld
Canton, CT
Sydney McMahan
Tulsa, OK
Jon Hoey
Sutton, MA
Willy Anderson
Groton, MA
Liam Davidson
Shrewsbury, MA
Caitlin Beakes
Chevy Chase, MD
Juliet Costa
Huntington, NY
Sarah Osborn
Belmont, MA
Eva Nates
Narberth, PA
      
 
 
 
 
While there&#039;s still ice on the lake at present, it&#039;ll not be long before camp will be here again!</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 13:46:08 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[Congratulations to our 2016 COC Sculling Camp interns:
Mackenzie Beckman
Bala Cynwyd, PA
Jenny McIlvaine
Cape Cod, MA
Alexei Sondergeld
Canton, CT
Sydney McMahan
Tulsa, OK
Jon Hoey
Sutton, MA
Willy Anderson
Groton, MA
Liam Davidson
Shrewsbury, MA
Caitlin Beakes
Chevy Chase, MD
Juliet Costa
Huntington, NY
Sarah Osborn
Belmont, MA
Eva Nates
Narberth, PA
      
 
 
 
 
While there&#039;s still ice on the lake at present, it&#039;ll not be long before camp will be here again! <img src="/assets/bulkUpload/IMG-0141.jpg" alt="IMG 0141" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1673/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Washburn and Reed finish 8th at NSRI</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1669/</link>
			<description>The Green Racing Project men’s pair of Parker Washburn (Andover, Massachusetts) and Andrew Reed (Wayland, Massachusetts) finished racing at the National Selection Regatta I on Thursday with second place in the B Final with a time of 6:54.2.
Throughout the week, Washburn and Reed raced the down course in Chula Vista, California against former national teamers and Olympians. The GRP pair missed the A final on Wednesday by about a boat length behind Vesper’s pair. In the B Final, the two Harvard University alums from Craftsbury, held second place throughout the race, holding off an aggressive sprint from former Olympian’s and twins Ross and Grant James.
After NSR’s Washburn and Reed accepted an invitation to take part in selection at the Princeton National Team Training Center. The “Craftsbury Green” will be back in action the week of April 19th in Sarasota, Florida for Olympic Trials I competing in the men’s quad, double, single and women’s double and single.</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2016 09:58:32 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[The Green Racing Project men’s pair of Parker Washburn (Andover, Massachusetts) and Andrew Reed (Wayland, Massachusetts) finished racing at the National Selection Regatta I on Thursday with second place in the B Final with a time of 6:54.2.
Throughout the week, Washburn and Reed raced the down course in Chula Vista, California against former national teamers and Olympians. The GRP pair missed the A final on Wednesday by about a boat length behind Vesper’s pair. In the B Final, the two Harvard University alums from Craftsbury, held second place throughout the race, holding off an aggressive sprint from former Olympian’s and twins Ross and Grant James.
After NSR’s Washburn and Reed accepted an invitation to take part in selection at the Princeton National Team Training Center. The “Craftsbury Green” will be back in action the week of April 19th in Sarasota, Florida for Olympic Trials I competing in the men’s quad, double, single and women’s double and single. <img src="/assets/Uploads/25937012271-d028d1c59d-k.jpg" alt="25937012271 d028d1c59d k" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1669/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>GRP Row Kicks off Olympic Year in California</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1661/</link>
			<description>The men’s pair of Parker Washburn (Andover, Massachusetts) and Andrew Reed (Wayland, Massachusetts) kick of the Green Racing Project rowers this year with Monday’s time trials at the National Selection Regatta I in Chula Vista, California. This is the first time the pair will be going down the course since August’s Senior Trials II, where they placed third.
From Great Hosmer Pond to Canal 54 in Fellsmere, Florida to Newport Beach in California, Washburn and Reed have focused their training on this first race of the year. The winner of NSR I earns a spot at racing the men’s pair for the United States at World Cup II. If this crew places top four at World Cup II they will earn a spot on the United States Olympic Team to compete in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil later this summer.
Washburn and Reed will be racing 15 other crews. They will be competing throughout the week, with finals on Thursday. Keep track of their results on USRowing.org.</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2016 15:56:36 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[The men’s pair of Parker Washburn (Andover, Massachusetts) and Andrew Reed (Wayland, Massachusetts) kick of the Green Racing Project rowers this year with Monday’s time trials at the National Selection Regatta I in Chula Vista, California. This is the first time the pair will be going down the course since August’s Senior Trials II, where they placed third.
From Great Hosmer Pond to Canal 54 in Fellsmere, Florida to Newport Beach in California, Washburn and Reed have focused their training on this first race of the year. The winner of NSR I earns a spot at racing the men’s pair for the United States at World Cup II. If this crew places top four at World Cup II they will earn a spot on the United States Olympic Team to compete in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil later this summer.
Washburn and Reed will be racing 15 other crews. They will be competing throughout the week, with finals on Thursday. Keep track of their results on USRowing.org. <img src="/assets/Uploads/IMG-4942-1024x576.jpg" alt="IMG 4942 1024x576" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1661/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>2016 Sculling and Running Camps Posted</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1584/</link>
			<description>Ready to lock in your time at Craftsbury next summer? We&#039;re ready to help you out! Gather your crew and head over to our Running and Sculling Camp registration pages to reserve your slice of idyllic Vermont summer now!</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2015 16:57:50 -0500</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[Ready to lock in your time at Craftsbury next summer? We&#039;re ready to help you out! Gather your crew and head over to our Running and Sculling Camp registration pages to reserve your slice of idyllic Vermont summer now! <img src="/assets/bulkUpload/2015-07-15-Igor-Belakovskiy-Dock.jpg" alt="2015 07 15 Igor Belakovskiy Dock" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1584/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>GRP Rowers Wrap Up Fall at Speed Order</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1580/</link>
			<description>The Green Racing Project Rowers were down in Princeton, New Jersey this past weekend for USRowing’s East Coast Fall Speed Order.
The two-day event includes a 6000-meter test on the Concept2 ergs on Saturday, with a Sunday time trial water piece of about 4000 meters. Starting order for the Sunday piece is determined off the finishing order of the Saturday erg.
The GRP had eleven athletes competing in three events: the women’s single, the men’s single and the men’s pair.
In the women’s single Maddie Lips (Parker, Colorado) had the fastest GRP erg Saturday morning, placing sixth. Liz Vogt (Trout Lake, Washington) finished 11th in the erg and Maggie Fellows (Warwick, Massachusetts) was 13th.
Starting with corresponding bow numbers the next morning, Lips stormed the field to placing second overall on the water with a time of 17:42.8. Fellows went down the course in 18:28.5 finishing 10th and Vogt got 12th with a time of 18:38.8.
Among a large field in the men’s single, Erik Frid (Madbury, New Hampshire) had the fastest GRP erg, giving him bow number four for Sunday’s water piece. Ben Dann (Pound Ridge, New York) had the next fastest Craftsbury erg placing seventh. Ben Davison (Durham, England) was right behind Dann in eighth. Hugh McAdam (Hollis, New Hampshire) was 21st on the erg.
The Sunday water-piece for the men’s single was a Craftsbury sweep, with all four GRP rowers placing in the top four. Winning the event was the young Davison with a time of 15:40.8. Second place was Dann, posting a time of 15:50.1. Just over two seconds back was Frid in third, with a time of 15:52.3 and in fourth was McAdam, who, from the back of the pack, went 15:57.1.
The two GRP entries in the men’s pair stood out among a field of Princeton Training Center crews. One GRP pair was Parker Washburn (Andover, Massachusetts) and Andrew Reed (Wayland, Massachusetts), the second being John Graves (Cincinnati, Ohio) and Peter Graves (Cincinnati, Ohio). With the fastest overall erg piece for the GRP on Saturday, Washburn was 19th in the highly competitive men’s pair field. Behind him was Reed in 21st, Peter Graves in 23rd and John Graves in 24th. Start order for the men’s pair was based off the erg average of the two rowers in each crew. This seeded the Washburn/Reed pair 10th and the Graves pair 12th.
On the water the GRP showed that erg times aren’t everything, beating several pairs with higher erg averages. The highest finisher was the Washburn/Reed pair, who placed sixth with a time of 14:42.7. About six seconds behind them were the Graves in ninth, with a time of 14:48.9.
The Fall Speed Order marks the last racing opportunity for the GRP this Fall.
The team will stay in New Jersey for a couple of days to take advantage of the milder New Jersey weather. Soaking up the last weeks of water in Craftsbury, the team plans to transition to indoors training and skiing.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2015 22:09:00 -0500</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[The Green Racing Project Rowers were down in Princeton, New Jersey this past weekend for USRowing’s East Coast Fall Speed Order.
The two-day event includes a 6000-meter test on the Concept2 ergs on Saturday, with a Sunday time trial water piece of about 4000 meters. Starting order for the Sunday piece is determined off the finishing order of the Saturday erg.
The GRP had eleven athletes competing in three events: the women’s single, the men’s single and the men’s pair.
In the women’s single Maddie Lips (Parker, Colorado) had the fastest GRP erg Saturday morning, placing sixth. Liz Vogt (Trout Lake, Washington) finished 11th in the erg and Maggie Fellows (Warwick, Massachusetts) was 13th.
Starting with corresponding bow numbers the next morning, Lips stormed the field to placing second overall on the water with a time of 17:42.8. Fellows went down the course in 18:28.5 finishing 10th and Vogt got 12th with a time of 18:38.8.
Among a large field in the men’s single, Erik Frid (Madbury, New Hampshire) had the fastest GRP erg, giving him bow number four for Sunday’s water piece. Ben Dann (Pound Ridge, New York) had the next fastest Craftsbury erg placing seventh. Ben Davison (Durham, England) was right behind Dann in eighth. Hugh McAdam (Hollis, New Hampshire) was 21st on the erg.
The Sunday water-piece for the men’s single was a Craftsbury sweep, with all four GRP rowers placing in the top four. Winning the event was the young Davison with a time of 15:40.8. Second place was Dann, posting a time of 15:50.1. Just over two seconds back was Frid in third, with a time of 15:52.3 and in fourth was McAdam, who, from the back of the pack, went 15:57.1.
The two GRP entries in the men’s pair stood out among a field of Princeton Training Center crews. One GRP pair was Parker Washburn (Andover, Massachusetts) and Andrew Reed (Wayland, Massachusetts), the second being John Graves (Cincinnati, Ohio) and Peter Graves (Cincinnati, Ohio). With the fastest overall erg piece for the GRP on Saturday, Washburn was 19th in the highly competitive men’s pair field. Behind him was Reed in 21st, Peter Graves in 23rd and John Graves in 24th. Start order for the men’s pair was based off the erg average of the two rowers in each crew. This seeded the Washburn/Reed pair 10th and the Graves pair 12th.
On the water the GRP showed that erg times aren’t everything, beating several pairs with higher erg averages. The highest finisher was the Washburn/Reed pair, who placed sixth with a time of 14:42.7. About six seconds behind them were the Graves in ninth, with a time of 14:48.9.
The Fall Speed Order marks the last racing opportunity for the GRP this Fall.
The team will stay in New Jersey for a couple of days to take advantage of the milder New Jersey weather. Soaking up the last weeks of water in Craftsbury, the team plans to transition to indoors training and skiing. <img src="/assets/bulkUpload/USRowing-logo-2-color-01.png" alt="USRowing logo 2 color 01" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1580/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Time to Renew your Annual Membership!</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1139/</link>
			<description>Seasons are changing, geese are flying south, woodpiles are neatly stacked and ready to go - must be time to sign up for or renew your annual membership to the Outdoor Center! Last season’s memberships expire October 31st and winter is right around the corner, so you&#039;ll want to sign up today. By being a member of the Outdoor Center you have access so many great Center offerings, year round! This means unlimited use of the ski trails in the winter (also good for running/biking trail use in the summer); discounts on equipment rentals, meals yoga classes, CrossFit, Community Fitness, as well as the popular Hosmer Community Rowing Club in the summer! Our member e-newsletter will keep you up to date on the goings-on at the Center, such as member events like cider pressing, hikes and training on the Concept2 ergometer led by our own Green Racing Project athletes! There are also plenty of race opportunities for all ages with the summer trail racing series and winter ski races that members can join for free. Memberships range from $100 for families, $25 for students/seniors and $50 for single adults. (Are you a Craftsbury or Albany resident or landowner? Your membership is free after completing the resident member form).To become a member or renew your membership download the application here and send it to us to get in on all the action! You can also sign up at the touring center during the winter season and enjoy the trails all year long!Hope to see you enjoying campus and our activities soon!Full membership details</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2014 13:34:41 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[Seasons are changing, geese are flying south, woodpiles are neatly stacked and ready to go - must be time to sign up for or renew your annual membership to the Outdoor Center! Last season’s memberships expire October 31st and winter is right around the corner, so you&#039;ll want to sign up today. By being a member of the Outdoor Center you have access so many great Center offerings, year round! This means unlimited use of the ski trails in the winter (also good for running/biking trail use in the summer); discounts on equipment rentals, meals yoga classes, CrossFit, Community Fitness, as well as the popular Hosmer Community Rowing Club in the summer! Our member e-newsletter will keep you up to date on the goings-on at the Center, such as member events like cider pressing, hikes and training on the Concept2 ergometer led by our own Green Racing Project athletes! There are also plenty of race opportunities for all ages with the summer trail racing series and winter ski races that members can join for free. Memberships range from $100 for families, $25 for students/seniors and $50 for single adults. (Are you a Craftsbury or Albany resident or landowner? Your membership is free after completing the resident member form).To become a member or renew your membership download the application here and send it to us to get in on all the action! You can also sign up at the touring center during the winter season and enjoy the trails all year long!Hope to see you enjoying campus and our activities soon!Full membership details <img src="/assets/NewsImages/320-Annrenew1314.jpg" alt="320-Annrenew1314.jpg" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1139/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Two Wins for GRP Rowers at 51st Head of the Charles Regatta</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1572/</link>
			<description>The Green Racing Project brought home two wins this weekend at the 51st Head of the Charles Regatta in Boston.
Willy Cowles (Farmington, Connecticut) won Saturday’s Men’s Championship Double with partner Sam Stitt from Potomac Boat Club. The two beat out the Green Racing Project entry of Peter and Tom Graves (Cincinnati, Ohio), who placed second. The Graves had a faster time down the course than Cowles and Stitt by split seconds, but their final time was effected by a 5 second penalty from missing a buoy. This allowed Cowles and Stitt to squeak out the Graves with a time of 17:01.955.
Sunday’s GRP win came from Hugh McAdam (Hollis, New Hampshire) in the Lightweight Men’s Single. The 2014 winner of the event, McAdam’s victory this year came in a time of 18:36.
The GRP also saw highly competitive results from the rest of the contingency. Coach and Sculling Camp Director Troy Howell kicked off Saturday’s racing with the Men’s Master Single. He placed eighth with a time of 20:29. The winner of the event was Russell Cone from Wide Load Boat Club with a time of 19:32.
The GRP filled Men’s Championship Single featured four top ten finishes. Second place finisher John Graves (Cincinnati, Ohio) was 5 seconds within winner Mahe Drysdale from West End Rowing Club. That said, 5 second penalty from missing a buoy officially set him 10 seconds back from this year’s silver medalist at the World Championships in the single with a time of 18:21. The GRP’s youngest member, Ben Davison (Durham, England), found himself among the top singles in fourth place, with a time of 18:30. Erik Frid (Madbury, New Hampshire) placed ninth, Ben Dann (Pound Ridge, New York) placed tenth, Andrew Reed (Wayland, Massachusetts) placed 11th, and Parker Washburn (Andover, Massachusetts) placed 22nd.
In the Women’s Championship Single Maggie Fellows (Warwick, Massachusetts) was the top GRP finisher in seventh place. Not far behind her was Maddie Lips (Parker, Colorado), who placed 12th. The winner of the event was Generva Stone of Cambridge Boat Club, who took the event with a time of 19:43.
The last GRP event of the weekend was the Men’s Director Challenge Quads. The doubles of the Graves, Stitt and Cowles joined forces for this boat. Despite not having the proper steering mechanism installed in their boat and having to check down their oars on the Elliot turn, the crew ran down the course in a time of 15:34. This was the fastest raw time on the day, but with a 49 second age handicap factored in, the Fruit Loops quad won the day, with the Craftsbury/Potomac ending up in second place.
The GRP rowers will continue training on Great Hosmer Pond until it freezes over and will travel down to New Jersey for the USRowing East Coast Fall Speed Order in early November. Stay tuned for more news and results.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 22:32:23 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[The Green Racing Project brought home two wins this weekend at the 51st Head of the Charles Regatta in Boston.
Willy Cowles (Farmington, Connecticut) won Saturday’s Men’s Championship Double with partner Sam Stitt from Potomac Boat Club. The two beat out the Green Racing Project entry of Peter and Tom Graves (Cincinnati, Ohio), who placed second. The Graves had a faster time down the course than Cowles and Stitt by split seconds, but their final time was effected by a 5 second penalty from missing a buoy. This allowed Cowles and Stitt to squeak out the Graves with a time of 17:01.955.
Sunday’s GRP win came from Hugh McAdam (Hollis, New Hampshire) in the Lightweight Men’s Single. The 2014 winner of the event, McAdam’s victory this year came in a time of 18:36.
The GRP also saw highly competitive results from the rest of the contingency. Coach and Sculling Camp Director Troy Howell kicked off Saturday’s racing with the Men’s Master Single. He placed eighth with a time of 20:29. The winner of the event was Russell Cone from Wide Load Boat Club with a time of 19:32.
The GRP filled Men’s Championship Single featured four top ten finishes. Second place finisher John Graves (Cincinnati, Ohio) was 5 seconds within winner Mahe Drysdale from West End Rowing Club. That said, 5 second penalty from missing a buoy officially set him 10 seconds back from this year’s silver medalist at the World Championships in the single with a time of 18:21. The GRP’s youngest member, Ben Davison (Durham, England), found himself among the top singles in fourth place, with a time of 18:30. Erik Frid (Madbury, New Hampshire) placed ninth, Ben Dann (Pound Ridge, New York) placed tenth, Andrew Reed (Wayland, Massachusetts) placed 11th, and Parker Washburn (Andover, Massachusetts) placed 22nd.
In the Women’s Championship Single Maggie Fellows (Warwick, Massachusetts) was the top GRP finisher in seventh place. Not far behind her was Maddie Lips (Parker, Colorado), who placed 12th. The winner of the event was Generva Stone of Cambridge Boat Club, who took the event with a time of 19:43.
The last GRP event of the weekend was the Men’s Director Challenge Quads. The doubles of the Graves, Stitt and Cowles joined forces for this boat. Despite not having the proper steering mechanism installed in their boat and having to check down their oars on the Elliot turn, the crew ran down the course in a time of 15:34. This was the fastest raw time on the day, but with a 49 second age handicap factored in, the Fruit Loops quad won the day, with the Craftsbury/Potomac ending up in second place.
The GRP rowers will continue training on Great Hosmer Pond until it freezes over and will travel down to New Jersey for the USRowing East Coast Fall Speed Order in early November. Stay tuned for more news and results. <img src="/assets/Uploads/12079552-10153324027184022-1708479398043057420-n.jpg" alt="12079552 10153324027184022 1708479398043057420 n" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/1572/</guid>
		</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>