<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Craftsbury Outdoor Center News</title>
		<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/rss-feeds/grp-news/</link>
		<atom:link href="https://www.craftsbury.com/rss-feeds/grp-news/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<description></description>

		
		<item>
			<title>Craftsbury Runners at Catamount Ultra</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2289/</link>
			<description>On Saturday, a Craftsbury gang headed to the Trapp Family Lodge in Stowe for the Catamount Ultra and Salomon Running Festival. With beautiful weather, nearly 450 racers, and tasty food, it was a festival indeed! All of the Craftsbury runners participated in the 25k version, completed one lap of the undulating race loop that wound around the Trapps property. Running director Heidi Caldwell was the first woman across the line, in a time of 1:58:28. She was followed by new running staff member Alanna McDonough about six minutes behind in 2nd. Next was the GRP Snow crew, with Caitlin Patterson in 5th, Hallie Grossman in 7th, and Kelsey Dickinson in 10th. Avid community track attendee and Tuesday Night Race racer Perry Burnell finished 96th.Congratulations to all! See full results here. </description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 14:49:33 -0400</pubDate>
			
			
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2289/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>GRP Races at Canal de Lachine in Montreal</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2279/</link>
			<description>The GRP traveled to Canada last weekend for some good ole fashioned Quebecer racing. The 11th annual Lachine Regatta was held on the Canal de Lachine in Montreal. As this regatta was free of “US national ranking implications” the GRP decided to made the most of the trip by doubling up in two events each - everyone raced in both the 1x and the 4x.The first race of the day was the 1x event. There were nearly 50 entries between the open men/women, masters men/women, and junior boys/girls. The racecourse was a 5k stretch in a shipping canal. Much to Wes’ demise, the start line was about 1k downstream from a set of shipping locks, which he desperately wanted to row through. But, even without the locks, the course certainly had its share of crazy obstacles. Over the course of 5k, the competitors had to navigate themselves through six bridges and around countless port/starboard buoys - some of which were located in the middle of the canal. The format was head race style with approximately ten second intervals between each competitor. This made for some pretty interesting racing as there was a lot of passing and lead changes taking place in a narrow canal. It was a successful morning outing for everyone in the 1x as it was a total Cedar Leaf sweep in all events. The men took places 1-5 in the event with Lucas coming in first, followed by Kevin, Wes, Nate and Andy in that order. Alex and Bridget took first and second respectively in the women’s division, and Troy took home the W in the men’s masters 1x. The group came in for a quick snack and reboot before they headed out in quads. Both 4xs raced in the open men’s division, but had slightly diverse lineups in that the women, Alex and Bridget raced in each of the quads, and Troy joined one as well.The second race of the day turned into a GRP vs. GRP battle as the two boats were able to separate themselves from the rest of the field within the first two kilometers of the race. Eventually, the 4x with Lucas, Andy, Kevin and Bridget came out with the win over Troy, Nathan, Wes and Alex. It was a great event in Montreal and the GRP is grateful for the great hospitality of the folks at Lachine Rowing Club. They are now back on Hosmer and look forward to training for Club Nationals and Trials III.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 15:44:02 -0400</pubDate>
			
			
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2279/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>GRP Race at Trials II/Speed Order II</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2277/</link>
			<description>Last weekend the rowers of the Green Racing Project traveled to Princeton, NJ to compete in their second race of the 2019 season. The regatta had different implications for the men and the women, as it was Trials for the Women’s 2x – meaning that the winner of the regatta earned the right to represent the United States in the 2x at this summer’s World Championships in Linz, Austria. Whereas it was a Speed Order for the Men’s 2x – meaning that the winner of the regatta earned the right to race at World Cup II, but will have to race at Trials III in July to earn the right to race at the World Championships in August. After a successful Trials I in the 1x, the members of the GRP had to do a bit of “dating around” to find a partner in the lead up to 2x Trials. Some members of the team found their match within the GRP, ie. Wes and Nathan on the men’s side and Alex and Taylor on the women’s side. Meanwhile, other GRPers linked up with rowers from different club programs. Lucas raced with Jacob Plihal from Vesper, Kevin raced with JP Kirkegaard from Vesper, Andy raced with Eric Hallenbeck from MRC, John raced with Justin Keen from PennAC, and Bridget found her match in Charlotte Buck from NYAC.Racing kicked off on Thursday AM with a 1900m Time Trial. Due to limited entries, no crews were eliminated in the Time Trial, but were seeded into heats based on finish order. The heats were scheduled to take place Friday morning, but in true Princeton-in-the-Spring fashion, Friday afternoon winds forced the race officials to push racing forward by half a day. Therefore the heats took place Thursday evening. On the men’s side, the top four from each heat advanced to the A/B semis, and the fifth place crews went directly to the C-final. Wes/Nathan, Lucas/Jacob, Kevin/JP and John/Justin all advanced to the A/B Semis and Andy/Eric went on to race in and win the C-final. On the women’s side, only the top two from each heat advanced directly to the semi’s and all others went to Friday morning repechages. Alex/Taylor and Bridget/Charlotte narrowly missed out on the top two spots, therefore the two GRP boats had to face each other in Friday morning’s repechage. Alex/Taylor came out on top with Bridget/Charlotte taking second place. Unfortunately only Alex/Taylor were able to move on to the semi’s. Saturday morning&#039;s semis had mixed results for the GRP. Due to the Trials four-lane progression on the women’s side, only the top two from each semi advanced to the final on Sunday. Alex/Taylor took a hard-fought third place in their semi and therefore did not move onto the final. On the men’s side, the top three from each semi moved onto the A final and the rest went to the B final. John/Justin, Kevin/JP and Lucas/Jacob all advanced to the A-final. Wes/Nathan narrowly missed the cutoff, but went on to win Sunday’s B final. Sunday’s Men’s 2x A final was hot and GRP heavy as half of the boats in the final were powered by Cedar Leaves. John/Justin came away with the win with Kevin/JP coming in second and Lucas/Jacob taking fifth place!Overall it was a great weekend of racing for the GRP. The team is happy to be back training on Hosmer as they look ahead to Trials III and Club Nationals in July!</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 11:20:19 -0400</pubDate>
			
			
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2277/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>GRP Ski and Biathlon 2019-2020</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2271/</link>
			<description>The Green Racing Project ski program is excited to announce the addition of one new athlete for the 2019-2020 season: Williams College skier Braden Becker.Braden is originally from Yarmouth, Maine, where he grew up skiing for the Yarmouth Ski Club and Maine Winter Sports Club (MWSC). He spent a year as a post-graduate at Sun Valley Ski Education Foundation before attending Williams College in Williamstown, MA. During his senior year at Williams, Braden qualified for U23 World Championships in Lahti, Finland. He also finished in the top 15 at NCAA’s four separate times during his collegiate career. Braden graduates in the spring of 2019 with a double major in Computer Science and English. He hopes to use his computer science knowledge helping with the Center’s digital infrastructure and spreading its message. He also is looking forward to helping out with construction and maintenance projects.Please join us in welcoming Braden to the team!2019-2020 Green Racing Project Roster:SkiBraden BeckerElizabeth GuineyBen LustgartenAkeo Maifeld-CarucciAdam MartinKaitlynn MillerCaitlin PattersonBiathlonJake BrownKelsey DickinsonEmily DreissigackerSusan DunkleeClare EganRaleigh GoesslingHallie GrossmanAlex Howe</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 17:13:29 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[The Green Racing Project ski program is excited to announce the addition of one new athlete for the 2019-2020 season: Williams College skier Braden Becker.Braden is originally from Yarmouth, Maine, where he grew up skiing for the Yarmouth Ski Club and Maine Winter Sports Club (MWSC). He spent a year as a post-graduate at Sun Valley Ski Education Foundation before attending Williams College in Williamstown, MA. During his senior year at Williams, Braden qualified for U23 World Championships in Lahti, Finland. He also finished in the top 15 at NCAA’s four separate times during his collegiate career. Braden graduates in the spring of 2019 with a double major in Computer Science and English. He hopes to use his computer science knowledge helping with the Center’s digital infrastructure and spreading its message. He also is looking forward to helping out with construction and maintenance projects.Please join us in welcoming Braden to the team!2019-2020 Green Racing Project Roster:SkiBraden BeckerElizabeth GuineyBen LustgartenAkeo Maifeld-CarucciAdam MartinKaitlynn MillerCaitlin PattersonBiathlonJake BrownKelsey DickinsonEmily DreissigackerSusan DunkleeClare EganRaleigh GoesslingHallie GrossmanAlex Howe <img src="/assets/Uploads/Screen-Shot-2017-02-25-at-10.18.23-PM-copy.png" alt="Screen Shot 2017 02 25 at 10.18.23 PM copy" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2271/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Three Athletes join Summer Collegiate Ski Program at Craftsbury</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2272/</link>
			<description>The Outdoor Center is excited to welcome three athletes to our collegiate training program for the summer of 2019: Leah Brams from Dartmouth College, Alex Lawson from Middlebury College, and Evelina Sutro from University of Vermont (UVM). Summer collegiate athletes spend several months in Craftsbury training with the Green Racing Project ski and biathlon teams while working at the Outdoor Center, and then continue on with their collegiate teams for the fall and winter season.Leah grew up in Belmont, Massachusetts, skiing for the Cambridge Sports Union before going on to ski for Darmouth College. This spring, she will finish her junior year at Dartmouth, where she is majoring in Environmental Science and Chemistry. During the 2018-2019 season, she finished 2nd in the 15k freestyle at UNH Carnival and in the top 20 in the 10k classic at Senior Nationals in Craftsbury. She also made All-East second team, as a top 10 ranked EISA skier. Leah looks forward to putting her energy into training with a strong group of women this summer, as well as enjoying the Craftsbury food and lots of outdoor time. With her academic background, she hopes to help out with energy conservation and waste reduction work at the Center, as well as some bike mechanic work.Alex is a Burke, Vermont native and one of our own Craftsbury Nordic athletes. She recently finished her sophomore year at Middlebury College where she is majoring in Neuroscience and Computer Science. Alex competed for Middlebury at both the 2018 and 2019 NCAA’s, and loves racing on the EISA circuit. As a long-time Craftsbury Nordic athlete, she is excited to become more integrated with the Outdoor Center community and to train with the GRP athletes. She hopes to help out with youth programs at the COC, especially bike club, and also hopes to help with community events like the Tuesday Night running series.Evelina is originally from Carbondale, Colorado, but as a dual Swedish-American citizen, she lived in Mora, Sweden and raced for IFK Mora SK throughout high school. She recently finished her sophomore year at UVM, where she is majoring in Health Science. She had an outstanding sophomore season, which culminated in a 3rd place finish in the 5k freestyle at NCAA’s in Stowe, VT. As a returning Craftsbury Summer Collegiate athlete from 2018, she is excited to be back in Craftsbury training with the GRP athletes, especially during long OD’s. She also wants to help out again with coaching younger athletes in skiing and biking.Please join us in welcoming this strong group of collegiate athletes to Craftsbury for the summer!</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 16:37:45 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[The Outdoor Center is excited to welcome three athletes to our collegiate training program for the summer of 2019: Leah Brams from Dartmouth College, Alex Lawson from Middlebury College, and Evelina Sutro from University of Vermont (UVM). Summer collegiate athletes spend several months in Craftsbury training with the Green Racing Project ski and biathlon teams while working at the Outdoor Center, and then continue on with their collegiate teams for the fall and winter season.Leah grew up in Belmont, Massachusetts, skiing for the Cambridge Sports Union before going on to ski for Darmouth College. This spring, she will finish her junior year at Dartmouth, where she is majoring in Environmental Science and Chemistry. During the 2018-2019 season, she finished 2nd in the 15k freestyle at UNH Carnival and in the top 20 in the 10k classic at Senior Nationals in Craftsbury. She also made All-East second team, as a top 10 ranked EISA skier. Leah looks forward to putting her energy into training with a strong group of women this summer, as well as enjoying the Craftsbury food and lots of outdoor time. With her academic background, she hopes to help out with energy conservation and waste reduction work at the Center, as well as some bike mechanic work.Alex is a Burke, Vermont native and one of our own Craftsbury Nordic athletes. She recently finished her sophomore year at Middlebury College where she is majoring in Neuroscience and Computer Science. Alex competed for Middlebury at both the 2018 and 2019 NCAA’s, and loves racing on the EISA circuit. As a long-time Craftsbury Nordic athlete, she is excited to become more integrated with the Outdoor Center community and to train with the GRP athletes. She hopes to help out with youth programs at the COC, especially bike club, and also hopes to help with community events like the Tuesday Night running series.Evelina is originally from Carbondale, Colorado, but as a dual Swedish-American citizen, she lived in Mora, Sweden and raced for IFK Mora SK throughout high school. She recently finished her sophomore year at UVM, where she is majoring in Health Science. She had an outstanding sophomore season, which culminated in a 3rd place finish in the 5k freestyle at NCAA’s in Stowe, VT. As a returning Craftsbury Summer Collegiate athlete from 2018, she is excited to be back in Craftsbury training with the GRP athletes, especially during long OD’s. She also wants to help out again with coaching younger athletes in skiing and biking.Please join us in welcoming this strong group of collegiate athletes to Craftsbury for the summer! <img src="/assets/Uploads/QRHXYFBZDMERAJT.20171206180639.jpg" alt="QRHXYFBZDMERAJT.20171206180639" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2272/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>U23 Sculling assistant, intern named</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2270/</link>
			<description>Grace Hollowell is returning to Craftsbury for her second summer as assistant coach for the Green Racing Project (GRP). Hollowell brings a wealth of coaching experience to GRP. A member of the Boston College coaching staff since fall 2018, she previously spent four years as the assistant women’s coach and recruiting coordinator at Dartmouth. She had coaching stints at Boston University (2013-14) and Smith College (2011-13). GRP head coach Steve Whelpley says “(Grace) gets our approach to small boats and individualized attention, but also brings a different perspective from her years coaching at various collegiate programs. We look forward to her leadership and ideas for the summer.&quot;Last summer at Craftsbury Hollowell helped coach the U23 M2x and M1x that qualified for the 2018 World Championships in Poland. She also coached the M2x and W4x that won the Royal Canadian Henley that summer. Before starting her career as a coach, she rowed at Harvard, where she was the captain of the lightweight team. Hollowell earned three varsity letters, was named team MVP twice, was an Eastern Association of Women’s Rowing Colleges (EAWRC) gold medalist, and completed her Bachelor of Arts degree. While coaching at Smith (2011-13), Hollowell also completed her Master of Science degree.Hollowell says she is “incredibly excited to return to Craftsbury this summer to work with a talented, driven, and thoughtful group of athletes and coaches. The community and culture of Craftsbury foster a unique experience that creates mindful, focused athletes who can make boats go fast and compete at the highest level. Not to mention you can&#039;t beat Vermont in the summer (or the food!!).&quot;We&#039;re equally excited about another successful summer with Grace!The Green Racing Project is pleased to welcome its first-ever summer intern, Mackenzi Sherman, this summer. &quot;Craftsbury has a wealth of coaches on campus during the summer. The addition of the GRP internship will allow for an up-and-coming coach to gain exposure to not only the GRP coaches but all those who coach throughout the summer camps,” says Coach Steve. Sherman has just finished her second season as the graduate assistant coach at Smith College, where she is getting her master’s degree in Exercise and Sport Studies. Before going to Smith, she spent the 2016-17 season as a volunteer assistant coach at Virginia - her alma mater.Sherman was a member of the UVA Women’s Rowing Team, earning three varsity letters (2014-16), All-ACC Second Team honors (2015-16) and was named to the All-ACC Academic Rowing Team in 2014 and 2016. She rowed on the Second Varsity Eight in 2016, when it won the ACC Championship. The same year, she rowed on the Second Varsity Eight when it placed fourth at the NCAA Championships. In 2013-14, Sherman was stroke seat on the Varsity Eight, which won the ACC Championship and placed third at NCAAs. We look forward to getting to know, grow, and row with you Mackenzi!</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 15:52:47 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[Grace Hollowell is returning to Craftsbury for her second summer as assistant coach for the Green Racing Project (GRP). Hollowell brings a wealth of coaching experience to GRP. A member of the Boston College coaching staff since fall 2018, she previously spent four years as the assistant women’s coach and recruiting coordinator at Dartmouth. She had coaching stints at Boston University (2013-14) and Smith College (2011-13). GRP head coach Steve Whelpley says “(Grace) gets our approach to small boats and individualized attention, but also brings a different perspective from her years coaching at various collegiate programs. We look forward to her leadership and ideas for the summer.&quot;Last summer at Craftsbury Hollowell helped coach the U23 M2x and M1x that qualified for the 2018 World Championships in Poland. She also coached the M2x and W4x that won the Royal Canadian Henley that summer. Before starting her career as a coach, she rowed at Harvard, where she was the captain of the lightweight team. Hollowell earned three varsity letters, was named team MVP twice, was an Eastern Association of Women’s Rowing Colleges (EAWRC) gold medalist, and completed her Bachelor of Arts degree. While coaching at Smith (2011-13), Hollowell also completed her Master of Science degree.Hollowell says she is “incredibly excited to return to Craftsbury this summer to work with a talented, driven, and thoughtful group of athletes and coaches. The community and culture of Craftsbury foster a unique experience that creates mindful, focused athletes who can make boats go fast and compete at the highest level. Not to mention you can&#039;t beat Vermont in the summer (or the food!!).&quot;We&#039;re equally excited about another successful summer with Grace!The Green Racing Project is pleased to welcome its first-ever summer intern, Mackenzi Sherman, this summer. &quot;Craftsbury has a wealth of coaches on campus during the summer. The addition of the GRP internship will allow for an up-and-coming coach to gain exposure to not only the GRP coaches but all those who coach throughout the summer camps,” says Coach Steve. Sherman has just finished her second season as the graduate assistant coach at Smith College, where she is getting her master’s degree in Exercise and Sport Studies. Before going to Smith, she spent the 2016-17 season as a volunteer assistant coach at Virginia - her alma mater.Sherman was a member of the UVA Women’s Rowing Team, earning three varsity letters (2014-16), All-ACC Second Team honors (2015-16) and was named to the All-ACC Academic Rowing Team in 2014 and 2016. She rowed on the Second Varsity Eight in 2016, when it won the ACC Championship. The same year, she rowed on the Second Varsity Eight when it placed fourth at the NCAA Championships. In 2013-14, Sherman was stroke seat on the Varsity Eight, which won the ACC Championship and placed third at NCAAs. We look forward to getting to know, grow, and row with you Mackenzi! <img src="/assets/Uploads/19-Grace-Hollowell-w3.jpg" alt="19 Grace Hollowell w3" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2270/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Green Racing Project at SuperTour Finals</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2265/</link>
			<description>The Green Racing Project skiers finished up their 2018-2019 season in Presque Isle, Maine, with a four race series at SuperTour Finals. Always the last races of the season, SuperTour Finals are one of the few times when American World Cup skiers return to the US to compete with the domestic field. This year, the races also were the final hurrah for GRP skier Ida Sargent, who announced her retirement from the sport a few weeks ago.March 29- Freestyle SprintRaces kicked off with a freestyle sprint. All six GRP athletes qualified: Ida Sargent led the women in 3rd, Caitlin Patterson took 9th, Kaitlynn Miller was 13th, and Liz Guiney took 18th. On the men&#039;s side, Ben Lustgarten qualified in 16th and Akeo Maifeld-Carucci took 22nd. Sargent skied well all the way through the heats, eventually taking 2nd in the A Final. Patterson also skied well, winning her quarterfinal heat and placing 5th in her semifinal for 10th overall. Guiney and Miller were eliminated in the quarterfinals, and placed 14th and 16th, respectively. Lustgarten and Maifeld-Carucci were also bumped out in quarterfinals and placed 14th and 23rd, respectively.March 30- 10/15k Classic Mass StartThe following day brought fast icy tracks for a classic mass start. After several hours of delay to soften the course, the men were underway with their 15k. Lustgarten skied well, placing 8th, and Maifeld-Carucci took 19th place. In the women&#039;s 10k mass start, Sargent built on her momentum from the previous day and took 5th place, followed by Patterson in 6th. Miller took 9th, and Guiney was 20th.March 31- Mixed Club 4x5k RelayOn the third consecutive day of racing, athletes had to put it all on the line for their teams in the mixed club relay. The format was as follows: 4x5k starting with a female classic leg, then a male classic leg, a female freestyle leg, then finishing with a male freestyle leg. The GRP I &quot;Cedar Leaves&quot; team of Ida Sargent, Ben Lustgarten, Caitlin Patterson, and Akeo Maifeld-Carucci took 4th place in the official category, close to the podium. Liz Guiney and Kaitlynn Miller teamed up with Alaska Winter Stars skier Gus Schumacher and Salomon rep/former GRP skier Bryan Cook. Their team took 2nd in the unofficial category and 7th overall.April 2- 30/50k Freestyle Mass StartAfter a rest day, athletes took on the final race of the season and arguably one of the most grueling: 30 and 50k freestyle mass starts. The women went first, skiing in fast conditions for their 30k. Patterson led the way for the GRP, finishing 7th. Miller took 9th, Sargent was 12th, Guiney was 17th, and biathlete Kelsey Dickinson took 28th. The men raced 50k a few hours later in ever softening snow. Biathlete Jake Brown stayed with the lead pack for the majority of the race and finished 5th. Lustgarten skied a blazing last two laps to finish 6th, followed by Maifeld-Carucci in 11th and Adam Martin was 14th. Results from SuperTour Finals are available on BullittTiming. With the season over, the skiers and biathletes will take a rest before resuming the training season in May!</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 09:51:35 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[The Green Racing Project skiers finished up their 2018-2019 season in Presque Isle, Maine, with a four race series at SuperTour Finals. Always the last races of the season, SuperTour Finals are one of the few times when American World Cup skiers return to the US to compete with the domestic field. This year, the races also were the final hurrah for GRP skier Ida Sargent, who announced her retirement from the sport a few weeks ago.March 29- Freestyle SprintRaces kicked off with a freestyle sprint. All six GRP athletes qualified: Ida Sargent led the women in 3rd, Caitlin Patterson took 9th, Kaitlynn Miller was 13th, and Liz Guiney took 18th. On the men&#039;s side, Ben Lustgarten qualified in 16th and Akeo Maifeld-Carucci took 22nd. Sargent skied well all the way through the heats, eventually taking 2nd in the A Final. Patterson also skied well, winning her quarterfinal heat and placing 5th in her semifinal for 10th overall. Guiney and Miller were eliminated in the quarterfinals, and placed 14th and 16th, respectively. Lustgarten and Maifeld-Carucci were also bumped out in quarterfinals and placed 14th and 23rd, respectively.March 30- 10/15k Classic Mass StartThe following day brought fast icy tracks for a classic mass start. After several hours of delay to soften the course, the men were underway with their 15k. Lustgarten skied well, placing 8th, and Maifeld-Carucci took 19th place. In the women&#039;s 10k mass start, Sargent built on her momentum from the previous day and took 5th place, followed by Patterson in 6th. Miller took 9th, and Guiney was 20th.March 31- Mixed Club 4x5k RelayOn the third consecutive day of racing, athletes had to put it all on the line for their teams in the mixed club relay. The format was as follows: 4x5k starting with a female classic leg, then a male classic leg, a female freestyle leg, then finishing with a male freestyle leg. The GRP I &quot;Cedar Leaves&quot; team of Ida Sargent, Ben Lustgarten, Caitlin Patterson, and Akeo Maifeld-Carucci took 4th place in the official category, close to the podium. Liz Guiney and Kaitlynn Miller teamed up with Alaska Winter Stars skier Gus Schumacher and Salomon rep/former GRP skier Bryan Cook. Their team took 2nd in the unofficial category and 7th overall.April 2- 30/50k Freestyle Mass StartAfter a rest day, athletes took on the final race of the season and arguably one of the most grueling: 30 and 50k freestyle mass starts. The women went first, skiing in fast conditions for their 30k. Patterson led the way for the GRP, finishing 7th. Miller took 9th, Sargent was 12th, Guiney was 17th, and biathlete Kelsey Dickinson took 28th. The men raced 50k a few hours later in ever softening snow. Biathlete Jake Brown stayed with the lead pack for the majority of the race and finished 5th. Lustgarten skied a blazing last two laps to finish 6th, followed by Maifeld-Carucci in 11th and Adam Martin was 14th. Results from SuperTour Finals are available on BullittTiming. With the season over, the skiers and biathletes will take a rest before resuming the training season in May! <img src="/assets/Uploads/STFteampic.jpg" alt="STFteampic" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2265/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>GRP and Craftsbury Junior Biathletes Podium at Nationals in Jericho </title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2264/</link>
			<description>This past weekend the full GRP biathlon crew as well as some Craftsbury junior biathletes competed at US Biathlon Nationals in Jericho, Vermont. Sprint:The three-day Championship event kicked off with a sprint. The GRP women cleaned the senior race with Susan Dunklee on the top step of the podium followed by Clare Egan in second, only 0.3 seconds back, and Kelsey Dickinson in third. Kelsey and Clare only had one miss each. Hallie Grossman was the next GRP finisher in 5th with two misses and Emily Dreissigacker placed 6th with three misses. While the women left big shoes to fill, the GRP men were up for the challenge with Jake Brown taking the win with two misses. Alex Howe also had a strong race finishing 5th with 3 misses. Raleigh Goessling finished 8th also with three misses and junior biathlon coach Ethan Dreissigacker placed 12th. In the junior womens race, former Craftsbury junior (and current William’s College skier) Marika Massey-Bierman raced her way onto the podium in third. She was followed by GRP rower Jenny Mcilvane in fourth. In the youth mens race, Bjorn Westervelt placed first. In the U15 girls race, Amelia Circosta raced her way onto the top tier of the podium while her brother Leo Circosta also had a strong race placing 5th in the U15 boys race.Pursuit:In the following day’s pursuit event, Susan defended her position once again racing her onto the top of the podium with seven misses. Hallie moved up into second and Kelsey defended her third place position for another GRP podium sweep. Emily placed 5th and Hannah Dreissigacker came out of retirement to place 7th. Clare sat out the race due to illness. For the men, Jake stayed on the podium in second with four misses while Alex and Raleigh maintained their positions in 5th and 8th respectively each with 7 misses. Ethan moved up to 10th place with 6 misses. In the junior womens race, Jenny moved up onto the podium in third. Bjorn Westervelt finished second in the youth mens race. Continuing the podium trend were Amelia and Ruth Krebs who finished an impressive first and third respectively in the U15 girls race. In the U15 boys event, Leo placed 5th closely followed by Charlie Krebs in 6th. Super Sprint:For the senior athletes, the final event of the National Championship weekend, and the season as a whole, was the Super Sprint. Susan made it three-for-three with her third win of the weekend. Clare made a comeback and placed second with clean shooting and Emily raced her way onto the podium in third, with only one miss, for the third GRP women’s podium sweep in as many races. Kelsey also had a strong race placing 4th with 2 misses and Hallie finished 9th. For the men, Jake finished 6th with Alex closely behind in 7th. Raleigh and Ethan placed 9th and 13th respectively. Mass Start:The Craftsbury juniors finished up their weekend with a mass start event. Jenny raced her way onto the podium in third for the second day in a row in the junior womens race while in the youth mens race, Bjorn ended the season on a high note with another win. In the U15 girls race, Amelia placed second and Ruth 6th while in the boys race their brothers, Leo and Charlie, finished 4th and 5th respectively. And that, my friends, concludes the biathlon racing season! Thank you for following and have a great spring!Results:Sprint | Pursuit | Super Sprint | Mass Start   </description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 15:39:15 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[This past weekend the full GRP biathlon crew as well as some Craftsbury junior biathletes competed at US Biathlon Nationals in Jericho, Vermont. Sprint:The three-day Championship event kicked off with a sprint. The GRP women cleaned the senior race with Susan Dunklee on the top step of the podium followed by Clare Egan in second, only 0.3 seconds back, and Kelsey Dickinson in third. Kelsey and Clare only had one miss each. Hallie Grossman was the next GRP finisher in 5th with two misses and Emily Dreissigacker placed 6th with three misses. While the women left big shoes to fill, the GRP men were up for the challenge with Jake Brown taking the win with two misses. Alex Howe also had a strong race finishing 5th with 3 misses. Raleigh Goessling finished 8th also with three misses and junior biathlon coach Ethan Dreissigacker placed 12th. In the junior womens race, former Craftsbury junior (and current William’s College skier) Marika Massey-Bierman raced her way onto the podium in third. She was followed by GRP rower Jenny Mcilvane in fourth. In the youth mens race, Bjorn Westervelt placed first. In the U15 girls race, Amelia Circosta raced her way onto the top tier of the podium while her brother Leo Circosta also had a strong race placing 5th in the U15 boys race.Pursuit:In the following day’s pursuit event, Susan defended her position once again racing her onto the top of the podium with seven misses. Hallie moved up into second and Kelsey defended her third place position for another GRP podium sweep. Emily placed 5th and Hannah Dreissigacker came out of retirement to place 7th. Clare sat out the race due to illness. For the men, Jake stayed on the podium in second with four misses while Alex and Raleigh maintained their positions in 5th and 8th respectively each with 7 misses. Ethan moved up to 10th place with 6 misses. In the junior womens race, Jenny moved up onto the podium in third. Bjorn Westervelt finished second in the youth mens race. Continuing the podium trend were Amelia and Ruth Krebs who finished an impressive first and third respectively in the U15 girls race. In the U15 boys event, Leo placed 5th closely followed by Charlie Krebs in 6th. Super Sprint:For the senior athletes, the final event of the National Championship weekend, and the season as a whole, was the Super Sprint. Susan made it three-for-three with her third win of the weekend. Clare made a comeback and placed second with clean shooting and Emily raced her way onto the podium in third, with only one miss, for the third GRP women’s podium sweep in as many races. Kelsey also had a strong race placing 4th with 2 misses and Hallie finished 9th. For the men, Jake finished 6th with Alex closely behind in 7th. Raleigh and Ethan placed 9th and 13th respectively. Mass Start:The Craftsbury juniors finished up their weekend with a mass start event. Jenny raced her way onto the podium in third for the second day in a row in the junior womens race while in the youth mens race, Bjorn ended the season on a high note with another win. In the U15 girls race, Amelia placed second and Ruth 6th while in the boys race their brothers, Leo and Charlie, finished 4th and 5th respectively. And that, my friends, concludes the biathlon racing season! Thank you for following and have a great spring!Results:Sprint | Pursuit | Super Sprint | Mass Start    <img src="/assets/Uploads/4.1.19biathlonnewsphoto1.jpeg" alt="4.1.19biathlonnewsphoto1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2264/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Sargent Retires from World Cup Racing in Quebec City</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2261/</link>
			<description>It was an emotional and bittersweet weekend in Quebec City as Green Racing Project and US Ski and Snowboard athlete Ida Sargent skied the final World Cup races of her career. She has been racing full-time for the past 9 years, and represented the US in two Olympics (in 2014 and 2018). At the tail end of a long and successful career, she is hanging up the boards this year, but not without leaving a lasting impression on the Craftsbury community and the next generation of nordic athletes. Because the World Cup season ended close to home in North America, Sargent was able to ski her last races in front of her family, longtime GRP coach Pepa Miloucheva, teammates, friends, and supporters. In addition, her GRP teammates Kaitlynn Miller and Caitlin Patterson raced with the US team in Quebec City.Freestyle SprintRacing action kicked off on Friday, March 22 with a freestyle sprint. With a lack of an overnight freeze and new precipitation, the course quickly turned to soft, ankle deep slush, which was an added challenge for the athletes. Unfortunately, both Sargent and Miller were racing with colds, but they put in their best effort regardless. Sargent finished 49th in the qualifier, Caitlin Patterson took 58th, and Miller was 61st.Classic Mass StartThe following day, the course firmed up well, making for fast classic tracks and treacherous downhills. In the women&#039;s 10k mass start, Sargent led the way for the Green Team women placing 48th, followed closely by Miller in 49th, and Patterson in 53rd.Freestyle PursuitThe final day of competition brought a freestyle pursuit, with start order determined by the combined time of the previous two day&#039;s races, in addition to any bonus seconds picked up along the way. Sargent, Miller, and Patterson all started in a wave +3:10 behind the first skier. Patterson skied up from her starting position of 52, finishing 46th in the overall mini-tour with the 43rd fastest time of the day. Sargent finished in 48th place, and Miller was 52nd. Upon crossing the line, Sargent&#039;s teammates immediately showered her in champagne and gathered her in a group hug.Full results from the weekend are available on FIS-Ski.com. The Green Team will finish their season March 29-April 2 in Presque Isle, ME for SuperTour Finals. </description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 13:56:10 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[It was an emotional and bittersweet weekend in Quebec City as Green Racing Project and US Ski and Snowboard athlete Ida Sargent skied the final World Cup races of her career. She has been racing full-time for the past 9 years, and represented the US in two Olympics (in 2014 and 2018). At the tail end of a long and successful career, she is hanging up the boards this year, but not without leaving a lasting impression on the Craftsbury community and the next generation of nordic athletes. Because the World Cup season ended close to home in North America, Sargent was able to ski her last races in front of her family, longtime GRP coach Pepa Miloucheva, teammates, friends, and supporters. In addition, her GRP teammates Kaitlynn Miller and Caitlin Patterson raced with the US team in Quebec City.Freestyle SprintRacing action kicked off on Friday, March 22 with a freestyle sprint. With a lack of an overnight freeze and new precipitation, the course quickly turned to soft, ankle deep slush, which was an added challenge for the athletes. Unfortunately, both Sargent and Miller were racing with colds, but they put in their best effort regardless. Sargent finished 49th in the qualifier, Caitlin Patterson took 58th, and Miller was 61st.Classic Mass StartThe following day, the course firmed up well, making for fast classic tracks and treacherous downhills. In the women&#039;s 10k mass start, Sargent led the way for the Green Team women placing 48th, followed closely by Miller in 49th, and Patterson in 53rd.Freestyle PursuitThe final day of competition brought a freestyle pursuit, with start order determined by the combined time of the previous two day&#039;s races, in addition to any bonus seconds picked up along the way. Sargent, Miller, and Patterson all started in a wave +3:10 behind the first skier. Patterson skied up from her starting position of 52, finishing 46th in the overall mini-tour with the 43rd fastest time of the day. Sargent finished in 48th place, and Miller was 52nd. Upon crossing the line, Sargent&#039;s teammates immediately showered her in champagne and gathered her in a group hug.Full results from the weekend are available on FIS-Ski.com. The Green Team will finish their season March 29-April 2 in Presque Isle, ME for SuperTour Finals.  <img src="/assets/Uploads/Pursuit-3.24.19-4-2-1024x592.jpg" alt="Pursuit 3.24.19 4 2 1024x592" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2261/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Clare Egan on World Cup Podium at Holmenkollen </title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2262/</link>
			<description>This past weekend the IBU World Cup season wrapped up at the Holmenkollen stadium in Oslo, Norway. Three GRP biathletes toed the line and came away with strong results highlighted by Clare Egan’s first ever podium finish in the mass start.The weekend got underway with a sprint event in which Clare finished 12th with just one standing miss. Susan Dunklee placed 30th with two misses, one in each stage. For the men, Jake Brown placed a solid 47th with three misses.  All three GRP biathletes qualified for the pursuit. Clare moved up to 9th place with three misses. She cleaned both middles stages. Susan moved up considerably placing 18th also with three misses. She cleaned her first two stages. In the men&#039;s race, Jake finished 48th with four misses.                     Clare was the only GRP athlete in the mass start, but she represented the team well racing to her first ever World Cup podium in 3rd. She had the best shooting in the race with only one miss. In a winter full of strong performances and personal bests for Clare, it seems only fitting that she would race her way onto the podium in the season’s final World Cup. While the IBU and World Cup seasons have come to a close, there’s one more biathlon event still to come: Nationals in Jericho, Vermont. Racing starts Friday (3/29) and the whole GRP biathlon will be competing so stay tuned for one more dose of biathlon fun before the off-season is upon us!Full World Cup results can be found at biathlonworld.com. </description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 14:58:09 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[This past weekend the IBU World Cup season wrapped up at the Holmenkollen stadium in Oslo, Norway. Three GRP biathletes toed the line and came away with strong results highlighted by Clare Egan’s first ever podium finish in the mass start.The weekend got underway with a sprint event in which Clare finished 12th with just one standing miss. Susan Dunklee placed 30th with two misses, one in each stage. For the men, Jake Brown placed a solid 47th with three misses.  All three GRP biathletes qualified for the pursuit. Clare moved up to 9th place with three misses. She cleaned both middles stages. Susan moved up considerably placing 18th also with three misses. She cleaned her first two stages. In the men&#039;s race, Jake finished 48th with four misses.                     Clare was the only GRP athlete in the mass start, but she represented the team well racing to her first ever World Cup podium in 3rd. She had the best shooting in the race with only one miss. In a winter full of strong performances and personal bests for Clare, it seems only fitting that she would race her way onto the podium in the season’s final World Cup. While the IBU and World Cup seasons have come to a close, there’s one more biathlon event still to come: Nationals in Jericho, Vermont. Racing starts Friday (3/29) and the whole GRP biathlon will be competing so stay tuned for one more dose of biathlon fun before the off-season is upon us!Full World Cup results can be found at biathlonworld.com.  <img src="/assets/Uploads/3.26.19biathlonnewsphoto1.jpg" alt="3.26.19biathlonnewsphoto1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2262/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>GRP Biathletes Post Standout Results at World Champs</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2257/</link>
			<description>IBU World Championships wrapped up this past weekend in Oestersund, Sweden. Five GRP biathletes represented the US at this championship event which consisted of 7 races over 10 days.Mixed Relay: Susan Dunklee and Clare Egan were joined by USBA teammates Sean Doherty and Leif Nordgren in the mixed relay race. Susan scrambled for the team cleaning both stages and using 5 spares. She tagged off to Clare who also cleaned both her stages using 3 spares. The team placed 19th with three penalty laps and a total of 13 spares.Sprint: In the women’s sprint race, Clare had an outstanding performance placing 11th with just one prone miss. Susan placed 57th. In the men’s race, Jake Brown finished 58th cleaning the prone stage in his World Champs debut. All three athletes qualified for the follow day’s pursuit race.Pursuit: In the pursuit, Clare moved back one place to finish 12th with 5 misses. Susan moved up considerably finishing 24th with 3 misses. For the men, Jake also moved up placing 53rd with 7 misses.Individual: In the individual race, Susan was the top GRP finisher placing 30th with 3 misses. She cleaned her first shooting stage. Clare placed 53rd with 5 misses. In the men’s race, Jake placed 68th.Single Mixed: In the single mixed relay, Susan was joined by USBA teammate Sean Doherty. Susan cleaned her first three shooting stages with no spares and then used two spares in her final stage. The duo placed 13th with a one penalty lap and total of 7 spares.Women’s Relay: In the women’s relay, Susan, Clare, and Emily Dreissigacker were joined by USBA teammate Joanne Reid. Susan gave the team a strong start with fast skiing and accurate shooting. She used one spare and tagged off to Clare in podium contention. Clare also had a strong leg shooting clean with no spares and tagging off to Joanne in the lead. Emily anchored the team in her inaugural World Champs appearance. The team placed 9th with a total of 2 penalties and 5 spares for their best-ever women’s relay World Champs performance.Men’s Relay: In the men’s relay, Jake and Alex Howe were joined by USBA teammates Leif Nordgren and Max Durtschi. Jake skied the second leg and Alex, in his first World Champs race, skied the third. Both men had strong performances each cleaning their respective shooting stages and only using two spares each. Mass start: Clare was the only GRP athletes to qualify for the mass start. She had a solid race placing 26th with 5 misses.World Cup racing action concludes next weekend with the final World Cup of the season hosted at the iconic Holmenkollen stadium in Oslo Norway. For more information and full results please visit biathlonworld.com.    </description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 13:38:26 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[IBU World Championships wrapped up this past weekend in Oestersund, Sweden. Five GRP biathletes represented the US at this championship event which consisted of 7 races over 10 days.Mixed Relay: Susan Dunklee and Clare Egan were joined by USBA teammates Sean Doherty and Leif Nordgren in the mixed relay race. Susan scrambled for the team cleaning both stages and using 5 spares. She tagged off to Clare who also cleaned both her stages using 3 spares. The team placed 19th with three penalty laps and a total of 13 spares.Sprint: In the women’s sprint race, Clare had an outstanding performance placing 11th with just one prone miss. Susan placed 57th. In the men’s race, Jake Brown finished 58th cleaning the prone stage in his World Champs debut. All three athletes qualified for the follow day’s pursuit race.Pursuit: In the pursuit, Clare moved back one place to finish 12th with 5 misses. Susan moved up considerably finishing 24th with 3 misses. For the men, Jake also moved up placing 53rd with 7 misses.Individual: In the individual race, Susan was the top GRP finisher placing 30th with 3 misses. She cleaned her first shooting stage. Clare placed 53rd with 5 misses. In the men’s race, Jake placed 68th.Single Mixed: In the single mixed relay, Susan was joined by USBA teammate Sean Doherty. Susan cleaned her first three shooting stages with no spares and then used two spares in her final stage. The duo placed 13th with a one penalty lap and total of 7 spares.Women’s Relay: In the women’s relay, Susan, Clare, and Emily Dreissigacker were joined by USBA teammate Joanne Reid. Susan gave the team a strong start with fast skiing and accurate shooting. She used one spare and tagged off to Clare in podium contention. Clare also had a strong leg shooting clean with no spares and tagging off to Joanne in the lead. Emily anchored the team in her inaugural World Champs appearance. The team placed 9th with a total of 2 penalties and 5 spares for their best-ever women’s relay World Champs performance.Men’s Relay: In the men’s relay, Jake and Alex Howe were joined by USBA teammates Leif Nordgren and Max Durtschi. Jake skied the second leg and Alex, in his first World Champs race, skied the third. Both men had strong performances each cleaning their respective shooting stages and only using two spares each. Mass start: Clare was the only GRP athletes to qualify for the mass start. She had a solid race placing 26th with 5 misses.World Cup racing action concludes next weekend with the final World Cup of the season hosted at the iconic Holmenkollen stadium in Oslo Norway. For more information and full results please visit biathlonworld.com.     <img src="/assets/Uploads/3.19.19biathlonphoto1.jpg" alt="3.19.19biathlonphoto1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2257/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>GRP Skiers at Falun World Cup</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2256/</link>
			<description>Over the weekend, Green Racing Project skiers competed in the final European World Cup races of the season in Falun, Sweden. With the Drammen sprints just four days prior, the turnaround to Falun was a tight one. Kaitlynn Miller, as the SuperTour leader, competed in both the freestyle sprint and 10k freestyle, while Ida Sargent raced the sprint.In Saturday&#039;s sprint, skiers faced one of the shorter World Cup sprint courses, but also one with very technical downhills. In spring conditions, some of the downhill corners accumulated deep slush and ruts that took out many skiers. In the qualifier, Sargent finished 37th, just over one second from the top 30. Miller fell prey to a slushy corner in her qualifier and ended up 61st.The following day was a 10k freestyle individual start. Miller had her best World Cup result of the season, finishing 34th in the 10k. She was +2:21 from winner Therese Johaug (who beat 2nd place by almost 20 seconds).With the European World Cup circuit completed, there is only one weekend of racing remaining in the WC season. On February 22-24, Quebec City will host a three race weekend, including a freestyle sprint, classic mass start, and freestyle pursuit. Sargent and Miller will be joined by Caitlin Patterson on the US World Cup team for Quebec.Results from Falun are available, as always, on FIS-ski.com. </description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 13:08:30 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[Over the weekend, Green Racing Project skiers competed in the final European World Cup races of the season in Falun, Sweden. With the Drammen sprints just four days prior, the turnaround to Falun was a tight one. Kaitlynn Miller, as the SuperTour leader, competed in both the freestyle sprint and 10k freestyle, while Ida Sargent raced the sprint.In Saturday&#039;s sprint, skiers faced one of the shorter World Cup sprint courses, but also one with very technical downhills. In spring conditions, some of the downhill corners accumulated deep slush and ruts that took out many skiers. In the qualifier, Sargent finished 37th, just over one second from the top 30. Miller fell prey to a slushy corner in her qualifier and ended up 61st.The following day was a 10k freestyle individual start. Miller had her best World Cup result of the season, finishing 34th in the 10k. She was +2:21 from winner Therese Johaug (who beat 2nd place by almost 20 seconds).With the European World Cup circuit completed, there is only one weekend of racing remaining in the WC season. On February 22-24, Quebec City will host a three race weekend, including a freestyle sprint, classic mass start, and freestyle pursuit. Sargent and Miller will be joined by Caitlin Patterson on the US World Cup team for Quebec.Results from Falun are available, as always, on FIS-ski.com.  <img src="/assets/Uploads/28576966-417185725409355-3594200182649545304-n.jpg" alt="28576966 417185725409355 3594200182649545304 n" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2256/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>GRP Athletes Compete at Holmenkollen and Drammen World Cups</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2252/</link>
			<description>The World Cup season is winding down, which usually means it&#039;s time for the annual stop in Oslo, Norway, for two of the biggest events of the year. On March 9 and 10, Oslo hosted the iconic Holmenkollen 30/50k ski races. Then, two days later racing moved to Drammen, Norway for city sprints. The races boast some of the largest and rowdiest crowds of the season, with campfires lining the courses and spectators camped out for day before. Four GRP athletes competed in either the Holmenkollen or Drammen, or both.On Saturday, women raced 30k classic on the tough Oslo courses, and GRP athlete Kaitlynn Miller finished 42nd. The next day, the men raced 50k on the same courses. Adam Martin finished 31st, just outside the points, and a new personal best World Cup result for him. Ben Lustgarten also started, but was a DNF as a result of vertigo he experienced during the race.On Tuesday, the World Cup moved to Drammen for classic city sprints. Ida Sargent was close to making the heats, finishing the qualifier in 34th place, about 2.5 seconds from the top 30. Kailtynn Miller finished 55th in the qualifier.Results from the Holmenkollen are available here, and Drammen here. The World Cup moves to Falun, Sweden this weekend for an all freestyle weekend, featuring a sprint and 10/15k distance race.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 17:42:56 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[The World Cup season is winding down, which usually means it&#039;s time for the annual stop in Oslo, Norway, for two of the biggest events of the year. On March 9 and 10, Oslo hosted the iconic Holmenkollen 30/50k ski races. Then, two days later racing moved to Drammen, Norway for city sprints. The races boast some of the largest and rowdiest crowds of the season, with campfires lining the courses and spectators camped out for day before. Four GRP athletes competed in either the Holmenkollen or Drammen, or both.On Saturday, women raced 30k classic on the tough Oslo courses, and GRP athlete Kaitlynn Miller finished 42nd. The next day, the men raced 50k on the same courses. Adam Martin finished 31st, just outside the points, and a new personal best World Cup result for him. Ben Lustgarten also started, but was a DNF as a result of vertigo he experienced during the race.On Tuesday, the World Cup moved to Drammen for classic city sprints. Ida Sargent was close to making the heats, finishing the qualifier in 34th place, about 2.5 seconds from the top 30. Kailtynn Miller finished 55th in the qualifier.Results from the Holmenkollen are available here, and Drammen here. The World Cup moves to Falun, Sweden this weekend for an all freestyle weekend, featuring a sprint and 10/15k distance race. <img src="/assets/Uploads/benoslodailyskier.jpg" alt="benoslodailyskier" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2252/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>GRP Skiers Wrap Up World Championships, Race China City Sprint Tour</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2247/</link>
			<description>Athletes from the Green Racing Project were spread wide across the globe this past week, as they raced in both Austria and China. Three GRP skiers, Caitlin Patterson, Adam Martin, and Ben Lustgarten finished up World Championships in Seefeld, Austria. Meanwhile, Ida Sargent, Corey Stock, and Liz Guiney took on the three stage China City Sprint Tour in Beijing, China.World ChampionshipsThe races at World Champs in Austria continued on February 27 with a 15k classic individual start. Ben Lustgarten represented the GRP in that race, taking 45th in a time of 42:12. The Championships wrapped up with 30 and 50k freestyle events. In the 30k on March 3, Caitlin Patterson skied to a 34th place finish. The following day, Adam Martin finished 45th in the 50k. World Cup racing continues this weekend with the Holmenkollen 30 and 50k classic races in Oslo, Norway on March 9 and 10. Results from Seefeld are available on FIS-ski.com.China City Sprint TourRacing in China started with a freestyle city sprint in downtown Beijing by the Bird&#039;s Nest stadium on March 1. In the qualifier, Ida Sargent led the way with a 16th. Liz Guiney qualified in 29th and Corey Stock in 35th. Sargent and Guiney were both knocked out in their quarterfinals and finished 18th and 29th, respectively. The following day, racing moved to an industrial district of Beijing, Shougang for another freestyle sprint. In the qualifier, Sargent took 9th, Guiney was 26th, and Stock was 27th. Sargent moved all the way to the A Final where she finished 2nd to Sweden&#039;s Linn Soemskar. Stock finished 3rd in her quarterfinal, for 16th on the day, and Guiney was 29th. The final day of racing was outside of Beijing in YanQing, and brought another freestyle city sprint. Sargent qualified in 16th, followed by Guiney in 30th, and Stock in 33rd. After taking second in her quarterfinal and advancing, Sargent placed 6th in her semifinal and 12th on the day. Her final ranking in the City Sprint Tour was 9th. Guiney finished 30th in the heats. Results from the three city sprints are also available on FIS-ski.com.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 10:59:56 -0500</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[Athletes from the Green Racing Project were spread wide across the globe this past week, as they raced in both Austria and China. Three GRP skiers, Caitlin Patterson, Adam Martin, and Ben Lustgarten finished up World Championships in Seefeld, Austria. Meanwhile, Ida Sargent, Corey Stock, and Liz Guiney took on the three stage China City Sprint Tour in Beijing, China.World ChampionshipsThe races at World Champs in Austria continued on February 27 with a 15k classic individual start. Ben Lustgarten represented the GRP in that race, taking 45th in a time of 42:12. The Championships wrapped up with 30 and 50k freestyle events. In the 30k on March 3, Caitlin Patterson skied to a 34th place finish. The following day, Adam Martin finished 45th in the 50k. World Cup racing continues this weekend with the Holmenkollen 30 and 50k classic races in Oslo, Norway on March 9 and 10. Results from Seefeld are available on FIS-ski.com.China City Sprint TourRacing in China started with a freestyle city sprint in downtown Beijing by the Bird&#039;s Nest stadium on March 1. In the qualifier, Ida Sargent led the way with a 16th. Liz Guiney qualified in 29th and Corey Stock in 35th. Sargent and Guiney were both knocked out in their quarterfinals and finished 18th and 29th, respectively. The following day, racing moved to an industrial district of Beijing, Shougang for another freestyle sprint. In the qualifier, Sargent took 9th, Guiney was 26th, and Stock was 27th. Sargent moved all the way to the A Final where she finished 2nd to Sweden&#039;s Linn Soemskar. Stock finished 3rd in her quarterfinal, for 16th on the day, and Guiney was 29th. The final day of racing was outside of Beijing in YanQing, and brought another freestyle city sprint. Sargent qualified in 16th, followed by Guiney in 30th, and Stock in 33rd. After taking second in her quarterfinal and advancing, Sargent placed 6th in her semifinal and 12th on the day. Her final ranking in the City Sprint Tour was 9th. Guiney finished 30th in the heats. Results from the three city sprints are also available on FIS-ski.com. <img src="/assets/Uploads/51712146-2271067556483903-8686695034038255616-n.jpg" alt="51712146 2271067556483903 8686695034038255616 n" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2247/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>GRP Biathletes Compete in Otepaeae IBU Cup</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2244/</link>
			<description>This past weekend GRP athletes Kelsey Dickinson, Hallie Grossman, Raleigh Goessling, and Johanna Talihaerm (summer training partner) raced the IBU Cup in Johanna’s home country of Estonia. The races took place in Otepaeae and the first event was a Super Sprint. In the qualifying round Johanna placed 7th with one prone miss. Kelsey also had a strong qualifier placing 9th with no misses. Hallie finished 58th. For the men, Raleigh placed 81st in the qualifying round. In the final, Johanna moved up to 4th while Kelsey was lapped placing 29th.In the next day’s sprint, Kelsey had a solid race finishing 38th with one standing miss. She was followed by Johanna in 50th and Hallie in 55th. On the men’s side, Raleigh placed 69th.Next up is World Champs which start March 7th. GRP biathletes Clare Egan, Emily Dreissigacker, Jake Brown, Susan Dunklee, and Alex Howe will be representing the US at this Championship event in Oestersund, Sweden so stay tuned!For more information and full results visit biathlonworld.com. </description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 06:59:53 -0500</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[This past weekend GRP athletes Kelsey Dickinson, Hallie Grossman, Raleigh Goessling, and Johanna Talihaerm (summer training partner) raced the IBU Cup in Johanna’s home country of Estonia. The races took place in Otepaeae and the first event was a Super Sprint. In the qualifying round Johanna placed 7th with one prone miss. Kelsey also had a strong qualifier placing 9th with no misses. Hallie finished 58th. For the men, Raleigh placed 81st in the qualifying round. In the final, Johanna moved up to 4th while Kelsey was lapped placing 29th.In the next day’s sprint, Kelsey had a solid race finishing 38th with one standing miss. She was followed by Johanna in 50th and Hallie in 55th. On the men’s side, Raleigh placed 69th.Next up is World Champs which start March 7th. GRP biathletes Clare Egan, Emily Dreissigacker, Jake Brown, Susan Dunklee, and Alex Howe will be representing the US at this Championship event in Oestersund, Sweden so stay tuned!For more information and full results visit biathlonworld.com.  <img src="/assets/Uploads/3.4.19biathlonnewsphoto1.png" alt="3.4.19biathlonnewsphoto1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2244/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>GRP Biathletes Race at Open Euro Champs</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2239/</link>
			<description>This past weekend some of the GRP biathletes competed at Open European Championships in Minsk-Raubichi, Belarus. The championship event kicked off with an individual race. Emily Dreissigacker had the top US result placing 43rd. She was followed by Kelsey Dickinson in 63rd and Hallie Grossman in 68th. On the men’s side, Raleigh Goessling finished 85th. Next up was relay day. In the single mixed relay, Hallie was joined by USBA teammate Travis Cooper. Both team members raced one leg before being lapped. The team placed 22nd. In the mixed relay, Alex Howe and Emily were joined by USBA teammates Deedra Irwin and Max Durtschi. Emily was the second leg and she cleaned both shooting stages using only 2 spares. The team was lapped placing 15th with a total of 2 penalties and 14 spares.In the sprint race, Alex placed 48th with two prone misses. Raleigh finished 83rd with 3 prone misses. For the women, Emily had a strong race finishing 10th with one standing miss. Hallie placed 54th with three standing misses and Kelsey finished 60th also with three misses. In the pursuit race, Alex moved up ten placed to finish 38th with only two misses. Emily moved up as well finishing 9th also with two misses. Hallie placed 51st and Kelsey was lapped.Racing action continues March 1st with IBU Cup 7 in Otepaeae, Estonia. Also stayed tuned for the start of World Champs on March 7th in Oestersund, Sweden. For more information and results visit biathlonworld.com.   </description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 14:08:06 -0500</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[This past weekend some of the GRP biathletes competed at Open European Championships in Minsk-Raubichi, Belarus. The championship event kicked off with an individual race. Emily Dreissigacker had the top US result placing 43rd. She was followed by Kelsey Dickinson in 63rd and Hallie Grossman in 68th. On the men’s side, Raleigh Goessling finished 85th. Next up was relay day. In the single mixed relay, Hallie was joined by USBA teammate Travis Cooper. Both team members raced one leg before being lapped. The team placed 22nd. In the mixed relay, Alex Howe and Emily were joined by USBA teammates Deedra Irwin and Max Durtschi. Emily was the second leg and she cleaned both shooting stages using only 2 spares. The team was lapped placing 15th with a total of 2 penalties and 14 spares.In the sprint race, Alex placed 48th with two prone misses. Raleigh finished 83rd with 3 prone misses. For the women, Emily had a strong race finishing 10th with one standing miss. Hallie placed 54th with three standing misses and Kelsey finished 60th also with three misses. In the pursuit race, Alex moved up ten placed to finish 38th with only two misses. Emily moved up as well finishing 9th also with two misses. Hallie placed 51st and Kelsey was lapped.Racing action continues March 1st with IBU Cup 7 in Otepaeae, Estonia. Also stayed tuned for the start of World Champs on March 7th in Oestersund, Sweden. For more information and results visit biathlonworld.com.    <img src="/assets/Uploads/2.25.19biathlonnewsphoto2.png" alt="2.25.19biathlonnewsphoto2" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2239/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>GRP&#039;s Akeo Maifeld-Carucci Wins American Birkebeiner; Martin and Patterson at World Championships</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2238/</link>
			<description>It was a big weekend for the Green Racing Project skiers, as Akeo Maifeld-Carucci won his first American Birkebeiner (know colloquially as the Birkie). It also marked the first time that a Green Racing Project athlete has won the Birkie, a 52k freestyle marathon through the woods of Northern Wisconsin. The race has the largest field in North America, and certainly the most prestigious marathon on the continent every year. Meanwhile, on the other side of the world Caitlin Patterson and Adam Martin made their World Championship debuts in Seefeld, Austria.American BirkieThis year, skiers faced slow conditions and new snow on the 52k trek from Cable to Hayward, Wisconsin. Maifeld-Carucci was skiing in the main pack of approximately 10 skiers until the &quot;halfway&quot; point at OO, with 28k remaining. At that point, Brian Gregg made a breakaway, and Maifeld-Carucci and Matt Liebsch chased him down. From that point, it was a pack of three skiers until the finish line. With the finishing line in sight, Maifeld-Carucci made his sprint for the line and took the win by 0.9 seconds over Gregg in second and Liebsch in third. As the overall winner and first American finisher, Maifeld-Carucci wins $10,000 as well as a mattress from Slumberland Furniture, one of the main event sponsors. Full results from the Birkie are here. Also look for GRP alums Bryan Cook, Hannah Dreissigacker, and Nils Koons, as well as rowing camp director Troy Howell.World ChampionshipsIn Seefeld, Austria, the nordic World Championships kicked off on February 21st with a freestyle sprint. GRP skiers competed in their first race on Saturday, in the 15k and 30k mass start skiathlon. In a skiathlon, skiers start with classic, then halfway through the race switch over to skate skis. Caitlin Patterson, on the heels of a cold, took 34th in the women&#039;s 15k skiathlon. Patterson was a 2018 Olympian in Pyeongchang, but this race marked her World Championships debut. On the men&#039;s side, Adam Martin, competing in his first World Championships race, finished 54th in the 30k skiathlon. Full results from Seefeld are available here. Ben Lustgarten is expected to race for the US in the 15k classic individual start on February 27th. The viewing schedule for the remaining events at World Championships is below: February 27: 15km classic, men, 8:00amFebruary 28: 4x5km relay, women, 7:00amMarch 1: 4x10km relay, men, 7:15amMarch 2: 30km skate mass start, women, 6:15amMarch 3: 50km skate mass start, men, 7:00am</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 11:04:55 -0500</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[It was a big weekend for the Green Racing Project skiers, as Akeo Maifeld-Carucci won his first American Birkebeiner (know colloquially as the Birkie). It also marked the first time that a Green Racing Project athlete has won the Birkie, a 52k freestyle marathon through the woods of Northern Wisconsin. The race has the largest field in North America, and certainly the most prestigious marathon on the continent every year. Meanwhile, on the other side of the world Caitlin Patterson and Adam Martin made their World Championship debuts in Seefeld, Austria.American BirkieThis year, skiers faced slow conditions and new snow on the 52k trek from Cable to Hayward, Wisconsin. Maifeld-Carucci was skiing in the main pack of approximately 10 skiers until the &quot;halfway&quot; point at OO, with 28k remaining. At that point, Brian Gregg made a breakaway, and Maifeld-Carucci and Matt Liebsch chased him down. From that point, it was a pack of three skiers until the finish line. With the finishing line in sight, Maifeld-Carucci made his sprint for the line and took the win by 0.9 seconds over Gregg in second and Liebsch in third. As the overall winner and first American finisher, Maifeld-Carucci wins $10,000 as well as a mattress from Slumberland Furniture, one of the main event sponsors. Full results from the Birkie are here. Also look for GRP alums Bryan Cook, Hannah Dreissigacker, and Nils Koons, as well as rowing camp director Troy Howell.World ChampionshipsIn Seefeld, Austria, the nordic World Championships kicked off on February 21st with a freestyle sprint. GRP skiers competed in their first race on Saturday, in the 15k and 30k mass start skiathlon. In a skiathlon, skiers start with classic, then halfway through the race switch over to skate skis. Caitlin Patterson, on the heels of a cold, took 34th in the women&#039;s 15k skiathlon. Patterson was a 2018 Olympian in Pyeongchang, but this race marked her World Championships debut. On the men&#039;s side, Adam Martin, competing in his first World Championships race, finished 54th in the 30k skiathlon. Full results from Seefeld are available here. Ben Lustgarten is expected to race for the US in the 15k classic individual start on February 27th. The viewing schedule for the remaining events at World Championships is below: February 27: 15km classic, men, 8:00amFebruary 28: 4x5km relay, women, 7:00amMarch 1: 4x10km relay, men, 7:15amMarch 2: 30km skate mass start, women, 6:15amMarch 3: 50km skate mass start, men, 7:00am <img src="/assets/Uploads/cABSF-Sally-Krueger-HR-2669-e1550964062957.jpg" alt="cABSF Sally Krueger HR 2669 e1550964062957" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2238/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>GRP Skiers Race Cogne World Cup and Minneapolis SuperTour</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2233/</link>
			<description>Green Racing Project skiers had good results both abroad and in the States this weekend. Three GRP skiers raced in the World Cup in Cogne, Italy, the final World Cup weekend before World Championships. Five more athletes were in Minneapolis, MN for SuperTour races at Theodore Wirth Park.Cogne World CupThe weekend kicked off Saturday with a freestyle sprint. Ida Sargent showed her consistency in sprint qualification on the World Cup, once more making the rounds in 28th place. She raced in the first quarterfinal heat and placed 5th, moving up to 24th place on the day. The following day brought 10/15k individual start classic races. Caitlin Patterson had the top GRP result, taking 36th in the women&#039;s 10k. Sargent placed 49th. In the men&#039;s 15k, Adam Martin took 49th.Results from the Cogne World Cup are available on FIS-ski.com. The World Championships kick off with a freestyle sprint on February 21st. GRP skiers Patterson, Sargent, Martin, and Ben Lustgarten are all on the US squad racing at World Championships, so stay tuned for results!Minneapolis SuperTourMeanwhile, the domestic skiers took on a three race SuperTour at Theodore Wirth, the site of next year&#039;s North American World Cup stop. The first race brought freestyle sprints. In women&#039;s qualification, Kaitlynn Miller led the way with a 4th place, followed by Liz Guiney in 5th, and Corey Stock in 16th. In men&#039;s qualification, Akeo Maifeld-Carucci placed 8th and Ben Lustgarten took 13th. The women raced 4 heats, with 4 women each. Guiney advanced through the quarterfinal and semifinal, and finished 4th in the A Final. Miller was second in her quarterfinal and 3rd in her semifinal, taking 6th overall. Stock finished 4th in her quarterfinal, for 16th overall. On the men&#039;s side, Maifeld-Carucci advanced all the way to the A Final as well, where he placed 5th after an unfortunate detour around a parked groomer in the trail! Lustgarten placed 3rd in his semifinal, and 6th overall. The following day brought mass start classic races. The men went first, racing 20k. Lustgarten broke away with one other athlete, and ultimately finished 2nd. Maifeld-Carucci took 10th in a sprint to the line. In the women&#039;s 15k, Miller broke the field and skied to a solo victory. Guiney was close behind in 3rd, and Stock finished 7th. The final day of competition brought 5/10k individual start freestyle races. In the women&#039;s 5k, Miller took 5th place and Guiney finished 9th. On the men&#039;s side, Maifeld-Carucci placed 3rd, and Lustgarten was close behind in 5th. Results from the weekend are available on Superior Timing. The SuperTour continues next weekend with the American Birkebeiner in Hayward, Wisconsin.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 19:56:41 -0500</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[Green Racing Project skiers had good results both abroad and in the States this weekend. Three GRP skiers raced in the World Cup in Cogne, Italy, the final World Cup weekend before World Championships. Five more athletes were in Minneapolis, MN for SuperTour races at Theodore Wirth Park.Cogne World CupThe weekend kicked off Saturday with a freestyle sprint. Ida Sargent showed her consistency in sprint qualification on the World Cup, once more making the rounds in 28th place. She raced in the first quarterfinal heat and placed 5th, moving up to 24th place on the day. The following day brought 10/15k individual start classic races. Caitlin Patterson had the top GRP result, taking 36th in the women&#039;s 10k. Sargent placed 49th. In the men&#039;s 15k, Adam Martin took 49th.Results from the Cogne World Cup are available on FIS-ski.com. The World Championships kick off with a freestyle sprint on February 21st. GRP skiers Patterson, Sargent, Martin, and Ben Lustgarten are all on the US squad racing at World Championships, so stay tuned for results!Minneapolis SuperTourMeanwhile, the domestic skiers took on a three race SuperTour at Theodore Wirth, the site of next year&#039;s North American World Cup stop. The first race brought freestyle sprints. In women&#039;s qualification, Kaitlynn Miller led the way with a 4th place, followed by Liz Guiney in 5th, and Corey Stock in 16th. In men&#039;s qualification, Akeo Maifeld-Carucci placed 8th and Ben Lustgarten took 13th. The women raced 4 heats, with 4 women each. Guiney advanced through the quarterfinal and semifinal, and finished 4th in the A Final. Miller was second in her quarterfinal and 3rd in her semifinal, taking 6th overall. Stock finished 4th in her quarterfinal, for 16th overall. On the men&#039;s side, Maifeld-Carucci advanced all the way to the A Final as well, where he placed 5th after an unfortunate detour around a parked groomer in the trail! Lustgarten placed 3rd in his semifinal, and 6th overall. The following day brought mass start classic races. The men went first, racing 20k. Lustgarten broke away with one other athlete, and ultimately finished 2nd. Maifeld-Carucci took 10th in a sprint to the line. In the women&#039;s 15k, Miller broke the field and skied to a solo victory. Guiney was close behind in 3rd, and Stock finished 7th. The final day of competition brought 5/10k individual start freestyle races. In the women&#039;s 5k, Miller took 5th place and Guiney finished 9th. On the men&#039;s side, Maifeld-Carucci placed 3rd, and Lustgarten was close behind in 5th. Results from the weekend are available on Superior Timing. The SuperTour continues next weekend with the American Birkebeiner in Hayward, Wisconsin. <img src="/assets/Uploads/52555135-10157175116397272-4441652089994608640-n.jpg" alt="52555135 10157175116397272 4441652089994608640 n" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2233/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>GRP Biathletes Compete at Soldier Hollow World Cup</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2231/</link>
			<description>This past weekend five GRP biathletes competed on home snow at the World Cup in Soldier Hollow, Utah. The American World Cup weekend kicked off with a sprint in which Clare Egan placed 21st with one standing miss. Susan Dunklee finished 45th with three misses, and both women qualified for the pursuit. On the men’s side, Alex Howe finished 81st and Jake Brown placed 85th. In the pursuit, Susan cleaned her first three stages and had one miss in her final stage to move up to 26th. Clare was close behind in 27th with three misses.Next up was relay day. In the single mixed relay, Susan was joined by USBA teammate Sean Doherty. Susan cleaned two of her four shooting stages using no spares. The team placed 14th with a total of 2 penalties and 13 spares. In the mixed relay, Alex, Clare, and Jake were joined by USBA teammate Joanne Reid. Alex cleaned using only one spare, Clare cleaned using no spares, and Jake cleaned using three spares. The team finished 10th with no penalties and 5 spares.Racing action continues tomorrow at Open European Championships in Minsk, Belarus, and World Championships start March 7th in Oestersund, Sweden. Stay tuned!For more information and full results visit biathlonworld.com.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 09:11:58 -0500</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[This past weekend five GRP biathletes competed on home snow at the World Cup in Soldier Hollow, Utah. The American World Cup weekend kicked off with a sprint in which Clare Egan placed 21st with one standing miss. Susan Dunklee finished 45th with three misses, and both women qualified for the pursuit. On the men’s side, Alex Howe finished 81st and Jake Brown placed 85th. In the pursuit, Susan cleaned her first three stages and had one miss in her final stage to move up to 26th. Clare was close behind in 27th with three misses.Next up was relay day. In the single mixed relay, Susan was joined by USBA teammate Sean Doherty. Susan cleaned two of her four shooting stages using no spares. The team placed 14th with a total of 2 penalties and 13 spares. In the mixed relay, Alex, Clare, and Jake were joined by USBA teammate Joanne Reid. Alex cleaned using only one spare, Clare cleaned using no spares, and Jake cleaned using three spares. The team finished 10th with no penalties and 5 spares.Racing action continues tomorrow at Open European Championships in Minsk, Belarus, and World Championships start March 7th in Oestersund, Sweden. Stay tuned!For more information and full results visit biathlonworld.com. <img src="/assets/Uploads/2.19.19biathlonnewsphoto1.jpg" alt="2.19.19biathlonnewsphoto1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2231/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Green Racing Project Rowers at C.R.A.S.H-B. Sprints</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2230/</link>
			<description>When as much of your year is spent with ice covering your body of water as our Green Racing Project athletes, you obviously spend plenty of time on the ergometer over the course of the year. The men on our GRP Rowing side of the team headed down to Boston this past weekend to join in on the pinnacle of erging, the C.R.A.S.H.-B. Sprints 2,000m race with almost a thousand other participants of all ages and categories. This was the first year in a new venue, the Boston University Indoor Track and Field arena with a full crowd of spectators reaching deafening volumes towards the end of each round of 2ks. C.R.A.S.H.-B. format, for anyone unfamiliar, is a one-and-done 2k for each age group and division. Each category sits down together and when the buzzer goes off, it’s a mad dash to the last meter on each person’s monitor. A “live-stream” of each race is up on a couple jumbotrons behind the ergs for the spectators to see the relative position of each boat as they proceed through each virtual meter. They also have some fantastic announcers that give insight into each race for the crowd to really get invested in the results. The paramedics have to work overtime at this event as well with countless people reaching the point of vomiting or passing out by the end of their 2k throughout the day. It’s quite the spectacle considering it’s just a bunch of people erging.Our men all sat down at 2:15pm for the Open Men’s category with Wes Vear, Lucas Bellows, Andy Raitto, and Kevin Meador, the newest member of the GRP Rowing team, all representing the Cedar Leaf. Bellows led the race for the first hundred meters and then was overtaken by Connor Corwen of Bucknell Crew Association for a few hundred meters. Then Vear took the lead and held onto it until the end, finishing with a 5:59.2 over Corwen’s 5:59.7. Meador finished third with a 6:02.0 and then Raitto took fifth with a 6:05.9. Bellows rounded out the GRP with a 6:09.9.You can find full results here.It was some great racing from the men and now they head south for their weeklong training trip to Peachtree City, Georgia to start to get the feel back for the water. Keep up with their training via the GRP blog over the next week!</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 15:16:57 -0500</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[When as much of your year is spent with ice covering your body of water as our Green Racing Project athletes, you obviously spend plenty of time on the ergometer over the course of the year. The men on our GRP Rowing side of the team headed down to Boston this past weekend to join in on the pinnacle of erging, the C.R.A.S.H.-B. Sprints 2,000m race with almost a thousand other participants of all ages and categories. This was the first year in a new venue, the Boston University Indoor Track and Field arena with a full crowd of spectators reaching deafening volumes towards the end of each round of 2ks. C.R.A.S.H.-B. format, for anyone unfamiliar, is a one-and-done 2k for each age group and division. Each category sits down together and when the buzzer goes off, it’s a mad dash to the last meter on each person’s monitor. A “live-stream” of each race is up on a couple jumbotrons behind the ergs for the spectators to see the relative position of each boat as they proceed through each virtual meter. They also have some fantastic announcers that give insight into each race for the crowd to really get invested in the results. The paramedics have to work overtime at this event as well with countless people reaching the point of vomiting or passing out by the end of their 2k throughout the day. It’s quite the spectacle considering it’s just a bunch of people erging.Our men all sat down at 2:15pm for the Open Men’s category with Wes Vear, Lucas Bellows, Andy Raitto, and Kevin Meador, the newest member of the GRP Rowing team, all representing the Cedar Leaf. Bellows led the race for the first hundred meters and then was overtaken by Connor Corwen of Bucknell Crew Association for a few hundred meters. Then Vear took the lead and held onto it until the end, finishing with a 5:59.2 over Corwen’s 5:59.7. Meador finished third with a 6:02.0 and then Raitto took fifth with a 6:05.9. Bellows rounded out the GRP with a 6:09.9.You can find full results here.It was some great racing from the men and now they head south for their weeklong training trip to Peachtree City, Georgia to start to get the feel back for the water. Keep up with their training via the GRP blog over the next week! <img src="/assets/bulkUpload/20190217-150556-e1550791009412-814x1024.jpg" alt="20190217 150556 e1550791009412 814x1024" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2230/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Sargent Races Double Sprint Weekend in Lahti, Finland</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2223/</link>
			<description>After a short break from World Cup racing, Ida Sargent was back in action for a double sprint weekend in Lahti, Finland. Lahti recently played host to World Junior and U23 World Championships, and the course is known for the long downhill stretch into the stadium, which tends to bring the field together for close sprint finishes.On Saturday, racers took on an individual freestyle sprint. Sargent qualified in 26th, one of three American skiers to make the heats. She was in the first quarterfinal heat along with teammate Sophie Caldwell. After a mass sprint to the line, the entire heat finished within 0.6 seconds. Sargent took 6th, and 30th overall on the day. Sargent&#039;s USA teammate Caldwell was able to advance to the A Final, where she finished 2nd.The following day, Sargent teamed up with Caldwell for a classic team sprint. They raced in the first semifinal of the day, finishing 6th, +10.78 seconds. However, only the top two from each semifinal qualify automatically for the final, along with the next six fastest times. Sargent and Caldwell missed out on a lucky loser spot as the second semifinal had faster times, and finished the day in 12th overall.World Cup action continues next weekend in Cogne, Italy with a freestyle sprint and 10/15k classic. GRP teammates Adam Martin and Caitlin Patterson will join Sargent for the Cogne World Cup weekend, the final one before World Championships. Results from Lahti are available on FIS-ski.com.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 09:26:33 -0500</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[After a short break from World Cup racing, Ida Sargent was back in action for a double sprint weekend in Lahti, Finland. Lahti recently played host to World Junior and U23 World Championships, and the course is known for the long downhill stretch into the stadium, which tends to bring the field together for close sprint finishes.On Saturday, racers took on an individual freestyle sprint. Sargent qualified in 26th, one of three American skiers to make the heats. She was in the first quarterfinal heat along with teammate Sophie Caldwell. After a mass sprint to the line, the entire heat finished within 0.6 seconds. Sargent took 6th, and 30th overall on the day. Sargent&#039;s USA teammate Caldwell was able to advance to the A Final, where she finished 2nd.The following day, Sargent teamed up with Caldwell for a classic team sprint. They raced in the first semifinal of the day, finishing 6th, +10.78 seconds. However, only the top two from each semifinal qualify automatically for the final, along with the next six fastest times. Sargent and Caldwell missed out on a lucky loser spot as the second semifinal had faster times, and finished the day in 12th overall.World Cup action continues next weekend in Cogne, Italy with a freestyle sprint and 10/15k classic. GRP teammates Adam Martin and Caitlin Patterson will join Sargent for the Cogne World Cup weekend, the final one before World Championships. Results from Lahti are available on FIS-ski.com. <img src="/assets/Uploads/Ida-Davos-Heats-Reese-Brown2.jpg" alt="Ida Davos Heats Reese Brown2" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2223/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>GRP Biathletes Race Through Frigid Temps in Canmore World Cup</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2222/</link>
			<description>This past weekend Clare Egan, Emily Dreissigacker, and Susan Dunklee made the trek back across the pond to compete in the Canmore World Cup. Jake Brown was also slated to race but sat out due to illness. They were greeted with freezing temperatures that stayed barely race legal for the first two events, but dipped below prior to the final sprint which had to be cancelled. In the short individual race, Clare had the top GRP performance of the day placing 43rd with 4 misses. She was closely followed by Estonian National Team member and GRP summer training partner, Johanna Talihaerm, in 44th with three misses. Emily placed 66th with only two misses in her final standing stage. In the following day’s relay, Susan, Clare, and Emily were joined by USBA teammate Joanne Reid. The team placed 8th with 2 penalties and 12 spares for their best finish since the Olympic relay in 2014. Susan scrambled for the team and cleaned her first stage with no spares. She tagged off to Clare. Emily anchored the team with strong shooting only using one standing spare. World Cup racing action continues in North American next weekend in Soldier Hollow. Keep your eyes peeled for a strong GRP contingency with Clare, Emily, Susan, Jake, and Alex Howe all slated to start.For more information and full results visit biathlonworld.com. </description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 09:07:31 -0500</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[This past weekend Clare Egan, Emily Dreissigacker, and Susan Dunklee made the trek back across the pond to compete in the Canmore World Cup. Jake Brown was also slated to race but sat out due to illness. They were greeted with freezing temperatures that stayed barely race legal for the first two events, but dipped below prior to the final sprint which had to be cancelled. In the short individual race, Clare had the top GRP performance of the day placing 43rd with 4 misses. She was closely followed by Estonian National Team member and GRP summer training partner, Johanna Talihaerm, in 44th with three misses. Emily placed 66th with only two misses in her final standing stage. In the following day’s relay, Susan, Clare, and Emily were joined by USBA teammate Joanne Reid. The team placed 8th with 2 penalties and 12 spares for their best finish since the Olympic relay in 2014. Susan scrambled for the team and cleaned her first stage with no spares. She tagged off to Clare. Emily anchored the team with strong shooting only using one standing spare. World Cup racing action continues in North American next weekend in Soldier Hollow. Keep your eyes peeled for a strong GRP contingency with Clare, Emily, Susan, Jake, and Alex Howe all slated to start.For more information and full results visit biathlonworld.com.  <img src="/assets/Uploads/2.11.19biathlonnewsphoto1.jpg" alt="2.11.19biathlonnewsphoto1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2222/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>GRP Athletes Podium at Biathlon NorAm in Jericho</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2214/</link>
			<description>This past weekend Kelsey Dickinson, Hallie Grossman, and Akeo Maifeld-Carucci raced the Biathlon NorAm in Jericho. Kelsey raced all three events while Hallie and Akeo each chose to compete in two. Technically the first sprint race on Thursday was a time trial (not a NorAm) used to help determine the US Open European Championships team. In the sprint time trial, Kelsey won the women’s race with two standing misses. For the men, Akeo placed third. The following evening the NorAm officially began with a sprint event which Hallie won with three misses. Kelsey joined her on the podium in second also with three misses. With Akeo not racing, Ethan Dreissigacker stepped up to the plate to represent the Craftsbury men placing 5th with three misses. After a day off, racing action wrapped up with a pursuit event. This time Kelsey took top honors with four misses while Hallie finished second with five misses. On the men&#039;s side, Akeo had a strong race placing second.Hallie, Kelsey, Emily Dreissigacker, Alex Howe, and Raleigh Goessling are all pre-qualified for the Open Euro Champs Team and will be competing in Minsk-Raubichi, Belarus at the end of February so stay tuned!Results:Thursday Sprint | Friday Sprint | Sunday Pursuit </description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 16:27:39 -0500</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[This past weekend Kelsey Dickinson, Hallie Grossman, and Akeo Maifeld-Carucci raced the Biathlon NorAm in Jericho. Kelsey raced all three events while Hallie and Akeo each chose to compete in two. Technically the first sprint race on Thursday was a time trial (not a NorAm) used to help determine the US Open European Championships team. In the sprint time trial, Kelsey won the women’s race with two standing misses. For the men, Akeo placed third. The following evening the NorAm officially began with a sprint event which Hallie won with three misses. Kelsey joined her on the podium in second also with three misses. With Akeo not racing, Ethan Dreissigacker stepped up to the plate to represent the Craftsbury men placing 5th with three misses. After a day off, racing action wrapped up with a pursuit event. This time Kelsey took top honors with four misses while Hallie finished second with five misses. On the men&#039;s side, Akeo had a strong race placing second.Hallie, Kelsey, Emily Dreissigacker, Alex Howe, and Raleigh Goessling are all pre-qualified for the Open Euro Champs Team and will be competing in Minsk-Raubichi, Belarus at the end of February so stay tuned!Results:Thursday Sprint | Friday Sprint | Sunday Pursuit  <img src="/assets/Uploads/2.4.19biathlonphoto2.jpg" alt="2.4.19biathlonphoto2" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2214/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Sargent 10th at Norwegian Nationals; GRP Skiers Win Craftsbury Marathon</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2213/</link>
			<description>It may have been an off weekend for both the cross country World Cup and the domestic SuperTour circuit, but Green Racing Project skiers still found themselves a few start lines this weekend. Ida Sargent was in Meraaker, Norway, competing in Norwegian National Championships, which usually occur mid-season. Back at home, three GRP skiers raced in the 33k freestyle race at the Craftsbury Marathon.Norwegian National ChampionshipsSargent toed the line for a freestyle sprint on Thursday, February 1 in Meraaker, Norway. In the qualifier, she placed 11th. She advanced to the semifinal round, where she placed 5th, and moved up to 10th overall on the day. The field at Norwegian Nationals included almost their entire World Cup team. Maiken Caspersen Falla won the qualifier, and Lotta Weng was victorious in the heats. Sargent returns to World Cup action on February 9th in Lahti, Finland. Results from Norwegian Nationals are available on FIS-ski.com.Craftsbury MarathonIn Craftsbury, several GRP skiers had the opportunity to join in on the marathon madness! While no GRP skiers participated in Saturday&#039;s classic marathon, GRP wax tech Nick Brown did race the 33k classic and placed 6th, and first in his age group. The following day, Adam Martin won the 33k freestyle marathon for men in a time of 1:30.30. Another GRP wax tech, former GRP skier, and organizer of the marathon, Ollie Burruss, placed 2nd, and Nick Brown, in his second 33k of the weekend, took 14th. On the women&#039;s side, Kaitlynn Miller took the victory with a time of 1:48.15.5, with Liz Guiney 0.3 seconds back in 2nd. The GRP skiers will be back in action on February 15-17 at the SuperTour in Minneapolis. Marathon results are available on Bullitt Timing.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 15:16:49 -0500</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[It may have been an off weekend for both the cross country World Cup and the domestic SuperTour circuit, but Green Racing Project skiers still found themselves a few start lines this weekend. Ida Sargent was in Meraaker, Norway, competing in Norwegian National Championships, which usually occur mid-season. Back at home, three GRP skiers raced in the 33k freestyle race at the Craftsbury Marathon.Norwegian National ChampionshipsSargent toed the line for a freestyle sprint on Thursday, February 1 in Meraaker, Norway. In the qualifier, she placed 11th. She advanced to the semifinal round, where she placed 5th, and moved up to 10th overall on the day. The field at Norwegian Nationals included almost their entire World Cup team. Maiken Caspersen Falla won the qualifier, and Lotta Weng was victorious in the heats. Sargent returns to World Cup action on February 9th in Lahti, Finland. Results from Norwegian Nationals are available on FIS-ski.com.Craftsbury MarathonIn Craftsbury, several GRP skiers had the opportunity to join in on the marathon madness! While no GRP skiers participated in Saturday&#039;s classic marathon, GRP wax tech Nick Brown did race the 33k classic and placed 6th, and first in his age group. The following day, Adam Martin won the 33k freestyle marathon for men in a time of 1:30.30. Another GRP wax tech, former GRP skier, and organizer of the marathon, Ollie Burruss, placed 2nd, and Nick Brown, in his second 33k of the weekend, took 14th. On the women&#039;s side, Kaitlynn Miller took the victory with a time of 1:48.15.5, with Liz Guiney 0.3 seconds back in 2nd. The GRP skiers will be back in action on February 15-17 at the SuperTour in Minneapolis. Marathon results are available on Bullitt Timing. <img src="/assets/Uploads/adamcburymarathonjlaz.jpg" alt="adamcburymarathonjlaz" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2213/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>GRP Skiers Podium at Lake Placid SuperTour; Race Ulricehamn World Cup</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2207/</link>
			<description>Skiers from the Green Racing Project had a number of standout results, both in the States, where some members raced the Lake Placid SuperTour/Eastern Cup, as well as abroad, at the World Cup stop in Ulricehamn, Sweden.Lake Placid SuperTourThe weekend&#039;s SuperTour stop in Lake Placid, New York, featured just about every type of weather possible. After an inch of rain on Thursday, it proceeded to snow every day of the competition. Friday opened with interval start freestyle races, 5k for women and 10k for men. In the men&#039;s race, Akeo Maifeld-Carucci had a fantastic result, placing 2nd, his best SuperTour finish of the season so far. Adam Martin was not far behind in 4th place. On the women&#039;s side, Kaitlynn Miller took 6th, Liz Guiney was 12th, and Corey Stock finished 21st.The following day athletes raced a classic sprint. All five GRP athletes qualified for the heats, with Kaitlynn Miller leading the way in 4th, Liz Guiney in 10th, and Corey Stock in 18th. On the men&#039;s side, Akeo Maifeld-Carucci qualified in 19th, and Adam Martin in 21st. Miller and Guiney both advanced all the way through to the A Final, where they placed 4th and 6th, respectively. Corey Stock made it to the semifinals, finishing in the top 10 (heat brackets were not available as of publication). Maifeld-Carucci and Martin did not advance out of their quarterfinal heats.The weekend wrapped up with 10/15k classic mass starts in blizzard conditions. In the women&#039;s race, Miller broke away with a three women pack, and then sprinted away for the victory, her first SuperTour win of the season. Guiney was 6th in a sprint to the line, and Stock took 10th. On the men&#039;s side, Martin made the podium with a 2nd place finish, and Maifeld-Carucci took 6th. Results from the weekend are available on Bullitt Timing. The SuperTour resumes on February 15th in Minneapolis, MN, and in the meantime the GRP skiers will race the Craftsbury Marathon this weekend!Ulricehamn World CupMeanwhile, over in Sweden, two GRP athletes raced the World Cup in Ulricehamn, With upwards of 45,000 spectators, Ulricehamn is known for the one of the largest crowds of any World Cup stop. On Saturday, Caitlin Patterson raced to 23rd in the 10k freestyle interval start, her best World Cup result of the season so far. Ben Lustgarten finished 64th in the men&#039;s 15k freestyle. The following day, both Patterson and Lustgarten were part of the USA relay team. Patterson skied the third leg, a freestyle one, for the women&#039;s 4x5k relay. The team finished 6th, and Patterson had the 7th fastest time for her leg. Lustgarten was the freestyle anchor for the men&#039;s 4x7.5k relay. He had an exciting finish with the Sweden II team and Italy, and ultimately brought the team home in 13th. The World Cup takes a break this coming week, and the resumes in Lahti, Finland on February 9th. Results from Ulricehamn are available on FIS-ski.com. </description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 11:20:51 -0500</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[Skiers from the Green Racing Project had a number of standout results, both in the States, where some members raced the Lake Placid SuperTour/Eastern Cup, as well as abroad, at the World Cup stop in Ulricehamn, Sweden.Lake Placid SuperTourThe weekend&#039;s SuperTour stop in Lake Placid, New York, featured just about every type of weather possible. After an inch of rain on Thursday, it proceeded to snow every day of the competition. Friday opened with interval start freestyle races, 5k for women and 10k for men. In the men&#039;s race, Akeo Maifeld-Carucci had a fantastic result, placing 2nd, his best SuperTour finish of the season so far. Adam Martin was not far behind in 4th place. On the women&#039;s side, Kaitlynn Miller took 6th, Liz Guiney was 12th, and Corey Stock finished 21st.The following day athletes raced a classic sprint. All five GRP athletes qualified for the heats, with Kaitlynn Miller leading the way in 4th, Liz Guiney in 10th, and Corey Stock in 18th. On the men&#039;s side, Akeo Maifeld-Carucci qualified in 19th, and Adam Martin in 21st. Miller and Guiney both advanced all the way through to the A Final, where they placed 4th and 6th, respectively. Corey Stock made it to the semifinals, finishing in the top 10 (heat brackets were not available as of publication). Maifeld-Carucci and Martin did not advance out of their quarterfinal heats.The weekend wrapped up with 10/15k classic mass starts in blizzard conditions. In the women&#039;s race, Miller broke away with a three women pack, and then sprinted away for the victory, her first SuperTour win of the season. Guiney was 6th in a sprint to the line, and Stock took 10th. On the men&#039;s side, Martin made the podium with a 2nd place finish, and Maifeld-Carucci took 6th. Results from the weekend are available on Bullitt Timing. The SuperTour resumes on February 15th in Minneapolis, MN, and in the meantime the GRP skiers will race the Craftsbury Marathon this weekend!Ulricehamn World CupMeanwhile, over in Sweden, two GRP athletes raced the World Cup in Ulricehamn, With upwards of 45,000 spectators, Ulricehamn is known for the one of the largest crowds of any World Cup stop. On Saturday, Caitlin Patterson raced to 23rd in the 10k freestyle interval start, her best World Cup result of the season so far. Ben Lustgarten finished 64th in the men&#039;s 15k freestyle. The following day, both Patterson and Lustgarten were part of the USA relay team. Patterson skied the third leg, a freestyle one, for the women&#039;s 4x5k relay. The team finished 6th, and Patterson had the 7th fastest time for her leg. Lustgarten was the freestyle anchor for the men&#039;s 4x7.5k relay. He had an exciting finish with the Sweden II team and Italy, and ultimately brought the team home in 13th. The World Cup takes a break this coming week, and the resumes in Lahti, Finland on February 9th. Results from Ulricehamn are available on FIS-ski.com.  <img src="/assets/Uploads/akeolpnensa.jpg" alt="akeolpnensa" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2207/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>GRP Biathletes Post Standout Results on IBU and World Cup</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2205/</link>
			<description>This past weekend Clare Egan, Susan Dunklee, and Jake Brown raced the World Cup in Antholz, Italy while Emily Dreissigacker, Hallie Grossman, Raleigh Goessling, and Alex Howe competed on the IBU Cup in Lenzerheide, Switzerland. World CupThe sixth World Cup weekend kicked off with a sprint in which Clare placed 22nd with two standing misses and Susan finished 66th. For the men, Jake posted a new personal-best finish in 40th with one prone miss. In the pursuit race, Clare moved up to 11th cleaning her first three stages. Jake qualified for the pursuit but was lapped after his fourth shooting stage. Clare was the only GRP athlete to qualify for the mass start. She had a strong race placing 15th. She missed two shots in her first shooting stage and then cleaned the remaining three stages. IBU CupThe IBU Cup weekend also kicked off with a sprint. Emily posted the top GRP result placing 27th with one standing miss while Hallie finished 33rd with three prone misses. For the men, Alex had a solid race placing 38th with three misses. Raleigh finished 54th also with three misses. In the women’s pursuit race Emily had a strong race placing 18th with three misses. Hallie was close behind in 32nd with four misses. For the men, Alex placed 44th. Alex, Raleigh, Emily, and Hallie were all on an all-GRP mixed relay team together. They were lapped and placed 9th.  Next up are Open European Champs trials in Jericho, Vermont this coming weekend followed by two North American World Cups with races starting in Canmore, British Columbia on February 7th and in Salt Lake City, Utah on February 14th. For more information and results check out biathlonworld.com.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 20:27:09 -0500</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[This past weekend Clare Egan, Susan Dunklee, and Jake Brown raced the World Cup in Antholz, Italy while Emily Dreissigacker, Hallie Grossman, Raleigh Goessling, and Alex Howe competed on the IBU Cup in Lenzerheide, Switzerland. World CupThe sixth World Cup weekend kicked off with a sprint in which Clare placed 22nd with two standing misses and Susan finished 66th. For the men, Jake posted a new personal-best finish in 40th with one prone miss. In the pursuit race, Clare moved up to 11th cleaning her first three stages. Jake qualified for the pursuit but was lapped after his fourth shooting stage. Clare was the only GRP athlete to qualify for the mass start. She had a strong race placing 15th. She missed two shots in her first shooting stage and then cleaned the remaining three stages. IBU CupThe IBU Cup weekend also kicked off with a sprint. Emily posted the top GRP result placing 27th with one standing miss while Hallie finished 33rd with three prone misses. For the men, Alex had a solid race placing 38th with three misses. Raleigh finished 54th also with three misses. In the women’s pursuit race Emily had a strong race placing 18th with three misses. Hallie was close behind in 32nd with four misses. For the men, Alex placed 44th. Alex, Raleigh, Emily, and Hallie were all on an all-GRP mixed relay team together. They were lapped and placed 9th.  Next up are Open European Champs trials in Jericho, Vermont this coming weekend followed by two North American World Cups with races starting in Canmore, British Columbia on February 7th and in Salt Lake City, Utah on February 14th. For more information and results check out biathlonworld.com. <img src="/assets/Uploads/1.28.19biathlonphoto1.jpg" alt="1.28.19biathlonphoto1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2205/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Four Green Racing Project Athletes Named to World Championships Team</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2203/</link>
			<description>On Tuesday, the US Ski and Snowboard Team announced their team for the 2019 World Championships in Seefeld, Austria. Among the 18 athletes named to the team, four members of the Green Racing Project were named: Ben Lustgarten, Adam Martin, Caitlin Patterson, and Ida Sargent.For Martin and Patterson, it will be their first time representing the US at World Championships. Lustgarten previously represented the US at the 2017 World Championships in Lahti, Finland. For Sargent, this will be her 5th time attending World Championships, starting in 2011 in Oslo, Norway.The Championships kick off on Thursday, February 21 and conclude on Sunday, March 3. All results will be available on FIS-Ski.com, and live video will be on the Olympic channel. Congratulations to our Green Racing Project athletes for qualifying, and best of luck in the championships!Link to the article about team naming here.Full Schedule:All times ESTPreliminary schedule, subject to changeThursday, Feb. 216:00 a.m. - Men and women&#039;s sprint qualification 8:30 a.m. - Men and women&#039;s sprint finals Saturday, Feb. 237:30 a.m. - Women&#039;s 15k skiathlon8:30 a.m. - Men&#039;s 30k skiathlon Sunday, Feb. 248:30 a.m. - Men and women&#039;s team sprint qualification 10:30 a.m. - Men and women&#039;s team sprint finals Tuesday, Feb. 267:30 a.m. - Women&#039;s 10kWednesday, Feb. 278:00 a.m. - Men&#039;s 15kThursday, Feb. 287:00 a.m. - Women&#039;s 4x5k relay Friday, March 17:00 a.m. - Men&#039;s 4x10k relay Saturday, March 27:00 a.m. - Women&#039;s 30k Sunday, March 37:00 a.m. - Men&#039;s 50k</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 14:47:35 -0500</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[On Tuesday, the US Ski and Snowboard Team announced their team for the 2019 World Championships in Seefeld, Austria. Among the 18 athletes named to the team, four members of the Green Racing Project were named: Ben Lustgarten, Adam Martin, Caitlin Patterson, and Ida Sargent.For Martin and Patterson, it will be their first time representing the US at World Championships. Lustgarten previously represented the US at the 2017 World Championships in Lahti, Finland. For Sargent, this will be her 5th time attending World Championships, starting in 2011 in Oslo, Norway.The Championships kick off on Thursday, February 21 and conclude on Sunday, March 3. All results will be available on FIS-Ski.com, and live video will be on the Olympic channel. Congratulations to our Green Racing Project athletes for qualifying, and best of luck in the championships!Link to the article about team naming here.Full Schedule:All times ESTPreliminary schedule, subject to changeThursday, Feb. 216:00 a.m. - Men and women&#039;s sprint qualification 8:30 a.m. - Men and women&#039;s sprint finals Saturday, Feb. 237:30 a.m. - Women&#039;s 15k skiathlon8:30 a.m. - Men&#039;s 30k skiathlon Sunday, Feb. 248:30 a.m. - Men and women&#039;s team sprint qualification 10:30 a.m. - Men and women&#039;s team sprint finals Tuesday, Feb. 267:30 a.m. - Women&#039;s 10kWednesday, Feb. 278:00 a.m. - Men&#039;s 15kThursday, Feb. 287:00 a.m. - Women&#039;s 4x5k relay Friday, March 17:00 a.m. - Men&#039;s 4x10k relay Saturday, March 27:00 a.m. - Women&#039;s 30k Sunday, March 37:00 a.m. - Men&#039;s 50k <img src="/assets/Uploads/benotepaa3.jpg" alt="benotepaa3" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2203/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>GRP Biathletes Post Strong Results on the IBU and World Cups</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2194/</link>
			<description>This past weekend racing action resumed for the biathlon squad after their holiday break with GRP athletes racing the World Cup in Oberhof, Germany and the IBU Cup in Duszniki, Poland. World CupThe GRP had a strong start to the weekend with two top-15 finishes in the sprint race. Susan Dunklee finished 10th with one prone miss and Clare Egan placed 13th with one standing miss. Summer GRP training partner, Johanna Talihaerm of Estonia, had a personal-best World Cup finish of 26th with clean shooting. In the pursuit race, Susan moved up to 7th with five misses. She was followed by Johanna in 31st and Clare in 33rd. For the relay, Susan and Clare were joined by GRP teammate Emily Dreissigacker and USBA teammate Joanne Reid. The team finished 12th with 5 penalties and 16 spares. World Cup racing action continues next weekend in Ruhpolding, Germany.IBU CupThe IBU Cup weekend consisted of two sprint races. In the first race, Emily placed 44th with two standing misses. She was followed by Hallie Grossman in 72nd. For the men, Jake Brown had a strong race placing 25th with 3 prone misses. Raleigh Goessling finished 87th. In the second sprint race, Hallie posted a personal-best IBU Cup finish of 33rd with just one standing miss. For the men, Jake also placed 33rd and Raleigh finished 62nd. Next weekend’s IBU Cup races will take place in Arber, Germany. More information and results can be found at biathlonworld.com.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 19:17:25 -0500</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[This past weekend racing action resumed for the biathlon squad after their holiday break with GRP athletes racing the World Cup in Oberhof, Germany and the IBU Cup in Duszniki, Poland. World CupThe GRP had a strong start to the weekend with two top-15 finishes in the sprint race. Susan Dunklee finished 10th with one prone miss and Clare Egan placed 13th with one standing miss. Summer GRP training partner, Johanna Talihaerm of Estonia, had a personal-best World Cup finish of 26th with clean shooting. In the pursuit race, Susan moved up to 7th with five misses. She was followed by Johanna in 31st and Clare in 33rd. For the relay, Susan and Clare were joined by GRP teammate Emily Dreissigacker and USBA teammate Joanne Reid. The team finished 12th with 5 penalties and 16 spares. World Cup racing action continues next weekend in Ruhpolding, Germany.IBU CupThe IBU Cup weekend consisted of two sprint races. In the first race, Emily placed 44th with two standing misses. She was followed by Hallie Grossman in 72nd. For the men, Jake Brown had a strong race placing 25th with 3 prone misses. Raleigh Goessling finished 87th. In the second sprint race, Hallie posted a personal-best IBU Cup finish of 33rd with just one standing miss. For the men, Jake also placed 33rd and Raleigh finished 62nd. Next weekend’s IBU Cup races will take place in Arber, Germany. More information and results can be found at biathlonworld.com. <img src="/assets/Uploads/1.13.19biathlonnewsphoto.jpg" alt="1.13.19biathlonnewsphoto" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2194/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Sargent Races Dresden World Cup</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2192/</link>
			<description>After winning the classic sprint at US Cross Country Championships on January 4, Ida Sargent was back in action on the World Cup in Dresden, Germany this weekend. Dresden is a city sprint, where organizers bring in truckloads of snow to spread on the city streets among historic buildings. With limited snow in Dresden, there was green grass on the side of the course, and even a spectator on horseback in the adjacent field!Sargent raced a freestyle sprint on Saturday, January 12, finishing 38th in the qualifier. She was just 2 seconds out of qualifying for the rounds, while dealing with an issue with her femoral nerve that is aggravated by icy conditions like Dresden. The following day, Sargent teamed up with World Cup rookie Hannah Halvorsen for the team sprint. They finished fourth in their semifinal, but unfortunately only the top two from each semifinal automatically advance to the finals. Five out of the six lucky loser spots for the final went to teams from the second semifinal, so Sargent and Halvorsen just missed out and finished 11th on the day.The World Cup continues next weekend in Otepaa, Estonia with a classic sprint and a classic distance race. Results from Dresden are available on FIS-ski.com</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 16:15:45 -0500</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[After winning the classic sprint at US Cross Country Championships on January 4, Ida Sargent was back in action on the World Cup in Dresden, Germany this weekend. Dresden is a city sprint, where organizers bring in truckloads of snow to spread on the city streets among historic buildings. With limited snow in Dresden, there was green grass on the side of the course, and even a spectator on horseback in the adjacent field!Sargent raced a freestyle sprint on Saturday, January 12, finishing 38th in the qualifier. She was just 2 seconds out of qualifying for the rounds, while dealing with an issue with her femoral nerve that is aggravated by icy conditions like Dresden. The following day, Sargent teamed up with World Cup rookie Hannah Halvorsen for the team sprint. They finished fourth in their semifinal, but unfortunately only the top two from each semifinal automatically advance to the finals. Five out of the six lucky loser spots for the final went to teams from the second semifinal, so Sargent and Halvorsen just missed out and finished 11th on the day.The World Cup continues next weekend in Otepaa, Estonia with a classic sprint and a classic distance race. Results from Dresden are available on FIS-ski.com <img src="/assets/Uploads/JCL-4173w.jpg" alt="JCL 4173w" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2192/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Green Racing Project Skiers Finish US Nationals on a Strong Note with Freestyle Events</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2188/</link>
			<description>Racing is officially wrapped up at US Cross Country Championships in Craftsbury, VT. After notching four podium results in the opening classic events, Green Racing Project skiers continued to have good results in the final two races of the series.After a rest day, racing continued on Sunday, January 6 with a 20/30k freestyle mass start. In the women&#039;s race, Caitlin Patterson broke away early and skied to the victory with a large cushion over second place. Kaitlynn Miller finished 10th, outpacing the pack she skied with for most of the race. Liz Guiney finished 19th. A few hours later, the men raced on the same course, this time adding two laps for a grueling 30k. Adam Martin won a photo finish in his pack to finish 5th, while Akeo Maifeld-Carucci barely missed 9th place in a lunge, and finished 10th.Two days later, the skiers took on the final event of the Championship, freestyle sprints. All three GRP women qualified for the heats, with Caitlin Patterson in 4th, Kaitlynn Miller 11th, and Liz Guiney 13th. On the men&#039;s side, Akeo Maifeld-Carucci had a strong qualifier, finishing 15th, and Adam Martin took 56th. Patterson moved through the quarterfinal and semifinal heats to make the A Final, where she placed 4th. Miller also made the semifinals, finishing 5th in her heat and 9th overall. Guiney took 5th place in her quarterfinal, and 21st overall. On the men&#039;s side, Maifeld-Carucci unfortunately fell and placed 6th in his quarterfinal, thus placing 27th overall. It was wonderful for the GRP to be able to race at home in Craftsbury and enjoy the home course advantage as well as large cheering squads! The skiers will take a short break from racing, continuing with the SuperTour in Lake Placid on January 25-27.Results from US Nationals.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 17:31:58 -0500</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[Racing is officially wrapped up at US Cross Country Championships in Craftsbury, VT. After notching four podium results in the opening classic events, Green Racing Project skiers continued to have good results in the final two races of the series.After a rest day, racing continued on Sunday, January 6 with a 20/30k freestyle mass start. In the women&#039;s race, Caitlin Patterson broke away early and skied to the victory with a large cushion over second place. Kaitlynn Miller finished 10th, outpacing the pack she skied with for most of the race. Liz Guiney finished 19th. A few hours later, the men raced on the same course, this time adding two laps for a grueling 30k. Adam Martin won a photo finish in his pack to finish 5th, while Akeo Maifeld-Carucci barely missed 9th place in a lunge, and finished 10th.Two days later, the skiers took on the final event of the Championship, freestyle sprints. All three GRP women qualified for the heats, with Caitlin Patterson in 4th, Kaitlynn Miller 11th, and Liz Guiney 13th. On the men&#039;s side, Akeo Maifeld-Carucci had a strong qualifier, finishing 15th, and Adam Martin took 56th. Patterson moved through the quarterfinal and semifinal heats to make the A Final, where she placed 4th. Miller also made the semifinals, finishing 5th in her heat and 9th overall. Guiney took 5th place in her quarterfinal, and 21st overall. On the men&#039;s side, Maifeld-Carucci unfortunately fell and placed 6th in his quarterfinal, thus placing 27th overall. It was wonderful for the GRP to be able to race at home in Craftsbury and enjoy the home course advantage as well as large cheering squads! The skiers will take a short break from racing, continuing with the SuperTour in Lake Placid on January 25-27.Results from US Nationals. <img src="/assets/Uploads/JCL-9036w.jpg" alt="JCL 9036w" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2188/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>U.S. Cross-Country Ski Championships presented by L.L. Bean: Day Four Recap</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2187/</link>
			<description>Racers woke up to a dusting of new snow on Sunday morning at U.S. Nationals, as Craftsbury prepared for a full day of mass start freestyle racing. The snow continued to fall lightly throughout the day, settling on the racers as they tackled multiple laps of the tough 5k course. The women’s 20k kicked off the day, and for the first lap, 2018 Olympians Caitlin Patterson (GRP) and Rosie Frankowski (APU) traded the lead, with a chase pack not far behind. However, over the course of the second lap, Patterson started to pull ahead. By the 10k, she had a 14.5 second gap on Frankowski, which expanded to nearly 36 seconds by the time they passed the 15k mark. Frankowski, likewise, had gapped the women behind her, and both women skied much of the grueling race alone. All told, Patterson crossed the finish line 40 seconds ahead of Frankowski, and was the only woman to stop the clock at under an hour. Jessica Yeaton (APU) followed six seconds behind Frankowski, though Hailey Swirbul’s (also APU) fourth-place finish earned her third place on the American podium. With her win, Patterson captured her second national title of the week, and another top spot for the GRP on their home course. Next up was the men’s 30k. A lead pack stayed largely together through the first two laps, but by the halfway point at the 15k, three men had made a move to put them solidly ahead. David Norris (APU), Scott Patterson (APU), and Kyle Bratrud (SMS T2) traded the lead throughout the rest of the race, passing through the 25k mark within one second of each other. During the last lap, however, Norris made his move, and Bratrud and Patterson could not match it. Norris crossed the line as the national champion 6.4 seconds ahead of Bratrud, with Patterson taking third another 13 seconds back. The afternoon saw massive fields for the junior boys’ 10k and junior girls’ 7.5k. The boys barreled across the finish line one after another, with Johnny Hagenbuch (Sun Valley) taking first, Luke Jager (APU) in second, and Zanden McMullen (APU) in third. The girls’ race was won convincingly by Kendall Kramer (Fairbanks), who skied to the finish with no one else in sight. Novie McCabe (Methow Valley) was second, and Sydney Palmer-Leger (Sun Valley) took third.Today’s national champions were presented with shirts from the Vermont Flannel Company, while the second-place podium finishers were given blocks of Cabot cheddar, and Vermont maple syrup from Butternut Mountain Farm for the third-place finishers.Full results2019 Nationals conclude with a day of freestyle sprinting tomorrow. See you there!  </description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 22:51:00 -0500</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[Racers woke up to a dusting of new snow on Sunday morning at U.S. Nationals, as Craftsbury prepared for a full day of mass start freestyle racing. The snow continued to fall lightly throughout the day, settling on the racers as they tackled multiple laps of the tough 5k course. The women’s 20k kicked off the day, and for the first lap, 2018 Olympians Caitlin Patterson (GRP) and Rosie Frankowski (APU) traded the lead, with a chase pack not far behind. However, over the course of the second lap, Patterson started to pull ahead. By the 10k, she had a 14.5 second gap on Frankowski, which expanded to nearly 36 seconds by the time they passed the 15k mark. Frankowski, likewise, had gapped the women behind her, and both women skied much of the grueling race alone. All told, Patterson crossed the finish line 40 seconds ahead of Frankowski, and was the only woman to stop the clock at under an hour. Jessica Yeaton (APU) followed six seconds behind Frankowski, though Hailey Swirbul’s (also APU) fourth-place finish earned her third place on the American podium. With her win, Patterson captured her second national title of the week, and another top spot for the GRP on their home course. Next up was the men’s 30k. A lead pack stayed largely together through the first two laps, but by the halfway point at the 15k, three men had made a move to put them solidly ahead. David Norris (APU), Scott Patterson (APU), and Kyle Bratrud (SMS T2) traded the lead throughout the rest of the race, passing through the 25k mark within one second of each other. During the last lap, however, Norris made his move, and Bratrud and Patterson could not match it. Norris crossed the line as the national champion 6.4 seconds ahead of Bratrud, with Patterson taking third another 13 seconds back. The afternoon saw massive fields for the junior boys’ 10k and junior girls’ 7.5k. The boys barreled across the finish line one after another, with Johnny Hagenbuch (Sun Valley) taking first, Luke Jager (APU) in second, and Zanden McMullen (APU) in third. The girls’ race was won convincingly by Kendall Kramer (Fairbanks), who skied to the finish with no one else in sight. Novie McCabe (Methow Valley) was second, and Sydney Palmer-Leger (Sun Valley) took third.Today’s national champions were presented with shirts from the Vermont Flannel Company, while the second-place podium finishers were given blocks of Cabot cheddar, and Vermont maple syrup from Butternut Mountain Farm for the third-place finishers.Full results2019 Nationals conclude with a day of freestyle sprinting tomorrow. See you there!   <img src="/assets/bulkUpload/JCL-5812w2.jpg" alt="JCL 5812w2" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2187/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Lustgarten Finishes 2019 Tour de Ski in 42nd</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2186/</link>
			<description>Green Racing Project skier Ben Lustgarten has completed his first ever Tour de Ski. The Tour is the most grueling event on the World Cup calendar, and includes seven races over the course of nine days, in four different countries. We previously covered the first three stages of Lustgarten&#039;s Tour results, and he has officially completed the final stage as of Sunday, January 6th.Stage number four on the Tour de Ski took racers to Oberstdorf, Germany for a 15k classic mass start. There, Lustgarten had one of his best races of the 2019 Tour, with a 57th place in the 15k. While the place wasn&#039;t a personal best, he was only 38 seconds back from the winner on the day. The following day, Lustgarten raced a 15k freestyle pursuit, also in Oberstdorf, and finished in 54th. From there, racers had a rest day and then moved to Val di Fiemme, Italy for the final stages. In stage six, Lustgarten placed 44th in another 15k classic mass start. Stage seven brought the most grueling day of all, the Final Climb, where racers skied 6k to the base of an alpine hill, and then climbed straight up, in some places hitting a 28% grade. Lustgarten fought hard on stage seven and finished 42nd overall in the Tour de Ski, with the 37th fastest time on day.Results from the FIS Tour de Ski are available HERE. Lustgarten will be back in action in the World Cups in Otepaa, Estonia, the weekend of January 19th.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 15:48:43 -0500</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[Green Racing Project skier Ben Lustgarten has completed his first ever Tour de Ski. The Tour is the most grueling event on the World Cup calendar, and includes seven races over the course of nine days, in four different countries. We previously covered the first three stages of Lustgarten&#039;s Tour results, and he has officially completed the final stage as of Sunday, January 6th.Stage number four on the Tour de Ski took racers to Oberstdorf, Germany for a 15k classic mass start. There, Lustgarten had one of his best races of the 2019 Tour, with a 57th place in the 15k. While the place wasn&#039;t a personal best, he was only 38 seconds back from the winner on the day. The following day, Lustgarten raced a 15k freestyle pursuit, also in Oberstdorf, and finished in 54th. From there, racers had a rest day and then moved to Val di Fiemme, Italy for the final stages. In stage six, Lustgarten placed 44th in another 15k classic mass start. Stage seven brought the most grueling day of all, the Final Climb, where racers skied 6k to the base of an alpine hill, and then climbed straight up, in some places hitting a 28% grade. Lustgarten fought hard on stage seven and finished 42nd overall in the Tour de Ski, with the 37th fastest time on day.Results from the FIS Tour de Ski are available HERE. Lustgarten will be back in action in the World Cups in Otepaa, Estonia, the weekend of January 19th. <img src="/assets/Uploads/bentourdeski.jpg" alt="bentourdeski" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2186/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Green Racing Project Skiers Podium Multiple Times in US Nationals Classic Events</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2184/</link>
			<description>US Cross Country Championships are underway in Craftsbury, VT. In the first two events of the championships, a 10/15k classic interval start and a classic sprint, skiers from the Green Racing Project have already collected 4 podium finishes.The first race of the Championship was the men’s 15k classic on Thursday, January 3. Five inches of new snow greeted the skiers on race morning, making for a slow, deep tracks. GRP skier Adam Martin finished in second place, a little over 30 seconds off the winning time of Kyle Bratrud. Akeo Maifeld-Carucci also had a strong result, with a tie for ninth place. Later in the day the women raced 10k classic. Caitlin Patterson had a convincing win over APU skier Jessica Yeaton, and Kaitlynn Miller also reached the podium in third. The other GRP women had good results as well: Ida Sargent broke a pole in the last kilometer of the race but still finished in ninth place, Liz Guiney took 14th, and Corey Stock was 34th.In the following day&#039;s classic sprint events, the GRP continued their string of good results. Four GRP women qualified for the heats, with Ida Sargent in first, Kaitlynn Miller fourth, Caitlin Patterson 10th, and Liz Guiney in 13th. Corey Stock finished 70th in the qualifier. On the men&#039;s side, Akeo Maifeld-Carucci placed 52nd in qualifying. Sargent went on to dominate the day, winning her quarterfinal and semifinal heats, and then going on to win the A Final in convincing fashion. The win is Sargent&#039;s first National Championship title. Patterson and Miller also made the A Final, finishing 4th and 5th, respectively. Guiney made it as far as the semifinals, where she finished 6th in her heat and 12th overall.We’re thrilled to be able to race on our home courses in Craftsbury, and excited for the upcoming races: a 20/30k freestyle mass start on Sunday and freestyle sprints on Tuesday! Keep following along on our website, Facebook, and Instagram for updates, and come visit to watch the racing live! Results: Schedule  </description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 13:40:09 -0500</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[US Cross Country Championships are underway in Craftsbury, VT. In the first two events of the championships, a 10/15k classic interval start and a classic sprint, skiers from the Green Racing Project have already collected 4 podium finishes.The first race of the Championship was the men’s 15k classic on Thursday, January 3. Five inches of new snow greeted the skiers on race morning, making for a slow, deep tracks. GRP skier Adam Martin finished in second place, a little over 30 seconds off the winning time of Kyle Bratrud. Akeo Maifeld-Carucci also had a strong result, with a tie for ninth place. Later in the day the women raced 10k classic. Caitlin Patterson had a convincing win over APU skier Jessica Yeaton, and Kaitlynn Miller also reached the podium in third. The other GRP women had good results as well: Ida Sargent broke a pole in the last kilometer of the race but still finished in ninth place, Liz Guiney took 14th, and Corey Stock was 34th.In the following day&#039;s classic sprint events, the GRP continued their string of good results. Four GRP women qualified for the heats, with Ida Sargent in first, Kaitlynn Miller fourth, Caitlin Patterson 10th, and Liz Guiney in 13th. Corey Stock finished 70th in the qualifier. On the men&#039;s side, Akeo Maifeld-Carucci placed 52nd in qualifying. Sargent went on to dominate the day, winning her quarterfinal and semifinal heats, and then going on to win the A Final in convincing fashion. The win is Sargent&#039;s first National Championship title. Patterson and Miller also made the A Final, finishing 4th and 5th, respectively. Guiney made it as far as the semifinals, where she finished 6th in her heat and 12th overall.We’re thrilled to be able to race on our home courses in Craftsbury, and excited for the upcoming races: a 20/30k freestyle mass start on Sunday and freestyle sprints on Tuesday! Keep following along on our website, Facebook, and Instagram for updates, and come visit to watch the racing live! Results: Schedule   <img src="/assets/Uploads/49429037-1779765835466526-7743422453791064064-n.jpg" alt="49429037 1779765835466526 7743422453791064064 n" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2184/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>U.S. Cross-Country Ski Championships presented by L.L. Bean: Day Two Recap</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2183/</link>
			<description>The second day of U.S. Nationals arrived with sunshine and crowds for a full day of classic sprinting. Over 200 women and nearly 300 men raced the qualifier, with Craftsbury GRP’s Ida Sargent and Ben Saxton of SMS T2 taking the top qualifying times. Kelsey Phinney and Julia Kern rounded out the top three for the women’s qualifier, while Daniel Streinz and Andy Newell qualified in second and third for the men. Sargent proceeded to dominate the women’s day, winning her quarterfinal and semifinal while posting the fastest times in each round. She capped it all off by taking the win in the final, which also held Green Racing Project skiers Kaitlynn Miller and Caitlin Patterson. Second and third place were taken by Julia Kern (SMS T2) and Hannah Halvorson (APU), who had a furious fight to line that led to finishing just two hundredths of a second apart.On the men’s side, Julien Locke of Canada won the A final after also posting the fastest times in his quarterfinal and semifinal. SMS T2 skier Ben Saxton crossed the line less than a second back, followed closely by APU’s Logan Hanneman in third. Since the overall podium featured a Canadian, however, fourth-place finisher Peter Holmes (Sun Valley) moved up to third for the U.S. National Championships podium, and Ben Saxton claimed the title of classic sprint national champion.First-place finishers today received hats hand-knit by Kaitlynn Miller, second-place finishers received prizes from Vermont Maple Sriracha, and third-place finishers received maple candy from Butternut Mountain Farm. In addition, the fastest qualifiers on the men’s and women’s sides received a product sampler from Vermont skin care company Ursa Major.Congrats to the new classic sprint national champions and thanks for joining us! More to come as U.S. Nationals presented by L.L. Bean continue here at Craftsbury. Full resultsOverheard: &quot;It was the best sprint course I&#039;ve ever skied!&quot;</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 23:47:12 -0500</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[The second day of U.S. Nationals arrived with sunshine and crowds for a full day of classic sprinting. Over 200 women and nearly 300 men raced the qualifier, with Craftsbury GRP’s Ida Sargent and Ben Saxton of SMS T2 taking the top qualifying times. Kelsey Phinney and Julia Kern rounded out the top three for the women’s qualifier, while Daniel Streinz and Andy Newell qualified in second and third for the men. Sargent proceeded to dominate the women’s day, winning her quarterfinal and semifinal while posting the fastest times in each round. She capped it all off by taking the win in the final, which also held Green Racing Project skiers Kaitlynn Miller and Caitlin Patterson. Second and third place were taken by Julia Kern (SMS T2) and Hannah Halvorson (APU), who had a furious fight to line that led to finishing just two hundredths of a second apart.On the men’s side, Julien Locke of Canada won the A final after also posting the fastest times in his quarterfinal and semifinal. SMS T2 skier Ben Saxton crossed the line less than a second back, followed closely by APU’s Logan Hanneman in third. Since the overall podium featured a Canadian, however, fourth-place finisher Peter Holmes (Sun Valley) moved up to third for the U.S. National Championships podium, and Ben Saxton claimed the title of classic sprint national champion.First-place finishers today received hats hand-knit by Kaitlynn Miller, second-place finishers received prizes from Vermont Maple Sriracha, and third-place finishers received maple candy from Butternut Mountain Farm. In addition, the fastest qualifiers on the men’s and women’s sides received a product sampler from Vermont skin care company Ursa Major.Congrats to the new classic sprint national champions and thanks for joining us! More to come as U.S. Nationals presented by L.L. Bean continue here at Craftsbury. Full resultsOverheard: &quot;It was the best sprint course I&#039;ve ever skied!&quot; <img src="/assets/bulkUpload/JCL-3818w.jpg" alt="JCL 3818w" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2183/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>U.S. Cross-Country Ski Championships presented by L.L. Bean: Day One Recap</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2182/</link>
			<description>Racers gearing up for the first day of U.S. Nationals at Craftsbury woke up to five fresh inches of soft, powdery snow on the ground, just in time to kick off a week of racing. Though the new conditions presented a challenge for racers and waxers, excitement was high as the nearly 600 competitors took to the tracks today to tear up a 10/15k (and Para-Nordic 5/7.5k) classic individual start. The morning started off with Para-Nordic racers taking on a 5/7.5k classic.The men’s Para race was won by Dan Cnossen by over two minutes, with Cnossen finishing in 25:09.9 to Aaron Pike’s 27:12.6. Both men represented the US at last year’s Paralympic Games, and Craftsbury was excited to welcome Dan back, as he trained with us throughout last winter in preparation for the Games. Third place went to Canadian Paralympian Yves Bourque, who finished in 30:21.0.One the women’s side, the top two podium spots were again shared by two 2018 US Paralympians, Oksana Masters and Kendall Gretsch. Both women won gold medals in Pyeongchang last year, and finished with strong results today – Masters with first place in 19:38.9, and Gretsch in second with a time of 21:16.7. Third place for the women was also a Canadian, Lyne Marie Bilodeau, with a finish time of 26:52.5.The next race of the day was the men’s 15k classic. Racers started on 15 second intervals, with the top three settling out to Kyle Bratrud taking first in 41:41.8, Craftsbury’s own Adam Martin in 42:12.8, and Kris Freeman in 42:27.6. The day of racing concluded with the women’s 10k classic. GRP’s Caitlin Patterson won convincingly in 30:44.7, followed by Jessica Yeaton in 31:05.5 and GRP’s Kaitlynn Miller rounding out the podium in a time of 31:22.1. However, since this is US Nationals and Yeaton is Australian, the official U.S. National Championship podium was Caitlin Patterson, Kaitlynn Miller, and Julia Kern (who placed fourth overall in 31:33.9). All of today&#039;s podium finishers went home with prizes that included maple syrup from Butternut Mountain Farm and hot sauce from Vermont Maple Sriracha.Keep following along on our website, Facebook, and Instagram for updates, and come visit to watch the racing live! Full resultsScheduleNotes from the stadium:Multiple volunteers stated how impressed they were at the racers’ comportment at the finish: “It was so much fun being at the finish when all those kids have just finished an incredibly tough race and were still so overwhelmingly polite and thankful,” said Lindy Sargent.Unprecedented traffic for start lists and results led our timing contractor, Bullitt Timing, to upgrade their website to a new server. Please be patient as things catch up, and clear your browser cache if you have trouble seeing their website!  </description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 20:16:58 -0500</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[Racers gearing up for the first day of U.S. Nationals at Craftsbury woke up to five fresh inches of soft, powdery snow on the ground, just in time to kick off a week of racing. Though the new conditions presented a challenge for racers and waxers, excitement was high as the nearly 600 competitors took to the tracks today to tear up a 10/15k (and Para-Nordic 5/7.5k) classic individual start. The morning started off with Para-Nordic racers taking on a 5/7.5k classic.The men’s Para race was won by Dan Cnossen by over two minutes, with Cnossen finishing in 25:09.9 to Aaron Pike’s 27:12.6. Both men represented the US at last year’s Paralympic Games, and Craftsbury was excited to welcome Dan back, as he trained with us throughout last winter in preparation for the Games. Third place went to Canadian Paralympian Yves Bourque, who finished in 30:21.0.One the women’s side, the top two podium spots were again shared by two 2018 US Paralympians, Oksana Masters and Kendall Gretsch. Both women won gold medals in Pyeongchang last year, and finished with strong results today – Masters with first place in 19:38.9, and Gretsch in second with a time of 21:16.7. Third place for the women was also a Canadian, Lyne Marie Bilodeau, with a finish time of 26:52.5.The next race of the day was the men’s 15k classic. Racers started on 15 second intervals, with the top three settling out to Kyle Bratrud taking first in 41:41.8, Craftsbury’s own Adam Martin in 42:12.8, and Kris Freeman in 42:27.6. The day of racing concluded with the women’s 10k classic. GRP’s Caitlin Patterson won convincingly in 30:44.7, followed by Jessica Yeaton in 31:05.5 and GRP’s Kaitlynn Miller rounding out the podium in a time of 31:22.1. However, since this is US Nationals and Yeaton is Australian, the official U.S. National Championship podium was Caitlin Patterson, Kaitlynn Miller, and Julia Kern (who placed fourth overall in 31:33.9). All of today&#039;s podium finishers went home with prizes that included maple syrup from Butternut Mountain Farm and hot sauce from Vermont Maple Sriracha.Keep following along on our website, Facebook, and Instagram for updates, and come visit to watch the racing live! Full resultsScheduleNotes from the stadium:Multiple volunteers stated how impressed they were at the racers’ comportment at the finish: “It was so much fun being at the finish when all those kids have just finished an incredibly tough race and were still so overwhelmingly polite and thankful,” said Lindy Sargent.Unprecedented traffic for start lists and results led our timing contractor, Bullitt Timing, to upgrade their website to a new server. Please be patient as things catch up, and clear your browser cache if you have trouble seeing their website!   <img src="/assets/bulkUpload/49187690-1779766062133170-4399097554025840640-n.jpg" alt="49187690 1779766062133170 4399097554025840640 n" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2182/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Salomon and Craftsbury Green Racing Project Announce Partnership</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2150/</link>
			<description>The Craftsbury Green Racing Project (GRP) elite nordic skiing and biathlon team is excited to announce a new partnership with Salomon.Starting with the winter 2018/19 racing season, the GRP skiers and biathletes will be training in Salomon outerwear during domestic camps and competitions. The 2018/19 Green Racing Project team is made up of eight biathletes and eight cross-country skiers, including six Olympians from the 2018 Pyeongchang Games. Coaches Pepa Miloucheva and Sam Dougherty, as well as wax technician Nicholas Brown, support the team at home in Craftsbury, VT and on the road.Look for the GRP athletes out on the cross-country trails this year in bright blue (men) and teal (women) jackets and black pants, and hopefully up on some podiums in our red and black (men) and blue-black (women) down jackets from Salomon! Domestic skiers will be starting the season in West Yellowstone, MT with FIS races on November 24th, while the biathlon season will get underway later in December in Soldier Hollow, UT. Look for the unveiling of the GRP’s new green and black race suits from Podiumwear at those events.Visit the team’s website at www.greenracingproject.com for athlete biographies and news updates, or connect with us on Instagram and Facebook.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 12:46:37 -0500</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[The Craftsbury Green Racing Project (GRP) elite nordic skiing and biathlon team is excited to announce a new partnership with Salomon.Starting with the winter 2018/19 racing season, the GRP skiers and biathletes will be training in Salomon outerwear during domestic camps and competitions. The 2018/19 Green Racing Project team is made up of eight biathletes and eight cross-country skiers, including six Olympians from the 2018 Pyeongchang Games. Coaches Pepa Miloucheva and Sam Dougherty, as well as wax technician Nicholas Brown, support the team at home in Craftsbury, VT and on the road.Look for the GRP athletes out on the cross-country trails this year in bright blue (men) and teal (women) jackets and black pants, and hopefully up on some podiums in our red and black (men) and blue-black (women) down jackets from Salomon! Domestic skiers will be starting the season in West Yellowstone, MT with FIS races on November 24th, while the biathlon season will get underway later in December in Soldier Hollow, UT. Look for the unveiling of the GRP’s new green and black race suits from Podiumwear at those events.Visit the team’s website at www.greenracingproject.com for athlete biographies and news updates, or connect with us on Instagram and Facebook. <img src="/assets/bulkUpload/CP-08078.jpg" alt="CP 08078" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2150/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>GRP Skiers Kick off the Race Season in Finland</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2148/</link>
			<description>Four GRP skiers started off the 2018-2019 season with FIS races in Rovaniemi, Finland this weekend. Adam Martin, Ida Sargent, Caitlin Patterson, and Kaitlynn Miller are currently training in Rovaniemi prior to the World Cup Opener in Kuusamo, Finland this coming weekend. The races were an opportunity for them to tune up and get the first races of the season over with before the ones that really count. The Russian National Team was using the Rovaniemi races as trials to choose their World Cup teams, so the field was stacked with Russians along with a few Finnish and French skiers.The first race on Thursday, November 15 was a 10/15k classic interval start. Adam Martin was the sole GRP skier to race, placing 25th in the men&#039;s 15k. This result put him solidly in the mix in the field of 54 racers, most of whom are World Cup regulars.Two days later, on November 17, the GRP women raced a classic sprint. In the qualifier, Ida Sargent placed 7th, Caitlin Patterson 13th, and Kaitlynn MIller 14th. As of press time, no results were available online for the heats, but we do know that Ida Sargent advanced to the semifinals but did not make the final, and Patterson and Miller were eliminated in their quarterfinals.The GRP World Cup contingent travels next to Ruka, Finland where they will start the season with a classic sprint and 10/15k classic race. Stay tuned for results from there!Results from Rovaniemi are available here for the classic distance, and on the GRP Instagram for the classic sprint.</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 11:14:15 -0500</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[Four GRP skiers started off the 2018-2019 season with FIS races in Rovaniemi, Finland this weekend. Adam Martin, Ida Sargent, Caitlin Patterson, and Kaitlynn Miller are currently training in Rovaniemi prior to the World Cup Opener in Kuusamo, Finland this coming weekend. The races were an opportunity for them to tune up and get the first races of the season over with before the ones that really count. The Russian National Team was using the Rovaniemi races as trials to choose their World Cup teams, so the field was stacked with Russians along with a few Finnish and French skiers.The first race on Thursday, November 15 was a 10/15k classic interval start. Adam Martin was the sole GRP skier to race, placing 25th in the men&#039;s 15k. This result put him solidly in the mix in the field of 54 racers, most of whom are World Cup regulars.Two days later, on November 17, the GRP women raced a classic sprint. In the qualifier, Ida Sargent placed 7th, Caitlin Patterson 13th, and Kaitlynn MIller 14th. As of press time, no results were available online for the heats, but we do know that Ida Sargent advanced to the semifinals but did not make the final, and Patterson and Miller were eliminated in their quarterfinals.The GRP World Cup contingent travels next to Ruka, Finland where they will start the season with a classic sprint and 10/15k classic race. Stay tuned for results from there!Results from Rovaniemi are available here for the classic distance, and on the GRP Instagram for the classic sprint. <img src="/assets/Uploads/adam.jpg" alt="adam" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2148/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>GRP Biathletes Selected to Race World and IBU Cups</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2138/</link>
			<description>This morning the U.S. Biathlon Association announced who earned race starts for Period 1 on the World Cup and the IBU Cup. Susan Dunklee and Clare Egan were pre-qualified for the World Cup based on last years results, but the remaining start positions were decided using rollerski trials from last week in Solder Hollow, Utah and this summer in Jericho, Vermont.Emily Dreissigacker will join Susan and Clare on the World Cup which kicks off December 2nd in Pokljuka, Slovenia. These three GRP women plus Joanne Reid (who was pre-qualified) will compete in Slovenia, but only three athletes will continue on to World Cup 2 in Hochfilzen, Austria. The fourth, yet-to-be-determined athlete, will join the IBU Cup squad in Ridnaun-Val Ridanna, Italy. Hallie Grossman, Kelsey Dickinson, Alex Howe, and Jake Brown were named to the IBU Cup team for Period 1 and will start their season at IBU Cup #2 in Ridnaun on December 13th. They will then continue racing through IBU Cup #3 in Obertilliach, Austria.Congrats to the GRP biathlon squad and stay tuned as racing gets underway! We will keep you up-to-date with schedules and results, but you can also check out biathlonworld.com for more information</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 13:19:02 -0500</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[This morning the U.S. Biathlon Association announced who earned race starts for Period 1 on the World Cup and the IBU Cup. Susan Dunklee and Clare Egan were pre-qualified for the World Cup based on last years results, but the remaining start positions were decided using rollerski trials from last week in Solder Hollow, Utah and this summer in Jericho, Vermont.Emily Dreissigacker will join Susan and Clare on the World Cup which kicks off December 2nd in Pokljuka, Slovenia. These three GRP women plus Joanne Reid (who was pre-qualified) will compete in Slovenia, but only three athletes will continue on to World Cup 2 in Hochfilzen, Austria. The fourth, yet-to-be-determined athlete, will join the IBU Cup squad in Ridnaun-Val Ridanna, Italy. Hallie Grossman, Kelsey Dickinson, Alex Howe, and Jake Brown were named to the IBU Cup team for Period 1 and will start their season at IBU Cup #2 in Ridnaun on December 13th. They will then continue racing through IBU Cup #3 in Obertilliach, Austria.Congrats to the GRP biathlon squad and stay tuned as racing gets underway! We will keep you up-to-date with schedules and results, but you can also check out biathlonworld.com for more information <img src="/assets/Uploads/11.6.18biathlonnewsphoto2.jpg" alt="11.6.18biathlonnewsphoto2" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2138/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Craftsbury Skiers Compete at NENSA Trapp Invitational Rollerski Race</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2139/</link>
			<description>NENSA and the Trapp Family Lodge recently hosted the last rollerski race event in the 2018 NENSA Rollerski Series, which included 5 races in New York and Vermont. The race, a 10k classic in Stowe, VT on November 3, wound its way along some of Stowe&#039;s rolling hills before climbing to its completion at the nordic center at the Trapp Family Lodge. Racers faced grueling conditions: a downpour, driving wind, and even some snow up top. However, almost 60 competitors still toed the line for the individual start race.In the women&#039;s race, GRP athlete Caitlin Patterson had the top result of the day, finishing 3rd overall and 1st in the senior women&#039;s category. Ida Sargent finished 1st in the master women&#039;s category, good for 4th overall. Liz Guiney was 2nd in senior women, and Kaitlynn Miller finished 3rd for senior women. Craftsbury also had a handful of junior athletes compete, as well as some former CNSC athletes. Phoebe Sweet, formerly CNSC and now skiing for UVM, finished 6th for junior women. Quincy Massey-Bierman was 8th in junior women, and Adrienne Remick took 10th. In the U23 women&#039;s category, former CNSC racers Alex Lawson and Avery Ellis, both skiing for Middlebury, finished 6th and 9th. Last, not but least, GRP summer training partner Lina Sutro from UVM finished an impressive 2nd overall, and 2nd in the U23 women&#039;s race.On the men&#039;s side, GRP skier Adam Martin skied to the overall win in a time of 28:39. Ben Lustgarten was not far behind, taking 2nd place, approximately 8 seconds behind Adam. GRP skier Akeo Maifield-Carucci finished 4th in the senior men&#039;s race. Our junior men had very solid results as well. Griffin Wright from the CNSC team placed 3rd in junior men, and Finn Sweet finished 5th.At the culmination of the 2018 Rollerski Series, NENSA named overall series winners, who were awarded prize money for their efforts! Athletes had to complete 3 of the 5 races to be eligible. On the women&#039;s side, Caitlin Patterson won the overall series, with two first place finishes and a third place at Trapp&#039;s. Ida Sargent took 2nd place in the overall, by virtue of two second place finishes in individual races, and her 4th at Trapp&#039;s. On the men&#039;s side, Adam Martin won the overall series, with a win at Trapp&#039;s, and two second place finishes earlier in the season.Full results from the race are available on BartTiming. Also, keep checking the Craftsbury Outdoor Center Facebook page, we&#039;ll be posting a full gallery soon!</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 13:32:12 -0500</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[NENSA and the Trapp Family Lodge recently hosted the last rollerski race event in the 2018 NENSA Rollerski Series, which included 5 races in New York and Vermont. The race, a 10k classic in Stowe, VT on November 3, wound its way along some of Stowe&#039;s rolling hills before climbing to its completion at the nordic center at the Trapp Family Lodge. Racers faced grueling conditions: a downpour, driving wind, and even some snow up top. However, almost 60 competitors still toed the line for the individual start race.In the women&#039;s race, GRP athlete Caitlin Patterson had the top result of the day, finishing 3rd overall and 1st in the senior women&#039;s category. Ida Sargent finished 1st in the master women&#039;s category, good for 4th overall. Liz Guiney was 2nd in senior women, and Kaitlynn Miller finished 3rd for senior women. Craftsbury also had a handful of junior athletes compete, as well as some former CNSC athletes. Phoebe Sweet, formerly CNSC and now skiing for UVM, finished 6th for junior women. Quincy Massey-Bierman was 8th in junior women, and Adrienne Remick took 10th. In the U23 women&#039;s category, former CNSC racers Alex Lawson and Avery Ellis, both skiing for Middlebury, finished 6th and 9th. Last, not but least, GRP summer training partner Lina Sutro from UVM finished an impressive 2nd overall, and 2nd in the U23 women&#039;s race.On the men&#039;s side, GRP skier Adam Martin skied to the overall win in a time of 28:39. Ben Lustgarten was not far behind, taking 2nd place, approximately 8 seconds behind Adam. GRP skier Akeo Maifield-Carucci finished 4th in the senior men&#039;s race. Our junior men had very solid results as well. Griffin Wright from the CNSC team placed 3rd in junior men, and Finn Sweet finished 5th.At the culmination of the 2018 Rollerski Series, NENSA named overall series winners, who were awarded prize money for their efforts! Athletes had to complete 3 of the 5 races to be eligible. On the women&#039;s side, Caitlin Patterson won the overall series, with two first place finishes and a third place at Trapp&#039;s. Ida Sargent took 2nd place in the overall, by virtue of two second place finishes in individual races, and her 4th at Trapp&#039;s. On the men&#039;s side, Adam Martin won the overall series, with a win at Trapp&#039;s, and two second place finishes earlier in the season.Full results from the race are available on BartTiming. Also, keep checking the Craftsbury Outdoor Center Facebook page, we&#039;ll be posting a full gallery soon! <img src="/assets/Uploads/44980408884-26d7f1c9db-z.jpg" alt="44980408884 26d7f1c9db z" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2139/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>GRP Results from USBA Fall Festival/Team Selection Series</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2136/</link>
			<description>All three races in the US Biathlon (USBA) Fall Festival Rollerski Trials are in the books, and the Green Racing Project had some standout results. USBA uses the results from these rollerski trials races, in addition to two previous races in Jericho, VT, to select their World Cup team for the upcoming season. While the selections won’t be made public until after the completion of all five races, we hope to see a number of GRP athletes represent the US in early World Cups.The race series started on Tuesday, October 30 with a 7.5/10k sprint race. In the senior women’s category, GRP athletes swept the top three positions, with Susan Dunklee, Clare Egan and Emily Dreissigacker going 1-2-3. All three missed just one shot in standing. The sweep continued from there, with Hallie Grossman taking 4th place (with clean shooting!), Johanna Taliharm (of Estonia, but a GRP summer training partner) in 5th, and Kelsey Dickinson in 6th. On the men’s side, Jake Brown took 5th for the GRP, Alex Howe finished 7th, and Raleigh Goessling was 8th.The following day, October 31, athletes raced another 7.5/10k sprint. The GRP women did well again, this time with Susan taking 1st and Hallie in 3rd. Johanna Taliharm placed 2nd. Emily Dreissigacker took 5th place, Clare Egan 6th, and Kelsey Dickinson 9th. In the men’s race, Jake Brown landed on the podium in 3rd place. Alex Howe placed 6th, and Raleigh Goessling was 8th.The final day of competition, November 2, was a mass start race, 12.5k for women and 15k for men. The GRP women had another great day, with Clare, Susan and Emily sweeping the podium once again, in that order. They were followed by Johanna in 4th, Hallie in 5th, and Kelsey in 6th. On the men&#039;s side, Jake finished 6th and Raleigh 7th. Results from all of the trials race are available on the USBA website, right HERE.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 14:54:44 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[All three races in the US Biathlon (USBA) Fall Festival Rollerski Trials are in the books, and the Green Racing Project had some standout results. USBA uses the results from these rollerski trials races, in addition to two previous races in Jericho, VT, to select their World Cup team for the upcoming season. While the selections won’t be made public until after the completion of all five races, we hope to see a number of GRP athletes represent the US in early World Cups.The race series started on Tuesday, October 30 with a 7.5/10k sprint race. In the senior women’s category, GRP athletes swept the top three positions, with Susan Dunklee, Clare Egan and Emily Dreissigacker going 1-2-3. All three missed just one shot in standing. The sweep continued from there, with Hallie Grossman taking 4th place (with clean shooting!), Johanna Taliharm (of Estonia, but a GRP summer training partner) in 5th, and Kelsey Dickinson in 6th. On the men’s side, Jake Brown took 5th for the GRP, Alex Howe finished 7th, and Raleigh Goessling was 8th.The following day, October 31, athletes raced another 7.5/10k sprint. The GRP women did well again, this time with Susan taking 1st and Hallie in 3rd. Johanna Taliharm placed 2nd. Emily Dreissigacker took 5th place, Clare Egan 6th, and Kelsey Dickinson 9th. In the men’s race, Jake Brown landed on the podium in 3rd place. Alex Howe placed 6th, and Raleigh Goessling was 8th.The final day of competition, November 2, was a mass start race, 12.5k for women and 15k for men. The GRP women had another great day, with Clare, Susan and Emily sweeping the podium once again, in that order. They were followed by Johanna in 4th, Hallie in 5th, and Kelsey in 6th. On the men&#039;s side, Jake finished 6th and Raleigh 7th. Results from all of the trials race are available on the USBA website, right HERE. <img src="/assets/Uploads/GRP-women.jpg" alt="GRP women" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2136/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>2018 Black River Beatdown Results</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2134/</link>
			<description>We had an awesome time hosting the 2018 Ironwood Adventureworks Black River Beatdown this Sunday, October 28. Almost 50 runners braved the rain and cold temperatures for 15k, 30k, and 45k trail races. Many of our competitors were in costume, and all enjoyed one of the last opportunities for a trail race in 2018. Big thanks to Ironwood Adventureworks for organizing the race, and to all of our runners for coming out!The 15k one loop race was the largest field of the day, with 25 competitors. Claire McIlvennie of Winooski, VT won the overall 15k as well as the women&#039;s race in a blazing time of 1:17:12. Second place in the women&#039;s race went to Elizabeth Anderson, and third place went to Ruth Addante. Elizabeth and Ruth also placed 3rd and 4th overall. The first men&#039;s 15k finisher was Robert Primeau, second place went to Paul Charron, and third place was Kyle Darling.A smaller group of runners braved the two lap, 30k course. The overall victory and men&#039;s win went to GRP skier Akeo Maifield-Carucci with a time of 2:39:51. Second place went to Jonathan Brown, and third place to Jake Wallenius-Duda. First place in the women&#039;s race went to Haley Heinrich, second place went to Caitlin Patterson, and third place to Stephanie Parent.Only five racers completed the three lap, 45k race. Our winner, Eric Morse, finished the course in a time of 4:33:10. Second place was Robert Cary of Albany, VT, and third place went to Robert Griffiths of Craftsbury, VT. A few of our resident GRP athletes joined in on the fun on Sunday and had great things to say about the event. From Ben Lustgarten, who competed in the 30k, &quot;the course marking was great, course was fun and varied, aid stations were awesome!&quot;. Caitlin Patterson, 2nd place female in the 30k, loved the &quot;great costumes and enthusiasm, a fun scene with everyone making the most of the cool fall weather.&quot;Full results from the 2018 Black River Beatdown available HERE.Additionally, click HERE to access a full photo album thanks to Wes Vear.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 15:15:47 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[We had an awesome time hosting the 2018 Ironwood Adventureworks Black River Beatdown this Sunday, October 28. Almost 50 runners braved the rain and cold temperatures for 15k, 30k, and 45k trail races. Many of our competitors were in costume, and all enjoyed one of the last opportunities for a trail race in 2018. Big thanks to Ironwood Adventureworks for organizing the race, and to all of our runners for coming out!The 15k one loop race was the largest field of the day, with 25 competitors. Claire McIlvennie of Winooski, VT won the overall 15k as well as the women&#039;s race in a blazing time of 1:17:12. Second place in the women&#039;s race went to Elizabeth Anderson, and third place went to Ruth Addante. Elizabeth and Ruth also placed 3rd and 4th overall. The first men&#039;s 15k finisher was Robert Primeau, second place went to Paul Charron, and third place was Kyle Darling.A smaller group of runners braved the two lap, 30k course. The overall victory and men&#039;s win went to GRP skier Akeo Maifield-Carucci with a time of 2:39:51. Second place went to Jonathan Brown, and third place to Jake Wallenius-Duda. First place in the women&#039;s race went to Haley Heinrich, second place went to Caitlin Patterson, and third place to Stephanie Parent.Only five racers completed the three lap, 45k race. Our winner, Eric Morse, finished the course in a time of 4:33:10. Second place was Robert Cary of Albany, VT, and third place went to Robert Griffiths of Craftsbury, VT. A few of our resident GRP athletes joined in on the fun on Sunday and had great things to say about the event. From Ben Lustgarten, who competed in the 30k, &quot;the course marking was great, course was fun and varied, aid stations were awesome!&quot;. Caitlin Patterson, 2nd place female in the 30k, loved the &quot;great costumes and enthusiasm, a fun scene with everyone making the most of the cool fall weather.&quot;Full results from the 2018 Black River Beatdown available HERE.Additionally, click HERE to access a full photo album thanks to Wes Vear. <img src="/assets/Uploads/44917873-1688149997961444-3143090288784834560-n.jpg" alt="44917873 1688149997961444 3143090288784834560 n" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2134/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Head of the Charles 2018 Recap and Results</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2132/</link>
			<description>After a whirlwind weekend in Boston, the 54th Head of the Charles is complete! The entire rowing world converges on the Charles River every year during the third weekend of October, and Craftsbury is no exception. Blustery winds and (mostly) blue skies marked the event, which saw nearly 11,000 racers negotiating the bridges and turns of the infamous three-mile course. Sculling staff and GRP rowers had a fantastic time both racing and working the tent in the bustling finish line area, handing out nearly 80 dozen cookies and chatting with tons of past and future campers. We also raffled off a free week of camp; we’ll be announcing the winner soon.Now, to the racing: First up on Saturday was Director of Sculling Troy Howell, racing in the Men’s Grand Master Singles. His seventh-place finish in a field of 52 easily secured him a guaranteed entry for next year’s regatta. Also on Saturday morning, Dick Dreissigacker and Judy Geer raced in the Senior Master Eights categories, for Motley Rowing Club and 1980 Rowing Club, respectively.  Motley finished 35th out of 62 crews, and 1980 came in 23rd out of 44 crews. Saturday afternoon features the championship sculling events, which kicked off with the Men’s Champ Doubles. GRP’s Nathan Lado and Wes Vear kicked it off indeed, racing to a first-place finish. Their winning time of 17:02 bested the second-place finishers and GRP alums Peter and Tom Graves by five seconds. Also in the event was a double of Mats Terwiesch and Josh Bilchik, two of our 2018 U23 alums. They placed eighth overall, and earned gold medals as the top lightweight double within the event. In the Women’s Champ Doubles, Jen Forbes raced with GRP alum Elizabeth Sonshine to a close second-place finish behind ARION, less than 1.5 seconds back. Jen also jumped into a Director’s Challenge Mixed 8+ on Sunday and a won a second medal, this time gold. (Important note: she was dressed as Olaf, the snowman from Frozen, for her victorious run down the course.)The Women’s Champ Singles saw Alex Spaulding and new GRP rower Taylor Goetzinger race to 11th and 20th places, respectively.  The field featured numerous top US and international scullers, but no one was surprised to see Charles River local Gevvie Stone taking her record ninth win in the event. Jenny McIlvane raced in the Women’s Lightweight Singles, finishing in ninth place.The Men’s Champ Singles also featured a wickedly competitive field, with some of the fastest US men, including our own John Graves and Ben Davison (rowing for his school, the University of Washington) mixing it up with the biggest international names (Mahe Drysdale, Damir Martin, and Robbie Manson, to name a few). As the results started to roll in, it appeared that first place would go to local Andy Campbell, American lightweight sculler and course record holder, with John holding in second place. But this is head racing, and nothing is set until the last sculler has crossed the line. As the wakes settled, it became clear that Ben Davison had rowed through the field from bow #26 to take the win. Ben’s gold-medal time was 17:55, Andy Campbell went 18:00 for silver, and John finished in 18:11 for bronze. Sunday was a quieter day on the racing front for Craftsbury, but Fleet Manager Erika Sloan raced to ninth place out of 22 in the Women’s Club Singles, and GRP sculler Lucas Bellows traded two oars for one to hop in with some New York Athletic Club athletes in the Men’s Champ Fours, placing 12th. Congratulations to all who raced, including the myriad other Craftsbury-connected crews out on the Charles this weekend. Well rowed by all!  Full results can be found on RegattaCentral or on HereNOW. Photos from the racing can be found on Row2k, Sport Graphics, and Scullingfool.The GRP next races from November 3-4 at the USRowing Fall Speed Order, a chance to test speed on the erg and in singles before winter training begins in earnest. John Graves is currently in the lead for the Lotman Challenge, and will also head to Philadelphia to contest the final leg at the Head of the Schuylkill Regatta next weekend. </description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 21:02:06 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[After a whirlwind weekend in Boston, the 54th Head of the Charles is complete! The entire rowing world converges on the Charles River every year during the third weekend of October, and Craftsbury is no exception. Blustery winds and (mostly) blue skies marked the event, which saw nearly 11,000 racers negotiating the bridges and turns of the infamous three-mile course. Sculling staff and GRP rowers had a fantastic time both racing and working the tent in the bustling finish line area, handing out nearly 80 dozen cookies and chatting with tons of past and future campers. We also raffled off a free week of camp; we’ll be announcing the winner soon.Now, to the racing: First up on Saturday was Director of Sculling Troy Howell, racing in the Men’s Grand Master Singles. His seventh-place finish in a field of 52 easily secured him a guaranteed entry for next year’s regatta. Also on Saturday morning, Dick Dreissigacker and Judy Geer raced in the Senior Master Eights categories, for Motley Rowing Club and 1980 Rowing Club, respectively.  Motley finished 35th out of 62 crews, and 1980 came in 23rd out of 44 crews. Saturday afternoon features the championship sculling events, which kicked off with the Men’s Champ Doubles. GRP’s Nathan Lado and Wes Vear kicked it off indeed, racing to a first-place finish. Their winning time of 17:02 bested the second-place finishers and GRP alums Peter and Tom Graves by five seconds. Also in the event was a double of Mats Terwiesch and Josh Bilchik, two of our 2018 U23 alums. They placed eighth overall, and earned gold medals as the top lightweight double within the event. In the Women’s Champ Doubles, Jen Forbes raced with GRP alum Elizabeth Sonshine to a close second-place finish behind ARION, less than 1.5 seconds back. Jen also jumped into a Director’s Challenge Mixed 8+ on Sunday and a won a second medal, this time gold. (Important note: she was dressed as Olaf, the snowman from Frozen, for her victorious run down the course.)The Women’s Champ Singles saw Alex Spaulding and new GRP rower Taylor Goetzinger race to 11th and 20th places, respectively.  The field featured numerous top US and international scullers, but no one was surprised to see Charles River local Gevvie Stone taking her record ninth win in the event. Jenny McIlvane raced in the Women’s Lightweight Singles, finishing in ninth place.The Men’s Champ Singles also featured a wickedly competitive field, with some of the fastest US men, including our own John Graves and Ben Davison (rowing for his school, the University of Washington) mixing it up with the biggest international names (Mahe Drysdale, Damir Martin, and Robbie Manson, to name a few). As the results started to roll in, it appeared that first place would go to local Andy Campbell, American lightweight sculler and course record holder, with John holding in second place. But this is head racing, and nothing is set until the last sculler has crossed the line. As the wakes settled, it became clear that Ben Davison had rowed through the field from bow #26 to take the win. Ben’s gold-medal time was 17:55, Andy Campbell went 18:00 for silver, and John finished in 18:11 for bronze. Sunday was a quieter day on the racing front for Craftsbury, but Fleet Manager Erika Sloan raced to ninth place out of 22 in the Women’s Club Singles, and GRP sculler Lucas Bellows traded two oars for one to hop in with some New York Athletic Club athletes in the Men’s Champ Fours, placing 12th. Congratulations to all who raced, including the myriad other Craftsbury-connected crews out on the Charles this weekend. Well rowed by all!  Full results can be found on RegattaCentral or on HereNOW. Photos from the racing can be found on Row2k, Sport Graphics, and Scullingfool.The GRP next races from November 3-4 at the USRowing Fall Speed Order, a chance to test speed on the erg and in singles before winter training begins in earnest. John Graves is currently in the lead for the Lotman Challenge, and will also head to Philadelphia to contest the final leg at the Head of the Schuylkill Regatta next weekend.  <img src="/assets/bulkUpload/HOCR2018-Craftsbury-2x-ForbesSonshine-MC2.jpg" alt="HOCR2018 Craftsbury 2x ForbesSonshine MC2" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2132/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Caldwell and Martin Podium at Newburyport Half Marathon </title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2131/</link>
			<description>Last weekend, Running Director Heidi Caldwell and GRP skier Adam Martin travelled to Newburyport, Massachusetts for the Newburyport Half Marathon. This race, held on Massachusetts’s North Shore, is relatively flat and fast and annually draws a very competitive field. Undeterred by the competition, Heidi and Adam both delivered noteworthy performances. Adam finished 2nd, in a blistering time of 1:06:18 (roughly a 5:05 minute mile) only two seconds behind 1st place Tadesse Yae Dabi. The Newburyport Daily News reported that Dabi is an “Ethiopian distance star” that has “competed all over the world.” Heidi was 6th overall and won the women’s race by a convincing seven minutes, in a time of 1:13:43 (about a 5:35 mile time). This time is nearly two minutes faster than her half marathon performance from earlier this month! Adam’s focus will now shift back to skiing, while Heidi’s next race is the California International Marathon in Sacramento on December 2nd. Congratulations to these two for highlighting Craftsbury’s running prowess. Full results from the race can be found here and stay tuned for an update on Heidi’s December marathon. </description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 21:51:44 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[Last weekend, Running Director Heidi Caldwell and GRP skier Adam Martin travelled to Newburyport, Massachusetts for the Newburyport Half Marathon. This race, held on Massachusetts’s North Shore, is relatively flat and fast and annually draws a very competitive field. Undeterred by the competition, Heidi and Adam both delivered noteworthy performances. Adam finished 2nd, in a blistering time of 1:06:18 (roughly a 5:05 minute mile) only two seconds behind 1st place Tadesse Yae Dabi. The Newburyport Daily News reported that Dabi is an “Ethiopian distance star” that has “competed all over the world.” Heidi was 6th overall and won the women’s race by a convincing seven minutes, in a time of 1:13:43 (about a 5:35 mile time). This time is nearly two minutes faster than her half marathon performance from earlier this month! Adam’s focus will now shift back to skiing, while Heidi’s next race is the California International Marathon in Sacramento on December 2nd. Congratulations to these two for highlighting Craftsbury’s running prowess. Full results from the race can be found here and stay tuned for an update on Heidi’s December marathon.  <img src="/assets/bulkUpload/adam-newburyport-half.jpg" alt="adam newburyport half" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2131/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>GRP and CNSC Race Fall Rollerski Classic at Jericho, VT</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2125/</link>
			<description>A large group of Green Racing Project and Craftsbury Nordic Ski Club skiers competed this weekend in the Fall Rollerski Classic in Jericho, VT. The race, a 10k classic interval start, was part of NENSA&#039;s summer and fall rollerski series, which has just one more race remaining in the season.Green Racing ProjectThe GRP had five athletes in the race, three women and two men. The women had the strongest results, with Caitlin Patterson and Ida Sargent going 1-2 overall. Corey Stock placed 8th overall, 3rd in the senior women&#039;s category. On the men&#039;s side, Adam Martin took 2nd overall to UVM&#039;s Bill Harmeyer. Akeo Maifield-Carucci placed 5th in the senior men&#039;s category.Craftsbury Nordic Ski ClubA large contingent of juniors from the Craftsbury Outdoor Center also raced. In the U18 girl&#039;s category, Adrienne Remick took 9th place. In the U18 men&#039;s race, Finn Sweet placed 3rd, Griffin Wright was 19th, and Greyson Davis took 20th. Phil Lawson, father of former CNSC junior Alex Lawson, won the M5 category. There were also a number of former CNSC athletes, now racing for their college teams. In the U20 girl&#039;s, Callie Young, racing for Dartmouth, took 4th, Phoebe Sweet (UVM) was 6th, and Rena Schwartz (Dartmouth) took 11th. Lina Sutro (UVM), who trained with the GRP this summer, placed an impressive 3rd overall in the women&#039;s race and won the U23 women&#039;s category. Anders Hanson (Colby) placed 14th in the U23 men&#039;s race.Full results from the race are available on BartTiming. The next NENSA Rollerski Race is on November 3rd at Trapp&#039;s!</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 15:03:14 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[A large group of Green Racing Project and Craftsbury Nordic Ski Club skiers competed this weekend in the Fall Rollerski Classic in Jericho, VT. The race, a 10k classic interval start, was part of NENSA&#039;s summer and fall rollerski series, which has just one more race remaining in the season.Green Racing ProjectThe GRP had five athletes in the race, three women and two men. The women had the strongest results, with Caitlin Patterson and Ida Sargent going 1-2 overall. Corey Stock placed 8th overall, 3rd in the senior women&#039;s category. On the men&#039;s side, Adam Martin took 2nd overall to UVM&#039;s Bill Harmeyer. Akeo Maifield-Carucci placed 5th in the senior men&#039;s category.Craftsbury Nordic Ski ClubA large contingent of juniors from the Craftsbury Outdoor Center also raced. In the U18 girl&#039;s category, Adrienne Remick took 9th place. In the U18 men&#039;s race, Finn Sweet placed 3rd, Griffin Wright was 19th, and Greyson Davis took 20th. Phil Lawson, father of former CNSC junior Alex Lawson, won the M5 category. There were also a number of former CNSC athletes, now racing for their college teams. In the U20 girl&#039;s, Callie Young, racing for Dartmouth, took 4th, Phoebe Sweet (UVM) was 6th, and Rena Schwartz (Dartmouth) took 11th. Lina Sutro (UVM), who trained with the GRP this summer, placed an impressive 3rd overall in the women&#039;s race and won the U23 women&#039;s category. Anders Hanson (Colby) placed 14th in the U23 men&#039;s race.Full results from the race are available on BartTiming. The next NENSA Rollerski Race is on November 3rd at Trapp&#039;s! <img src="/assets/Uploads/45250676542-fd39fdb72a-z.jpg" alt="45250676542 fd39fdb72a z" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2125/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>GRP Scullers Race Green Mountain Head: Win syrup, apples, and cider</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2116/</link>
			<description>GRP scullers raced at Green Mountain Head this weekend for what are arguably the best prizes in all of fall head racing. For the last 37 years, Putney Rowing Club has hosted the regatta on their small stretch of the Connecticut River, and have provided single and double scullers of all ages a truly unique race experience. For starters, the regatta parking lot is a corn field that is usually harvested just days before the start of GMH. Volunteers usher racers that are both towing trailers and car-topping their boats over mounds of dirt and remainders of prickly corn stalks. Cars bounce comically over the now-empty rows of corn in anticipation of a great day of racing. Don’t be fooled by the low-key nature of this race, though - some of the athletes you see noshing freshly fried apple cider donuts are Olympians and world champions alike. “I looked over and saw Gevvie putting away two cider doughnuts, and then Mary came over and bought one,“ Alex Spaulding (who won a gallon of cider for her third place finish behind Mary and Gevvie) recounts feeling inspired by 2016 Olympic Silver Medalist Gevvie Stone and 2018 World Championship Silver Medalist Mary Jones Nabel on their pre-race fueling methods. “I knew that [Jen and I] should probably get one too, maybe [cider doughnuts] are the secret to going fast.” The men’s and women’s single sculls events were heavily peppered with athletes from national teams past and present, along with novice, club, and masters rowers alike.  Aside from the general friendliness and good-natured vibes, Putney Rowing Club members and volunteers provide racers with a lunch of healthy snacks, cheese sandwiches, apples, apple cider, and the famously quirky offering of....egg rolls?“I’ve never had an egg roll before,” recalls GRP sculler and self-proclaimed “big eater” Wes Vear - “but after today, I think I’ve more than well enough made up for lost time.” GRP scullers had sights set on both racing well during the 5 kilometer race (split in half by a two stake buoys that racers have to effectively make a u-turn around), and taking home one of the prizes awarded to the top three finishers of each event. First place finishers receive a quart of maple syrup, second place gets a bag of apples, and third takes home a gallon of apple cider. All of these products are local to the great state of Vermont. Men’s 1x (19-34)Nathan Lado- 2nd *APPLE WINNER*Wes Vear- 6thLucas Bellows- 8th Men’s 1x (45-55)Troy Howell- 3rd *CIDER WINNER* Women’s 1x (19-34)Alex Spaulding- 3rd *CIDER WINNER*Jen Forbes- 4thJenny McIlvane- 8th Mixed 2x Jen Forbes/Nathan Lado- 1st *SYRUP WINNER*Wes Vear/Alex Spaulding- 3rd *CIDER WINNER*Troy Howell/Jenny McIlvane- 4th Congrats on a fun and successful weekend of racing! And a huge thank you to Putney Rowing Club for putting on such a fun, competitive and good-spirited regatta!Up next: Head of the Kevin III (October 13)  </description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 20:02:18 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[GRP scullers raced at Green Mountain Head this weekend for what are arguably the best prizes in all of fall head racing. For the last 37 years, Putney Rowing Club has hosted the regatta on their small stretch of the Connecticut River, and have provided single and double scullers of all ages a truly unique race experience. For starters, the regatta parking lot is a corn field that is usually harvested just days before the start of GMH. Volunteers usher racers that are both towing trailers and car-topping their boats over mounds of dirt and remainders of prickly corn stalks. Cars bounce comically over the now-empty rows of corn in anticipation of a great day of racing. Don’t be fooled by the low-key nature of this race, though - some of the athletes you see noshing freshly fried apple cider donuts are Olympians and world champions alike. “I looked over and saw Gevvie putting away two cider doughnuts, and then Mary came over and bought one,“ Alex Spaulding (who won a gallon of cider for her third place finish behind Mary and Gevvie) recounts feeling inspired by 2016 Olympic Silver Medalist Gevvie Stone and 2018 World Championship Silver Medalist Mary Jones Nabel on their pre-race fueling methods. “I knew that [Jen and I] should probably get one too, maybe [cider doughnuts] are the secret to going fast.” The men’s and women’s single sculls events were heavily peppered with athletes from national teams past and present, along with novice, club, and masters rowers alike.  Aside from the general friendliness and good-natured vibes, Putney Rowing Club members and volunteers provide racers with a lunch of healthy snacks, cheese sandwiches, apples, apple cider, and the famously quirky offering of....egg rolls?“I’ve never had an egg roll before,” recalls GRP sculler and self-proclaimed “big eater” Wes Vear - “but after today, I think I’ve more than well enough made up for lost time.” GRP scullers had sights set on both racing well during the 5 kilometer race (split in half by a two stake buoys that racers have to effectively make a u-turn around), and taking home one of the prizes awarded to the top three finishers of each event. First place finishers receive a quart of maple syrup, second place gets a bag of apples, and third takes home a gallon of apple cider. All of these products are local to the great state of Vermont. Men’s 1x (19-34)Nathan Lado- 2nd *APPLE WINNER*Wes Vear- 6thLucas Bellows- 8th Men’s 1x (45-55)Troy Howell- 3rd *CIDER WINNER* Women’s 1x (19-34)Alex Spaulding- 3rd *CIDER WINNER*Jen Forbes- 4thJenny McIlvane- 8th Mixed 2x Jen Forbes/Nathan Lado- 1st *SYRUP WINNER*Wes Vear/Alex Spaulding- 3rd *CIDER WINNER*Troy Howell/Jenny McIlvane- 4th Congrats on a fun and successful weekend of racing! And a huge thank you to Putney Rowing Club for putting on such a fun, competitive and good-spirited regatta!Up next: Head of the Kevin III (October 13)   <img src="/assets/bulkUpload/399D5DEA-C654-4943-8BD6-F18AA6C90B39.jpeg" alt="399D5DEA C654 4943 8BD6 F18AA6C90B39" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2116/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>GRP Biathletes Podium at Climb to the Castle Rollerski Race</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2110/</link>
			<description>Last weekend, two GRP biathletes and one Craftsbury junior raced the infamous NYSEF Climb to the Castle. This mass start skate rollerski event climbs 2,300 feet up the Whiteface Mountain Veterans Memorial Highway. For the women, Quincy Massey-Bierman placed 11th overall and won the woman’s U16 category. For the men, Jake Brown topped the field with a new non-race wheel course record. He was joined on the podium by GRP teammate Raleigh Goessling in second place. The biathletes will return to racing action later this fall in Soldier Hollow, Utah.Results  </description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 08:27:01 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[Last weekend, two GRP biathletes and one Craftsbury junior raced the infamous NYSEF Climb to the Castle. This mass start skate rollerski event climbs 2,300 feet up the Whiteface Mountain Veterans Memorial Highway. For the women, Quincy Massey-Bierman placed 11th overall and won the woman’s U16 category. For the men, Jake Brown topped the field with a new non-race wheel course record. He was joined on the podium by GRP teammate Raleigh Goessling in second place. The biathletes will return to racing action later this fall in Soldier Hollow, Utah.Results   <img src="/assets/Uploads/9.24.18newsphoto.jpg" alt="9.24.18newsphoto" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2110/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>GRP Skiers Podium at New Zealand Winter Games</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2102/</link>
			<description>In the first FIS races of the 2018-2019 season, Green Racing Project skiers had great results, with a handful of podiums among them. The New Zealand Winter Games occur every September, with the cross country portion at the Snow Farm in Cardrona, NZ. The GRP skiers are currently down at the Snow Farm for a training camp, and used the races to build in some nice intensity during their camp.On Tuesday, September 4, the Games kicked off with a 5/10k individual start freestyle race. In the men&#039;s race, Ben Lustgarten had the top GRP result, taking 3rd, with Adam Martin close behind in 4th, and Akeo Maifield-Carucci in 6th. In the women&#039;s 5k, Caitlin Patterson also hit the podium in 3rd, Ida Sargent took 4th, and Corey Stock was 7th.Wednesday brought a freestyle sprint, with small but very competitive fields. In the men&#039;s qualifier, Lustgarten took 3rd, Martin 7th, and Maifield-Carucci 9th. Lustgarten raced well through the rounds to finish 4th in the final, and Martin and Maifield-Carucci made it to the semis, with final places of 7th and 8th, respectively. In the women&#039;s race, Sargent qualified in 2nd and then went on to finish 2nd in the final behind her US Ski Team teammate Sophie Caldwell. Patterson qualified 5th and finished 5th in the heats, while Stock qualified 6th and finished 7th. The final day was a 10/15k mass start classic race. While the GRP only had four skiers overall in both races, all four made the podium in their respective events. In the women&#039;s 10k, Patterson took 2nd to Jessie Diggins in a close finish, and Sargent was close behind in 3rd. In the 15k an hour later, Martin took 2nd and Lustgarten 3rd.Full results from the weekend are available on the New Zealand Winter Games website. Thanks for following along!</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 21:55:24 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[In the first FIS races of the 2018-2019 season, Green Racing Project skiers had great results, with a handful of podiums among them. The New Zealand Winter Games occur every September, with the cross country portion at the Snow Farm in Cardrona, NZ. The GRP skiers are currently down at the Snow Farm for a training camp, and used the races to build in some nice intensity during their camp.On Tuesday, September 4, the Games kicked off with a 5/10k individual start freestyle race. In the men&#039;s race, Ben Lustgarten had the top GRP result, taking 3rd, with Adam Martin close behind in 4th, and Akeo Maifield-Carucci in 6th. In the women&#039;s 5k, Caitlin Patterson also hit the podium in 3rd, Ida Sargent took 4th, and Corey Stock was 7th.Wednesday brought a freestyle sprint, with small but very competitive fields. In the men&#039;s qualifier, Lustgarten took 3rd, Martin 7th, and Maifield-Carucci 9th. Lustgarten raced well through the rounds to finish 4th in the final, and Martin and Maifield-Carucci made it to the semis, with final places of 7th and 8th, respectively. In the women&#039;s race, Sargent qualified in 2nd and then went on to finish 2nd in the final behind her US Ski Team teammate Sophie Caldwell. Patterson qualified 5th and finished 5th in the heats, while Stock qualified 6th and finished 7th. The final day was a 10/15k mass start classic race. While the GRP only had four skiers overall in both races, all four made the podium in their respective events. In the women&#039;s 10k, Patterson took 2nd to Jessie Diggins in a close finish, and Sargent was close behind in 3rd. In the 15k an hour later, Martin took 2nd and Lustgarten 3rd.Full results from the weekend are available on the New Zealand Winter Games website. Thanks for following along! <img src="/assets/Uploads/41184384-1837189483034907-5800525621566111744-n.jpg" alt="41184384 1837189483034907 5800525621566111744 n" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2102/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Adam Martin 2nd at 2018 Merino Muster</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2099/</link>
			<description>The 2018-2019 ski racing season is officially underway, at least in the Southern Hemisphere! Green Racing Project skier Adam Martin was the lone GRP representative in the 2018 edition of the Merino Muster on Saturday, September 1. The Muster is a 42k skate marathon at the Snow Farm in Cardrona, New Zealand, and is also a part of the WorldLoppet Marathon series.Martin spent the 42k entire race with the lead pack, which included US skiers Simi Hamilton and Kyle Bratrud, as well as Japanese skier Tomoka Satou. In the final meters of the race, it came down to a sprint finish between Martin and Hamilton for the win. Martin ended up 2nd, with a time of 1:39:49 to Hamilton&#039;s 1:39:46.The entire GRP ski team is currently at a training camp at the Snow Farm. On Tuesday, September 4, the cross country portion of New Zealand Winter Games will begin, which includes three races. Tuesday will bring a 5/10k skate individual start, Wednesday a skate sprint, and Thursday a 10/15k classic mass start. The rest of the GRP will lace up their boots for those races, so stay tuned for results from down south.Merino Muster 2018 Results</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 22:36:04 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[The 2018-2019 ski racing season is officially underway, at least in the Southern Hemisphere! Green Racing Project skier Adam Martin was the lone GRP representative in the 2018 edition of the Merino Muster on Saturday, September 1. The Muster is a 42k skate marathon at the Snow Farm in Cardrona, New Zealand, and is also a part of the WorldLoppet Marathon series.Martin spent the 42k entire race with the lead pack, which included US skiers Simi Hamilton and Kyle Bratrud, as well as Japanese skier Tomoka Satou. In the final meters of the race, it came down to a sprint finish between Martin and Hamilton for the win. Martin ended up 2nd, with a time of 1:39:49 to Hamilton&#039;s 1:39:46.The entire GRP ski team is currently at a training camp at the Snow Farm. On Tuesday, September 4, the cross country portion of New Zealand Winter Games will begin, which includes three races. Tuesday will bring a 5/10k skate individual start, Wednesday a skate sprint, and Thursday a 10/15k classic mass start. The rest of the GRP will lace up their boots for those races, so stay tuned for results from down south.Merino Muster 2018 Results <img src="/assets/Uploads/40441204-2221412674539717-4215190284226527232-n.jpg" alt="40441204 2221412674539717 4215190284226527232 n" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2099/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Green Racing Project Success at Pan American Games Trials</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2095/</link>
			<description>Last week marked the final summer racing for our Green Racing Project rowers as they took to the waters of Lake Mercer for the fifth time this summer for a couple of them. Our athletes continued the progress that they’ve had over the course of the summer at the Pan American Games Trials Regatta last Monday to determine who will represent the United States and the Pan American Games Qualifying Regatta in Rio de Janeiro on November 29th. Last week’s racing had a different format than has been used in the past with a morning time trial leading to a straight final of four boats in the afternoon. Taking the new format in stride… or should we say stroke?… all of our five boats advanced to their respective finals with Lucas Bellows leading off the Greenies for the day by placing third in the Men’s Single Sculls. Jenifer Forbes and Alex Spaulding followed in short order, placing first and third, respectively, in the Women’s Single Sculls. Rounding out the GRP time trials were Nathan Lado and Wes Vear in the Men’s Double Sculls as well as Frank Horpel in a composite lineup of Craftsbury and Oklahoma City High Performance Team’s Kevin Cardno, finishing first and fourth. On to the afternoon’s finals seven hours later. It was Craftsbury’s bowballs across the line first in all three of their events. Lucas Bellows once again started the Greenies off in their headwind racing conditions by winning his final with a time of 7:47.98 and a margin of more than four seconds over second place. Jenifer Forbes proceeded to win her final in a time of 8:29.51 and a two second margin over second place with Alex Spaulding rounding out fourth place with a time of 8:46.51. Nathan Lado and Wes Vear won their final with a time of 7:00.23 and one of the highest percentages of the day over second place of Frank Horpel’s GRP/OKC composite boat with a time of 7:09.48.The first place finishers have all accepted their bids which means that the GRP will be heading down to Rio de Janeiro on November 27th to race at the qualifying regatta. Qualifying crews from that regatta will then race at the Pan American Games next July in Lima, Peru.Go GRP, go Green!Full racing results can be found here!</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 07:12:18 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[Last week marked the final summer racing for our Green Racing Project rowers as they took to the waters of Lake Mercer for the fifth time this summer for a couple of them. Our athletes continued the progress that they’ve had over the course of the summer at the Pan American Games Trials Regatta last Monday to determine who will represent the United States and the Pan American Games Qualifying Regatta in Rio de Janeiro on November 29th. Last week’s racing had a different format than has been used in the past with a morning time trial leading to a straight final of four boats in the afternoon. Taking the new format in stride… or should we say stroke?… all of our five boats advanced to their respective finals with Lucas Bellows leading off the Greenies for the day by placing third in the Men’s Single Sculls. Jenifer Forbes and Alex Spaulding followed in short order, placing first and third, respectively, in the Women’s Single Sculls. Rounding out the GRP time trials were Nathan Lado and Wes Vear in the Men’s Double Sculls as well as Frank Horpel in a composite lineup of Craftsbury and Oklahoma City High Performance Team’s Kevin Cardno, finishing first and fourth. On to the afternoon’s finals seven hours later. It was Craftsbury’s bowballs across the line first in all three of their events. Lucas Bellows once again started the Greenies off in their headwind racing conditions by winning his final with a time of 7:47.98 and a margin of more than four seconds over second place. Jenifer Forbes proceeded to win her final in a time of 8:29.51 and a two second margin over second place with Alex Spaulding rounding out fourth place with a time of 8:46.51. Nathan Lado and Wes Vear won their final with a time of 7:00.23 and one of the highest percentages of the day over second place of Frank Horpel’s GRP/OKC composite boat with a time of 7:09.48.The first place finishers have all accepted their bids which means that the GRP will be heading down to Rio de Janeiro on November 27th to race at the qualifying regatta. Qualifying crews from that regatta will then race at the Pan American Games next July in Lima, Peru.Go GRP, go Green!Full racing results can be found here! <img src="/assets/bulkUpload/IMG-1164.jpg" alt="IMG 1164" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2095/</guid>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Podium Finishes for Craftsbury Runners Across New England</title>
			<link>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2094/</link>
			<description>On Saturday, Running Director Heidi Caldwell raced at the New Hampshire 10 Miler in Auburn, NH. This race attracts a speedy crowd as it is part of the New England USATF Grand Prix Championship series. Nonetheless, Heidi placed an impressive 2nd place!On Sunday, a small Craftsbury contingent primarily made up of GRP biathletes descended upon Mt. Mansfield for the annual Race to the Top of Vermont. In this annual suffer fest, runners and bikers alike are treated to 4.3 miles of climbing up Mt. Mansfield. In the men’s race, Jake Brown crossed the line first, in a blistering fast 34:34. Raleigh Goessling wasn’t far behind in 3rd. Junior Bjorn Westervelt was 13th place overall, 1st in the 15-19 age group. Ethan Dreissigacker won the Clydesdale division and was 28th overall. In the women’s race, Kelsey Dickinson took the win, followed by Hallie Grossman in 3rd. See results here from Saturday and here from Sunday. </description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2018 18:00:03 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[On Saturday, Running Director Heidi Caldwell raced at the New Hampshire 10 Miler in Auburn, NH. This race attracts a speedy crowd as it is part of the New England USATF Grand Prix Championship series. Nonetheless, Heidi placed an impressive 2nd place!On Sunday, a small Craftsbury contingent primarily made up of GRP biathletes descended upon Mt. Mansfield for the annual Race to the Top of Vermont. In this annual suffer fest, runners and bikers alike are treated to 4.3 miles of climbing up Mt. Mansfield. In the men’s race, Jake Brown crossed the line first, in a blistering fast 34:34. Raleigh Goessling wasn’t far behind in 3rd. Junior Bjorn Westervelt was 13th place overall, 1st in the 15-19 age group. Ethan Dreissigacker won the Clydesdale division and was 28th overall. In the women’s race, Kelsey Dickinson took the win, followed by Hallie Grossman in 3rd. See results here from Saturday and here from Sunday.  <img src="/assets/bulkUpload/40049700-2123939521024507-7419559263720177664-n.jpg" alt="40049700 2123939521024507 7419559263720177664 n" />]]></content:encoded>
			<guid>https://www.craftsbury.com/general/about-the-center/news/detail/2094/</guid>
		</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>